



<p>The Man Who Had All the Luck - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck","wgTitle":"The Man Who Had All the Luck","wgCurRevisionId":918628829,"wgRevisionId":918628829,"wgArticleId":1499548,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["1940 plays","Broadway plays","Plays by Arthur Miller"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck","wgRelevantArticleId":1499548,"wgRequestId":"XZZXJwpAAEYAADP4wYkAAAAK",</p>
<p>"wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q7749937","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":</p>
<p>"ready","jquery.makeCollapsible.styles":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","jquery.makeCollapsible","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head","mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns",</p>
<p>"ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>


























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>The Man Who Had All the Luck</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:ManLuckPoster.jpg"></ref> Poster for the 2002 Broadway revivalThe Man Who Had All the Luck is a play by <ref target="/wiki/Arthur_Miller" title="Arthur Miller">Arthur Miller</ref>.
<p>David Beeves is a young <ref target="/wiki/Midwestern_United_States" title="Midwestern United States">Midwestern</ref> <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Automobile" title="Automobile">automobile</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Mechanic" title="Mechanic">mechanic</ref> who discovers he is blessed with what appears to be almost <ref target="/wiki/Supernatural" title="Supernatural">supernatural</ref> good fortune that allows him to overcome every seemingly insurmountable obstacle that crosses his path while those around him fall in defeat. Like <ref target="/wiki/Midas" title="Midas">Midas</ref>, everything he touches is tinged with gold, leaving him to wonder if and when his luck will change and he too will be forced to deal with life's tragedies, until he eventually realizes that his good heart, hard work, and quick thought have been responsible for his success far more than luck.</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Plot">1 Plot</ref>
<ref target="#Analysis">2 Analysis</ref>
<ref target="#Notes">3 Notes</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">4 External links</ref>


<h2>Plot[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Plot">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Arthur Miller’s second major play (after <ref target="/wiki/No_Villain" title="No Villain">No Villain</ref>) The Man Who Had All the Luck follows protagonist David Beeves’ existential exploration into the enigmatic question of how fate and the human will interact with each other. The play takes on a fantastical, parable-like architecture in its plot construction and character development as we follow Beeves into three and a half of the luckiest years of his life. The story begins during an evening in April at an undisclosed Midwestern town, evoking a feel of nostalgia and Americana in the process. David Beeves works as a self-taught auto mechanic in a barn that doubles as a repair station – this is where the entire first act takes place. The scene unfolds as David tells J.B., a local shop owner, that he plans to confront his girlfriend Hester’s father about their intention to marry. This, of course, is not as easy as it seems; her father, Andrew Falk, has resented David for over seven years and still controls every aspect of Hester’s life. After receiving conflicting advice on how to mediate the situation from J.B., Hester, his father Pat, and Shory (a disabled veteran who manages the feed and grain store adjacent to the barn), a rich farm owner named Dan Dibble brings his Marmon over for repair after a competing mechanic informs him that the engine will have to be taken apart. J.B. then notes to David in secrecy that getting the Marmon to run properly might cement his place in the tractor business, despite David’s lack of prowess in tractor repair. David agrees to the job with brisk charm, though is filled with doubt about his ability to diagnose the Marmon properly.</p>
	Shortly thereafter, Mr. Falk arrives in a bitter frustration, ordering Hester to return home and confronting David Beeves directly. David, restraining himself from rash emotion and violence, bluntly tells Falk that he and Hester are marrying. Falk subsequently threatens to kill Beeves if he sees him again and pushes his stalled car away. Only moments later Dan Dibble returns with Hester, admitting in a stunned confession that he accidentally hit and killed her father with the front of his vehicle. David, feeling an ambivalent combination of sympathy for Hester, elation now that his obstacles have been removed, and a skeptical notion that what just happened was unreal, stays in the barn to work on the Marmon. As time presses on, Beeves gets progressively more tired and frustrated with his incompetence in diagnosing the Marmon’s mechanical issues. At the brink of his exhaustion, an Austrian mechanic named Gus enters the barn and offers to fix the Marmon at no charge while David rests. When he awakes in the morning, Gus has disappeared and Dibble has returned. Assuming that David was the one who repaired the automobile, Dibble promises to bring all of his tractors that need work done to David in the future, and guarantees the forming of other business connections along the way. In utter disbelief of his luck, David is unable to accept the money for restoring the Marmon.
	The play resumes following a three-year lapse at the farmhouse David and Hester have inherited after Andrew Falk’s death. David’s close friends and family have gathered at the house, eagerly awaiting his brother Amos’s baseball game. It is later revealed that Pat has received a telegram from Augie Belfast, a talent scout for the Detroit Tigers, notifying the family that he will be watching the game tonight specifically for Amos. After they return from the game, the crowd awaits Belfast’s arrival and verdict on whether Amos has the skill to be drafted into the Major Leagues at the Beeves’ residence. During this brief interim, David decides to invest in a mink farm at the persuasion of Dan Dibble. Spirits are high within the group initially, but as time passes without any sign of Belfast, Beeves starts to doubt the value of man’s hard work and determination. When the man ultimately does show, he lauds Amos’s talent as a pitcher, but remarks that when the bases are loaded, he becomes panicky because he has been used to practicing in the cellar throughout his life. He leaves the house unwilling to make any sort of deal with Amos. Resentful and humiliated, Amos vows never to play baseball again, blames his father for his misfortunes, and discloses his envious feelings toward David’s fulfillment in life. Beeves tells him he is not fulfilled in life because of his perceived inability to have children, which spurs Hester to unexpectedly reveal that she is having a child.
	Several months pass, and Hester has begun to enter labor as David, J.B., Shory, and Gus wait downstairs for the child to be born. Beeves tries to convince Gus to take over sixty percent of his business ventures so he can raise enough money to purchase more mink. Gus refuses on the basis that David could lose everything he owns if his mink perish, to which he replies that he has already mortgaged most of his assets. As things escalate into quarrel, David divulges that Hester has fallen and that it is possible that the child could be delivered as a stillbirth or deformed. David is convinced that this catastrophe is his final payment for all of the luck that has pursued him throughout his recent life. Ironically, the child is born a healthy boy, and David continues to feel ashamed and guilty about his prosperity. A month later, Gus and Hester learn that Dan Dibble’s mink have all died after consuming contaminated feed – David uses the same feed for his own mink. Both decide to hold off on telling him; Gus fearing that his psychological and emotional stability might come into jeopardy, and Hester believing that such a loss would eventually make him happy in the long run. Dibble eventually calls the house and informs David, who begins to chastise Hester. She makes the decision to leave him, the reasoning behind this misconstrued by David as Gus having an affair with his wife. Just as things come to an emotional climax, Dibble arrives and assuages their fears – he and David both realize that the careful monitoring of the feed has saved his mink. David has an epiphany after Gus points out that only Beeves’ hard work and meticulous care giving could have saved the mink, not luck. He then departs. Hester asks David to come up for bed, and as thunder roars in the distance, he stares out the window with apprehension.

<h2>Analysis[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Analysis">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref target="/wiki/Christopher_Bigsby" title="Christopher Bigsby">Christopher Bigsby</ref> states that this is a study of human freedom. Beyond offering an account of a man's decline into madness, and eventual redemption, it explores the degree to which many of the characters become complicit in their own irrelevance, the degree to which they collude in the idea of man as a victim, as a subject of cosmic ironies."<ref target="#cite_note-1">[1]</ref>
<p>Although written in 1940, the play did not reach <ref target="/wiki/New_York_City" title="New York City">New York City</ref> until four years later, Miller's first to be mounted on <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref>. Directed by <ref target="/wiki/Joseph_Fields" title="Joseph Fields">Joseph Fields</ref>, it opened on November 23, 1944 at the <ref target="/wiki/Eugene_O%27Neill_Theatre" title="Eugene O'Neill Theatre">Forrest Theatre</ref>, where it ran for only 4 performances.<ref target="#cite_note-2">[2]</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Karl_Swenson" title="Karl Swenson">Karl Swenson</ref> starred as David Beeves.</p>
<p>The play's failure nearly derailed Miller's career, and it remained one of his least known works until 1990, when the <ref target="/wiki/Bristol_Old_Vic" title="Bristol Old Vic">Bristol Old Vic</ref> staged The Man Who Had All The Luck with <ref target="/wiki/Iain_Glen" title="Iain Glen">Iain Glen</ref> in the lead role. The production was directed by <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Paul_Unwin_(film_director)" title="Paul Unwin (film director)">Paul Unwin</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-3">[3]</ref> It later transferred to the Young Vic in London. In 2000 director <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Dan_Fields&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Dan Fields (page does not exist)">Dan Fields</ref> mounted a production that ran for seven weeks at the <ref target="/wiki/Ivy_Substation" title="Ivy Substation">Ivy Substation</ref> theater in <ref target="/wiki/Culver_City,_California" title="Culver City, California">Culver City, California</ref>. The following year, a production was staged by the <ref target="/wiki/Williamstown,_Massachusetts" title="Williamstown, Massachusetts">Williamstown</ref> Theatre Festival, which had presented the <ref target="/wiki/United_States" title="United States">American</ref> premiere of Miller's <ref target="/wiki/The_Ride_Down_Mt._Morgan" title="The Ride Down Mt. Morgan">The Ride Down Mt. Morgan</ref>.</p>
<p>After fifteen previews, a Broadway revival directed by <ref target="/wiki/Scott_Ellis" title="Scott Ellis">Scott Ellis</ref> opened on May 1, 2002 at the <ref target="/wiki/American_Airlines_Theatre" title="American Airlines Theatre">American Airlines Theatre</ref>, where it ran for 62 performances. The cast included <ref target="/wiki/Chris_O%27Donnell" title="Chris O'Donnell">Chris O'Donnell</ref> as David Beeves, with <ref target="/wiki/Samantha_Mathis" title="Samantha Mathis">Samantha Mathis</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Mason_Adams" title="Mason Adams">Mason Adams</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/James_Rebhorn" title="James Rebhorn">James Rebhorn</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Richard_Riehle" title="Richard Riehle">Richard Riehle</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/David_Wohl_(actor)" title="David Wohl (actor)">David Wohl</ref>, and <ref target="/wiki/Sam_Robards" title="Sam Robards">Sam Robards</ref>, whose performance garnered him <ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award" title="Tony Award">Tony</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award" title="Drama Desk Award">Drama Desk Award</ref> nominations for Best Featured Actor in a Play.</p>
<p>In 2006, it was announced Ellis was directing a feature film adaptation of the play.<ref target="#cite_note-4">[4]</ref></p>
<p>The play was revived at the <ref target="/wiki/Donmar_Warehouse" title="Donmar Warehouse">Donmar Warehouse</ref>, London, in March 2008 in a production by <ref target="/wiki/Sean_Holmes" title="Sean Holmes">Sean Holmes</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-5">[5]</ref></p>
<p>The 25th of September 2012 saw the start of a UK wide tour by Sell A Door Theatre Company, in association with Mull Theatre. The tour is directed by David Hutchinson and designed by <ref target="/wiki/Richard_Evans_(designer)" title="Richard Evans (designer)">Richard Evans</ref>. The tour took in the whole of the UK from Orkney Arts Theatre to Greenwich Theatre, London.</p>

<h2>Notes[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Notes">edit</ref>]</h2>


<ref target="#cite_ref-1">^</ref> Bigsby, Christopher (2005). <ref class="external text" href="https://books.google.com/books?id=13YH9UHBkTMC&pg=PA301&lpg=PA301&dq=arthur+miller+at+bristol+old+vic&source=bl&ots=7Xwd8EEtlI&sig=au-Ale6qVENm82fEcGp7-YTy7Mw&hl=en&ei=fqakSYSEHNW5twejpo3VBA&sa=X&oi=book_result&resnum=3&ct=result#PPA58,M1" rel="nofollow">Arthur Miller a critical study</ref>. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. p. 57. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/978-0-511-26621-8" title="Special:BookSources/978-0-511-26621-8">978-0-511-26621-8</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/OCLC" title="OCLC">OCLC</ref> <ref class="external text" href="//www.worldcat.org/oclc/122260560" rel="nofollow">122260560</ref>. Retrieved 2009-02-25..mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:"\"""\"""'""'"}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}

<ref target="#cite_ref-2">^</ref> 
<p>Shelton, Mark. <ref class="external text" href="http://blogs.thestage.co.uk/shenton/2008/03/the-man-who-has-all-the-luck/#more" rel="nofollow">"The man who HAS all the luck..."</ref> The Stage. Retrieved 2009-02-25.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-3">^</ref> 
<p>Newman, Steve (February 2005). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.brooklynvoice.com/Newman/arthurmiller/ArthurMiller.html" rel="nofollow">"Arthur Miller – Playwright & Protagonist"</ref>. www.brooklynvoice.com. Retrieved 2009-02-25.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-4">^</ref> 
<ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070912131406/http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0444662/" rel="nofollow">"The Man Who Had All the Luck (2009)"</ref>. www.imdb.com. Archived from <ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0444662/" rel="nofollow">the original</ref> on September 12, 2007. Retrieved 2009-02-25.


<ref target="#cite_ref-5">^</ref> 
<p>Fisher, Philip. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.britishtheatreguide.info/reviews/manluck-rev.htm" rel="nofollow">"The British Theatre Guide: Reviews - The Man Who Had All the Luck (Donmar Warehouse)"</ref>. www.britishtheatreguide.info. Retrieved 2009-02-25.</p>


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.ibdb.com/broadway-production/the-man-who-had-all-the-luck-1601" rel="nofollow">Internet Broadway Database listing</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://theater2.nytimes.com/mem/theater/treview.html?res=9C06E7DA1531F931A35756C0A9649C8B63" rel="nofollow">2002 New York Times review</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.myculvercity.org/cultural/ivysubstation.asp?sec=arts" rel="nofollow">Ivy Substation Theater & Media Park in Culver City, CA</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Template:Arthur_Miller" title="Template:Arthur Miller">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:Arthur_Miller" title="Template talk:Arthur Miller">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:Arthur_Miller&action=edit">e</ref><ref target="/wiki/Arthur_Miller" title="Arthur Miller">Arthur Miller</ref>Plays
<ref target="/wiki/No_Villain" title="No Villain">No Villain</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/They_Too_Arise" title="They Too Arise">They Too Arise</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Honors_at_Dawn" title="Honors at Dawn">Honors at Dawn</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Golden_Years_(play)" title="The Golden Years (play)">The Golden Years</ref> (radio play)
<ref target="/wiki/That_They_May_Win" title="That They May Win">That They May Win</ref> (one-act)
<ref class="mw-selflink selflink">The Man Who Had All the Luck</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/All_My_Sons" title="All My Sons">All My Sons</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Death_of_a_Salesman" title="Death of a Salesman">Death of a Salesman</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/An_Enemy_of_the_People" title="An Enemy of the People">An Enemy of the People (adapted)</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Crucible" title="The Crucible">The Crucible</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/A_View_from_the_Bridge" title="A View from the Bridge">A View from the Bridge</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/A_Memory_of_Two_Mondays" title="A Memory of Two Mondays">A Memory of Two Mondays</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/After_the_Fall_(play)" title="After the Fall (play)">After the Fall</ref>
<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Incident_At_Vichy" title="Incident At Vichy">Incident At Vichy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Price_(play)" title="The Price (play)">The Price</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Creation_of_the_World_and_Other_Business" title="The Creation of the World and Other Business">The Creation of the World and Other Business</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Archbishop%27s_Ceiling" title="The Archbishop's Ceiling">The Archbishop's Ceiling</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_American_Clock" title="The American Clock">The American Clock</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Up_from_Paradise" title="Up from Paradise">Up from Paradise</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Elegy_for_a_Lady" title="Elegy for a Lady">Elegy for a Lady</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Some_Kind_of_Love_Story" title="Some Kind of Love Story">Some Kind of Love Story</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Everybody_Wins_(film)" title="Everybody Wins (film)">Everybody Wins</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Ride_Down_Mt._Morgan" title="The Ride Down Mt. Morgan">The Ride Down Mt. Morgan</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Last_Yankee" title="The Last Yankee">The Last Yankee</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Broken_Glass_(play)" title="Broken Glass (play)">Broken Glass</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Mr._Peters%27_Connections" title="Mr. Peters' Connections">Mr. Peters' Connections</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Resurrection_Blues" title="Resurrection Blues">Resurrection Blues</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Finishing_the_Picture" title="Finishing the Picture">Finishing the Picture</ref>
<p>Novels</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Focus_(novel)" title="Focus (novel)">Focus</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Homely_Girl:_A_Life" title="Homely Girl: A Life">Homely Girl: A Life</ref>
<p>Screenplays</p>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Hook_(screenplay)" title="The Hook (screenplay)">The Hook</ref> (1947)
<ref target="/wiki/Let%27s_Make_Love" title="Let's Make Love">Let's Make Love</ref> (1960)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Misfits_(1961_film)" title="The Misfits (1961 film)">The Misfits</ref> (1961)
<ref target="/wiki/Everybody_Wins_(film)" title="Everybody Wins (film)">Everybody Wins</ref> (1984)
<ref target="/wiki/Death_of_a_Salesman_(1985_film)" title="Death of a Salesman (1985 film)">Death of a Salesman</ref> (1985)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Crucible_(1996_film)" title="The Crucible (1996 film)">The Crucible</ref> (1995)
<p>Related</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Marilyn_Monroe" title="Marilyn Monroe">Marilyn Monroe</ref> (second wife)
<ref target="/wiki/Inge_Morath" title="Inge Morath">Inge Morath</ref> (third wife)
<ref target="/wiki/Rebecca_Miller" title="Rebecca Miller">Rebecca Miller</ref> (daughter)
<ref target="/wiki/Joan_Copeland" title="Joan Copeland">Joan Copeland</ref> (sister)
<ref target="/wiki/Arthur_Miller:_Writer" title="Arthur Miller: Writer">Arthur Miller: Writer</ref> (2017 documentary)
<ref target="/wiki/Willy_Loman" title="Willy Loman">Willy Loman</ref> (character)

<p>.</p>





<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&oldid=918628829">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&oldid=918628829</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:1940_plays" title="Category:1940 plays">1940 plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Broadway_plays" title="Category:Broadway plays">Broadway plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_by_Arthur_Miller" title="Category:Plays by Arthur Miller">Plays by Arthur Miller</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=The+Man+Who+Had+All+the+Luck" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=The+Man+Who+Had+All+the+Luck" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&oldid=918628829" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7749937" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&id=918628829" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=The+Man+Who+Had+All+the+Luck">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=The+Man+Who+Had+All+the+Luck&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://et.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck" hreflang="et" lang="et" title="The Man Who Had All the Luck – Estonian">Eesti</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7749937#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 29 September 2019, at 16:38 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.192","walltime":"0.285","ppvisitednodes":{"value":364,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":20309,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":92,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":8,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":1,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":1,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":15559,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":1,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 252.741 1 -total"," 78.30% 197.898 1 Template:Reflist"," 61.07% 154.356 1 Template:Cite_book"," 13.64% 34.466 1 Template:Italic_title"," 10.37% 26.198 4 Template:Cite_web"," 6.45% 16.296 1 Template:The_Works_of_Arthur_Miller"," 4.39% 11.090 1 Template:Navbox"," 1.21% 3.070 1 Template:Main_other"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.113","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":2763511,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1287","timestamp":"20190929163849","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"The Man Who Had All the Luck","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/The_Man_Who_Had_All_the_Luck","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7749937","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7749937","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2005-02-13T06:31:03Z","dateModified":"2019-09-29T16:38:43Z","image":"https:\/\/upload.wikimedia.org\/wikipedia\/en\/d\/dd\/ManLuckPoster.jpg","headline":"play written by Arthur Miller"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":101,"wgHostname":"mw1275"});});</p>


