



<p>The Lightning Thief (musical) - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)","wgTitle":"The Lightning Thief (musical)","wgCurRevisionId":919190001,"wgRevisionId":919190001,"wgArticleId":53855773,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["CS1 errors: dates","Pages with timeline metadata","Official website not in Wikidata","2017 musicals","Musicals based on novels","Greco-Roman mythology in popular culture","2019-2020 Broadway musicals"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug",</p>
<p>"Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)","wgRelevantArticleId":53855773,"wgRequestId":"XZgb@gpAICkAACJTemcAAABR","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgRedirectedFrom":"The_Lightning_Thief:_The_Percy_Jackson_Musical","wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgInternalRedirectTargetUrl":"/wiki/The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q29832089","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={</p>
<p>"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["mediawiki.action.view.redirect","ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head",</p>
<p>"mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>


























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>The Lightning Thief (musical)</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>
  (Redirected from <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief:_The_Percy_Jackson_Musical&redirect=no" title="The Lightning Thief: The Percy Jackson Musical">The Lightning Thief: The Percy Jackson Musical</ref>)

<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<p>The Lightning Thief:The Percy Jackson Musical<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:The_Lightning_Thief_The_Percy_Jackson_Musical_poster.jpg"></ref>Off-Broadway promotional posterMusicRob RokickiLyricsRob RokickiBookJoe TraczBasis<ref target="/wiki/The_Lightning_Thief" title="The Lightning Thief">The Lightning Thief</ref>by <ref target="/wiki/Rick_Riordan" title="Rick Riordan">Rick Riordan</ref>PremiereMarch 23, 2017: <ref target="/wiki/Lucille_Lortel_Theatre" title="Lucille Lortel Theatre">Lucille Lortel Theatre</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/New_York_City" title="New York City">New York City</ref>Productions2017 <ref target="/wiki/Off-Broadway" title="Off-Broadway">Off-Broadway</ref> 2019 National Tour2019 <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref></p>
<p>The Lightning Thief: The Percy Jackson Musical is a <ref target="/wiki/Musical_theatre" title="Musical theatre">musical</ref> with music and lyrics by Rob Rokicki and a book by Joe Tracz, based on the <ref target="/wiki/The_Lightning_Thief" title="The Lightning Thief">2005 novel of the same name</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Rick_Riordan" title="Rick Riordan">Rick Riordan</ref>. The musical follows <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Percy_Jackson_(character)" title="Percy Jackson (character)">Percy Jackson</ref>, a teenager who newly discovers that he is a <ref target="/wiki/Demigod" title="Demigod">demigod</ref> and goes on an epic quest to find <ref target="/wiki/Zeus" title="Zeus">Zeus</ref>' missing lightning bolt and prevent a war between the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Greek_gods" title="Greek gods">Greek gods</ref>.</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Background">1 Background</ref>
<ref target="#Plot">2 Plot</ref>

<ref target="#Act_1">2.1 Act 1</ref>
<ref target="#Act_2">2.2 Act 2</ref>


<ref target="#Principal_roles_and_original_cast">3 Principal roles and original cast</ref>
<ref target="#Musical_numbers">4 Musical numbers</ref>

<ref target="#Recording">4.1 Recording</ref>


<ref target="#Critical_response">5 Critical response</ref>
<ref target="#Awards_and_nominations">6 Awards and nominations</ref>
<ref target="#References">7 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">8 External links</ref>


<h2>Background[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Background">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>It was initially introduced in <ref target="/wiki/New_York_City" title="New York City">New York City</ref> by <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Theatreworks_USA" title="Theatreworks USA">Theatreworks USA</ref> in 2014 as a one-hour <ref target="/wiki/Musical_theatre" title="Musical theatre">musical</ref>, part of its free theatre series, and went into a national tour. It was announced on January 10, 2017 that a new version would be produced, with a new score and an updated, expanded script. The musical would have a limited run, with performances beginning on March 23, an opening set for April 4 and a last performance on May 6 at the <ref target="/wiki/Lucille_Lortel_Theatre" title="Lucille Lortel Theatre">Lucille Lortel Theatre</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-1">[1]</ref> The show announced its national tour on April 17, 2018, which debuted in Chicago in 2019.</p>
<p>On August 12, 2019 it was announced that the musical would play a 16-week limited run on Broadway beginning previews September 20 and an opening set for October 16 at the <ref target="/wiki/Longacre_Theatre" title="Longacre Theatre">Longacre Theatre</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-2">[2]</ref> On August 19, it was announced that the entire national tour cast would be reprising their roles for the Broadway run.<ref target="#cite_note-3">[3]</ref></p>

<h2>Plot[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Plot">edit</ref>]</h2>
<h3>Act 1[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Act 1">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Percy Jackson, a teenager with <ref target="/wiki/Attention_deficit_hyperactivity_disorder" title="Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder">ADHD</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Dyslexia" title="Dyslexia">dyslexia</ref>, is on a field trip to the <ref target="/wiki/Metropolitan_Museum_of_Art" title="Metropolitan Museum of Art">New York Metropolitan Museum of Art</ref>. While there, his substitute pre-algebra teacher, Mrs. Dodds, asks to speak with him. Once alone, Mrs. Dodds transforms into a <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Fury_(mythology)" title="Fury (mythology)">Fury</ref>, a mythological Greek demon of <ref target="/wiki/Hades" title="Hades">Hades</ref>. Thanks to a pen that transforms into a sword named Riptide, thrown to Percy by his <ref target="/wiki/Latin" title="Latin">Latin</ref> teacher, Mr. Brunner, Percy manages to fend off and vaporize Mrs. Dodds. After this incident, Percy is expelled from his school due to him failing to stay with the group, and him already being on probation. When Percy tries to explain what happened, he is shocked to find that neither Mr. Brunner or his best friend, Grover Underwood remember Mrs. Dodds, nor does anyone else ("Prologue/The Day I Got Expelled"). Percy says goodbye to them, and heads home for summer vacation.</p>
<p>Back at his apartment, his mother, Sally, seems to understand and even forgive Percy's expulsion, while her boyfriend, Gabe, does not. Gabe bullies Percy, and Sally confesses she needs to tell him about his father, who left before Percy was born. Percy, extremely bitter about his father and upset with himself for being expelled yet again, laments on his actions, being increasingly hard upon himself. Sally assures Percy the quirks and abnormalities of someone is what makes them special ("Strong"). Sally takes Percy to the beach where she met Percy's father, and the two run into Grover. Shockingly for Percy, Grover turns out to actually be a <ref target="/wiki/Satyr" title="Satyr">satyr</ref>, a Greek goat-like protector.</p>
<p>Suddenly, a <ref target="/wiki/Minotaur" title="Minotaur">Minotaur</ref> (half-bull, half-man) attacks the trio. Sally sacrifices herself so that Percy and Grover can make it to a place she calls "camp". The Minotaur kills Sally right before Percy's eyes who, in vengeance of his mother, finishes him off. Percy is kicked in the head and falls unconscious, where he dreams of a man in a Hawaiian shirt, who gives him a seashell, claiming, "What belongs to the sea can always return" ("The Minotaur/The Weirdest Dream").</p>
<p>When Percy awakes, he finds himself in a place called Camp Half-Blood. The shell the strange man in his dream gifted him remains in his pocket. The camp director, Mr. D (who is actually <ref target="/wiki/Dionysus" title="Dionysus">Dionysus</ref>, god of wine and madness), reluctantly explains to Percy that he is a <ref target="/wiki/Demigod" title="Demigod">demigod</ref>, the son of a human and a Greek god ("Another Terrible Day"). Mr. Brunner (who is really <ref target="/wiki/Chiron" title="Chiron">Chiron</ref>, an immortal centaur), is also at the camp, and explains to Percy that the gods will send a sign to claim him. However, Percy is still skeptical and angry that his father has shown no sign of care for him all these years. Luke Castellan, a nineteen-year-old son of Hermes, sympathises with Percy, telling him that lots of half-bloods never know their godly parents, as they are not claimed ("Their Sign").</p>
<p>Percy settles in and meets several other campers such as Silena Beauregard (a daughter of <ref target="/wiki/Aphrodite" title="Aphrodite">Aphrodite</ref>), Katie Gardner (a daughter of <ref target="/wiki/Demeter" title="Demeter">Demeter</ref>), Clarisse La Rue (a daughter of <ref target="/wiki/Ares" title="Ares">Ares</ref> who takes an immediate disliking to Percy), and Annabeth Chase (a daughter of <ref target="/wiki/Athena" title="Athena">Athena</ref> who took care of Percy while he was unconscious). Annabeth quickly takes the helm of the leader during a game of capture the flag, instructing Percy to sit and wait in the boys' bathroom to assure he won't "mess things up". Clarisse singles him out and tries to "pulverize" him, but the toilets unexpectedly burst to life, dousing her ("Put You in Your Place"). After things settle down, the campers, bar Clarisse, join around the campfire and vent about their unsteady, and in some cases harmful, relationships with both their godly and mortal parents ("Campfire Song").</p>
<p>Percy is claimed as the son of <ref target="/wiki/Poseidon" title="Poseidon">Poseidon</ref>, god of the sea, and it is at once rumored that <ref target="/wiki/Zeus" title="Zeus">Zeus</ref>' lightning bolt has been stolen and Percy is the number one suspect. Percy is told he and two others must go on a quest to retrieve the bolt, to prevent a war between the gods. He is also sent to receive a prophecy from the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Oracle_of_Delphi" title="Oracle of Delphi">Oracle of Delphi</ref> ("The Oracle"). However, Percy only accepts the quest because Luke hints that his mom will be in the Underworld, the target location of the search, since Hades is the rumored real thief. Annabeth and Grover force themselves into the quest, and after a pair of winged shoes is given to them from Luke, the three are pushed into the woods with little care and protection ("Killer Quest!").</p>

<h3>Act 2[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: Act 2">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The three questers have just escaped a bus, attacked by the three Furies. Just after blowing it up, they become hopelessly lost ("Lost!"). In a frantic decision, Percy suggests they should enter Aunty Em's Garden Gnome Emporium. The strange Auntie Em requests to take pictures of the three, but is revealed to actually be <ref target="/wiki/Medusa" title="Medusa">Medusa</ref>. Percy cuts off her head with his pen/sword, Riptide, and, as a joke, sends the head to the gods over the mail. Annabeth seems particularly upset with this run-in, so while Grover scouts out their surroundings, Percy confronts her about this. She confesses that for her whole life she has been ignored by everyone around her, and is desperate for a chance to prove herself to Athena, her mother, and make the history books ("My Grand Plan").</p>
<p>Grover returns with train tickets to <ref target="/wiki/St._Louis" title="St. Louis">St. Louis</ref> and they set off, encountering many dangers such as a <ref target="/wiki/Chimera_(mythology)" title="Chimera (mythology)">Chimera</ref>, nasty storms, some dam snacks and the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lotus_(mythology)" title="Lotus (mythology)">Lotus</ref> Hotel and Casino. They also meet up with Ares, who gives them a lift to Nevada ("Drive"). While on a bus ride to Los Angeles, Percy has a dream of a man speaking with someone whom the man refers to as "my lord". The powerful voice mentions sacrifices and brings up a name, Thalia ("The Weirdest Dream Reprise"). Percy wakes with a jolt and asks Grover if he has ever heard of someone named Thalia. Grover confides that a few years back he was sent to escort Luke, Annabeth and Thalia Grace, Zeus's daughter, to camp. However, the team was attacked, and Grover failed to save Thalia, who ended up <ref target="/wiki/Sacrifice" title="Sacrifice">sacrificing</ref> herself, and being turned into the tree that protects the boarders of Camp Half-Blood. He holds himself responsible, and thinks Percy will be ashamed of him ("The Tree on the Hill"). Percy assures Grover that no matter who he is or what he does, Percy will always want him as a friend.</p>
<p>The trio arrive in the Underworld, where they are given a tour of the horror by <ref target="/wiki/Charon" title="Charon">Charon</ref> and several long-dead musicians ("DOA"). Percy realizes that the lightning bolt is hidden in his backpack, and the three work out the possibilities of how it could have gotten there. An incident where Percy is nearly dragged into <ref target="/wiki/Tartarus" title="Tartarus">Tartarus</ref> by the shoes Luke gave him occurs and the group is discovered. After a brief conversation with an innocent Hades, Percy withdraws the shell from his pocket and blows it, realizing it was from Poseidon, and it opens a portal out of the Underworld. Vowing to return to save his mom, Percy, Annabeth and Grover escape. Percy hypothesizes that Ares is the one who planted the bolt in his bag and comes to terms with both himself and Poseidon, declaring himself a son of Poseidon, and uses his gift with water and the help of Annabeth and Grover to best Ares ("Son of Poseidon").</p>
<p>The trio return to camp heroes, but Percy couldn't be more troubled. He confides in Luke that he feels just as confused as before, and Luke agrees, stating he felt similar after his own quest. Luke inadvertently tells Percy that he is the true lightning thief and that he has teamed up with Kronos to get back at the gods, who he feels have done him wrong ("The Last Day of Summer"). Luke attacks Percy and escapes. Percy declares that there will be a war no matter how they try to stall it, but he and his friends will be prepared and do whatever it takes to fight it ("Bring on the Monsters").</p>

<h2>Principal roles and original cast[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: Principal roles and original cast">edit</ref>]</h2>


<p>Character(s)</p>

<p>Original <ref target="/wiki/Lucille_Lortel_Theatre" title="Lucille Lortel Theatre">Off-Broadway</ref> cast(2017)</p>

<p>US Tour Cast(2019)</p>

<p>Original <ref target="/wiki/Longacre_Theatre" title="Longacre Theatre">Broadway</ref> Cast (2019)</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Percy_Jackson" title="Percy Jackson">Percy Jackson</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Chris_McCarrell" title="Chris McCarrell">Chris McCarrell</ref>


<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Grover_Underwood" title="Grover Underwood">Grover Underwood</ref> & <ref target="/wiki/Dionysus" title="Dionysus">Mr. D (Dionysus)</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/George_Salazar" title="George Salazar">George Salazar</ref>

<p>Jorrel Javier</p>


<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Annabeth_Chase" title="Annabeth Chase">Annabeth Chase</ref>

<p>Kristin Stokes</p>


<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Luke_Castellan" title="Luke Castellan">Luke Castellan</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Ares" title="Ares">Ares</ref>, Gabe & Others

<p>James Hayden Rodriguez</p>


<p>Sally Jackson, Silena Beauregard, <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Charon_(mythology)" title="Charon (mythology)">Charon</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Pythia" title="Pythia">Oracle</ref>, & Others</p>

<p>Carrie Compere</p>

<p>Jalynn Steele</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Alecto" title="Alecto">Mrs. Dodds</ref>, Clarisse La Rue, Katie Gardner & Others

<p>Sarah Beth Pfeifer</p>


<p>Mr. Brunner/<ref target="/wiki/Chiron" title="Chiron">Chiron</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Poseidon" title="Poseidon">Poseidon</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Hades" title="Hades">Hades</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Medusa" title="Medusa">Medusa</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Cronus" title="Cronus">Kronos</ref>, & Others</p>

<p>Jonathan Raviv</p>

<ref target="/wiki/Ryan_Knowles" title="Ryan Knowles">Ryan Knowles</ref>

<h2>Musical numbers[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: Musical numbers">edit</ref>]</h2>



<p>Act 1</p>
<p>"Prologue/The Day I Got Expelled" – Percy, Mr. Brunner, Mrs. Dodds, Grover, Company</p>
<p>"Strong" – Sally and Percy</p>
<p>"The Minotaur/The Weirdest Dream" – Percy, Sally, Grover and Company</p>
<p>"Another Terrible Day" – Mr. D</p>
<p>"Their Sign" – Chiron, Percy and Luke</p>
<p>"Put You in Your Place" – Clarisse, Annabeth, Percy and Company</p>
<p>"The Campfire Song" – Luke, Annabeth, Percy, Grover, Katie, Silena, and Chiron</p>
<p>"The Oracle" – Oracle, Ensemble</p>
<p>"Good Kid" – Percy and Company</p>
<p>"Killer Quest!" – Percy, Grover, Annabeth, and Company</p>




<p>Act 2</p>
<p>"Lost!” – Percy, Annabeth and Grover</p>
<p>"My Grand Plan" – Annabeth</p>
<p>"Drive" – Grover, Annabeth, Percy, Ares and Company</p>
<p>"The Weirdest Dream (Reprise)" – Percy, Kronos, Luke</p>
<p>"The Tree on the Hill" – Grover, Thalia, Annabeth, Luke, Percy, Company</p>
<p>"D.O.A." – Charon and Company</p>
<p>"Son of Poseidon" – Percy, Ares, Annabeth, Grover, Sally, Company</p>
<p>"The Last Day of Summer" – Percy, Luke, Company</p>
<p>"Bring on the Monsters"– Percy, Annabeth, Grover, Clarisse, Chiron, Silena, and Luke</p>



<h3>Recording[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: Recording">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The original cast album was released on July 7, 2017. For a limited-time, Broadway Records offered a special package that included an official Lightning Thief T-shirt in addition to a physical copy of the cast album.<ref target="#cite_note-4">[4]</ref></p>

<h2>Critical response[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=8" title="Edit section: Critical response">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>The Lightning Thief: The Percy Jackson Musical has received positive reviews from critics. Fern Siegel, for <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/The_Huffington_Post" title="The Huffington Post">The Huffington Post</ref>, praised the musical for its dialogue, story and cast, calling it "a reminder that Off-Broadway is an important venue for musicals",<ref target="#cite_note-THP-5">[5]</ref> while Raven Snook, for <ref target="/wiki/Time_Out_(magazine)" title="Time Out (magazine)">Time Out</ref>, describe it as "worthy of the gods".<ref target="#cite_note-Time_Out-6">[6]</ref></p>
<ref target="/wiki/Frank_Scheck" title="Frank Scheck">Frank Scheck</ref>, in reviewing the production for <ref target="/wiki/The_Hollywood_Reporter" title="The Hollywood Reporter">The Hollywood Reporter</ref>, wrote that the musical "proves far more enjoyable than the misbegotten <ref target="/wiki/Percy_Jackson_%26_the_Olympians:_The_Lightning_Thief" title="Percy Jackson & the Olympians: The Lightning Thief">2010 film version</ref> or its <ref target="/wiki/Percy_Jackson:_Sea_of_Monsters" title="Percy Jackson: Sea of Monsters">2013 sequel</ref>" and "also provides an excellent if irreverent introduction to <ref target="/wiki/Greek_mythology" title="Greek mythology">Greek mythology</ref> that just might persuade some kids to dig deeper."<ref target="#cite_note-THR-7">[7]</ref>

<h2>Awards and nominations[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=9" title="Edit section: Awards and nominations">edit</ref>]</h2>


<p>Year</p>

<p>Award</p>

<p>Category</p>

<p>Nominee</p>

<p>Result</p>


<p>2017</p>

<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award" title="Drama Desk Award">Drama Desk Award</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Musical" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Musical">Outstanding Musical</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Book_of_a_Musical" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Book of a Musical">Outstanding Book of a Musical</ref>

<p>Joe Tracz</p>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Featured_Actor_in_a_Musical" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Featured Actor in a Musical">Outstanding Featured Actor in a Musical</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/George_Salazar" title="George Salazar">George Salazar</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<p>Theater Fans' Choice Awards</p>

<p>Best Off-Broadway Musical</p>

<p>Nominated</p>


<p>2019</p>

<p>Theater Fans’ Choice Awards</p>

<p>Best Touring Production</p>

<p>Won</p>

<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=10" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>


<ref target="#cite_ref-1">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.playbill.com/article/new-version-of-the-lightning-thief-musical-to-play-off-broadway" rel="nofollow">"New Version of Lightning Thief Musical to Play Off-Broadway"</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/Playbill" title="Playbill">Playbill</ref>. January 10, 2017. Retrieved April 23, 2017..mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:"\"""\"""'""'"}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}

<ref target="#cite_ref-2">^</ref> Gans, Andrew (Mon Aug 12 11:10:43 EDT 2019). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.playbill.com/article/the-lightning-thief-the-percy-jackson-musical-is-heading-to-broadway" rel="nofollow">"The Lightning Thief: The Percy Jackson Musical Is Heading to Broadway"</ref>. Playbill. Retrieved 2019-08-28. Check date values in: |date= (<ref target="/wiki/Help:CS1_errors#bad_date" title="Help:CS1 errors">help</ref>)

<ref target="#cite_ref-3">^</ref> Clement, Olivia (2019-08-12). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.playbill.com/article/broadways-lightning-thief-finds-its-cast" rel="nofollow">"Broadway's Lightning Thief Finds Its Cast"</ref>. Playbill. Retrieved 2019-08-28.

<ref target="#cite_ref-4">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.broadwayrecords.com/cds/the-lightning-thief-original-cast-recording" rel="nofollow">"The Lightning Thief Original Cast Recording"</ref>. Broadway Records. Retrieved 2017-07-13.

<ref target="#cite_ref-THP_5-0">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/stage-door-the-lightning-thief-the-percy-jackson_us_58eef470e4b048372700d599" rel="nofollow">"Stage Door: The Lightning Thief: The Percy Jackson Musical, In & Of Itself"</ref>. <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/The_Huffington_Post" title="The Huffington Post">The Huffington Post</ref>. April 13, 2017. Retrieved April 23, 2017.

<ref target="#cite_ref-Time_Out_6-0">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.timeout.com/newyork/theater/the-lightning-thief-the-percy-jackson-musical" rel="nofollow">"The Lightning Thief: The Percy Jackson Musical"</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/Time_Out_(magazine)" title="Time Out (magazine)">Time Out</ref>. Retrieved April 23, 2017.

<ref target="#cite_ref-THR_7-0">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/review/lightning-thief-percy-jackson-musical-theater-review-991079" rel="nofollow">"'The Lightning Thief: The Percy Jackson Musical': Theater Review"</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/The_Hollywood_Reporter" title="The Hollywood Reporter">The Hollywood Reporter</ref>. April 4, 2017. Retrieved April 23, 2017.


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit&section=11" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="external text" href="http://lightningthiefmusical.com" rel="nofollow">Official website</ref>




<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&oldid=919190001">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&oldid=919190001</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:2017_musicals" title="Category:2017 musicals">2017 musicals</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Musicals_based_on_novels" title="Category:Musicals based on novels">Musicals based on novels</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Greco-Roman_mythology_in_popular_culture" title="Category:Greco-Roman mythology in popular culture">Greco-Roman mythology in popular culture</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:2019-2020_Broadway_musicals" title="Category:2019-2020 Broadway musicals">2019-2020 Broadway musicals</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:CS1_errors:_dates" title="Category:CS1 errors: dates">CS1 errors: dates</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Pages_with_timeline_metadata" title="Category:Pages with timeline metadata">Pages with timeline metadata</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Official_website_not_in_Wikidata" title="Category:Official website not in Wikidata">Official website not in Wikidata</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=The+Lightning+Thief+%28musical%29" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=The+Lightning+Thief+%28musical%29" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&oldid=919190001" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q29832089" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=The_Lightning_Thief_%28musical%29&id=919190001" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=The+Lightning+Thief+%28musical%29">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=The+Lightning+Thief+%28musical%29&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diebe_im_Olymp_(Musical)" hreflang="de" lang="de" title="Diebe im Olymp (Musical) – German">Deutsch</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lightning_Thief" hreflang="it" lang="it" title="The Lightning Thief – Italian">Italiano</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E7%9B%97%E3%81%BE%E3%82%8C%E3%81%9F%E9%9B%B7%E6%92%83_(%E3%83%9F%E3%83%A5%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B8%E3%82%AB%E3%83%AB)" hreflang="ja" lang="ja" title="盗まれた雷撃 (ミュージカル) – Japanese">日本語</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q29832089#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 2 October 2019, at 10:04 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.192","walltime":"0.262","ppvisitednodes":{"value":771,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":18101,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":1083,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":12,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":0,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":1,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":21050,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":1,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 230.212 1 -total"," 55.38% 127.481 1 Template:Reflist"," 38.46% 88.546 4 Template:Cite_web"," 24.94% 57.409 1 Template:Infobox_Musical"," 22.38% 51.530 1 Template:Infobox"," 8.86% 20.402 1 Template:Official_website"," 5.56% 12.791 3 Template:Cite_news"," 2.07% 4.760 1 Template:Column-width"," 1.97% 4.543 1 Template:If_both"," 1.93% 4.441 1 Template:Col-2"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.098","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":2889666,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1284","timestamp":"20191002100435","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"The Lightning Thief (musical)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/The_Lightning_Thief_(musical)","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q29832089","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q29832089","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2017-04-23T04:42:47Z","dateModified":"2019-10-02T10:04:40Z","image":"https:\/\/upload.wikimedia.org\/wikipedia\/en\/b\/bf\/The_Lightning_Thief_The_Percy_Jackson_Musical_poster.jpg"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":116,"wgHostname":"mw1320"});});</p>


