



<p>The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial","wgTitle":"The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial","wgCurRevisionId":897971284,"wgRevisionId":897971284,"wgArticleId":7810140,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["Articles needing additional references from August 2011","All articles needing additional references","Articles with IBDb links","1953 plays","American plays","Courts-martial in fiction","Courtroom drama plays","Military courtroom dramas","Doubleday (publisher) books","Works about ships","Adaptations of works by Herman Wouk","Works by Herman Wouk"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March",</p>
<p>"April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial","wgRelevantArticleId":7810140,"wgRequestId":"XZiGOwpAMFoAAJjBfv8AAABF","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q7720941","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":</p>
<p>!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head",</p>
<p>"mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>


























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Question_book-new.svg"></ref>This article needs additional citations for <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Verifiability" title="Wikipedia:Verifiability">verification</ref>. Please help <ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit">improve this article</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Help:Introduction_to_referencing_with_Wiki_Markup/1" title="Help:Introduction to referencing with Wiki Markup/1">adding citations to reliable sources</ref>. Unsourced material may be challenged and removed.Find sources: <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?as_eq=wikipedia&q=%22The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial%22" rel="nofollow">"The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial"</ref> – <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?tbm=nws&q=%22The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial%22+-wikipedia" rel="nofollow">news</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?&q=%22The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial%22+site:news.google.com/newspapers&source=newspapers" rel="nofollow">newspapers</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?tbs=bks:1&q=%22The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial%22+-wikipedia" rel="nofollow">books</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="//scholar.google.com/scholar?q=%22The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial%22" rel="nofollow">scholar</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="https://www.jstor.org/action/doBasicSearch?Query=%22The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial%22&acc=on&wc=on" rel="nofollow">JSTOR</ref> (August 2011) (<ref target="/wiki/Help:Maintenance_template_removal" title="Help:Maintenance template removal">Learn how and when to remove this template message</ref>)
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:CaineMutinyCourtMartial.JPG"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:CaineMutinyCourtMartial.JPG" title="Enlarge"></ref>First edition (<ref target="/wiki/Doubleday_(publisher)" title="Doubleday (publisher)">Doubleday</ref>)
<p>The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial is a two-act <ref target="/wiki/Play_(theatre)" title="Play (theatre)">play</ref>, of the <ref target="/wiki/Legal_drama" title="Legal drama">courtroom drama</ref> type, that was dramatized for the stage by <ref target="/wiki/Herman_Wouk" title="Herman Wouk">Herman Wouk</ref>, which he adapted from his own <ref target="/wiki/Novel" title="Novel">novel</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/The_Caine_Mutiny" title="The Caine Mutiny">The Caine Mutiny</ref>.</p>
<p>Wouk's novel covered a long stretch of time aboard the <ref target="/wiki/United_States_Navy" title="United States Navy">USS</ref> Caine, a Navy <ref target="/wiki/Destroyer_minesweeper" title="Destroyer minesweeper">destroyer minesweeper</ref> in the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Pacific" title="Pacific">Pacific</ref>. It begins with Willis Keith's assignment to the Caine, chronicles the mismanagement of the ship under <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Captain_Queeg" title="Captain Queeg">Philip Francis Queeg</ref>, explains how Steve Maryk relieved Queeg of command, gives an account of Maryk's <ref target="/wiki/Court-martial" title="Court-martial">court-martial</ref>, and describes the aftermath of the <ref target="/wiki/Mutiny" title="Mutiny">mutiny</ref> for all involved.</p>
<p>The play covers only the court-martial itself. Like jurors at a trial, the audience knows only what various witnesses tell of the events on the Caine.</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Production_history">1 Production history</ref>
<ref target="#Characters">2 Characters</ref>
<ref target="#Plot">3 Plot</ref>

<ref target="#Act_1:_The_Prosecution">3.1 Act 1: The Prosecution</ref>
<ref target="#Act_2:_The_Defense">3.2 Act 2: The Defense</ref>

<ref target="#Scene_1">3.2.1 Scene 1</ref>
<ref target="#Scene_2">3.2.2 Scene 2</ref>




<ref target="#See_also">4 See also</ref>
<ref target="#References">5 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">6 External links</ref>


<h2>Production history[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Production history">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>The play was first presented by Paul Gregory in the <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Granada_Theatre_(Santa_Barbara,_California)&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Granada Theatre (Santa Barbara, California) (page does not exist)">Granada Theatre</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Santa_Barbara,_California" title="Santa Barbara, California">Santa Barbara, California</ref>, on October 12, 1953 and then went on tour across the United States before being given its first performance on <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> at the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Plymouth_Theatre" title="Plymouth Theatre">Plymouth Theatre</ref> on 20 January 1954 in a production directed by <ref target="/wiki/Charles_Laughton" title="Charles Laughton">Charles Laughton</ref> and produced by <ref target="/wiki/Paul_Gregory_(producer)" title="Paul Gregory (producer)">Paul Gregory</ref>. The play starred <ref target="/wiki/Henry_Fonda" title="Henry Fonda">Henry Fonda</ref> as Barney Greenwald, the accused mutineer's defense attorney, and <ref target="/wiki/John_Hodiak" title="John Hodiak">John Hodiak</ref> as the accused, Steve Maryk; <ref target="/wiki/Lloyd_Nolan" title="Lloyd Nolan">Lloyd Nolan</ref> played Queeg. <ref target="/wiki/Herbert_Anderson" title="Herbert Anderson">Herbert Anderson</ref> (later <ref target="/wiki/Dennis_the_Menace_(1959_TV_series)" title="Dennis the Menace (1959 TV series)">Dennis the Menace</ref>'s father on TV) played Dr. Bird. <ref target="/wiki/James_Garner" title="James Garner">James Garner</ref> appeared in a non speaking role as a court martial panelist. It ran for 415 performances.</p>
<p>It was revived in 1983 at the <ref target="/wiki/Stamford_Center_for_the_Arts" title="Stamford Center for the Arts">Stamford Center for the Arts</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Stamford,_Connecticut" title="Stamford, Connecticut">Stamford, Connecticut</ref> and then at the <ref target="/wiki/Circle_in_the_Square_Theatre" title="Circle in the Square Theatre">Circle in the Square Theatre</ref> in a production directed by <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Arthur_Sherman&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Arthur Sherman (page does not exist)">Arthur Sherman</ref> with <ref target="/wiki/John_Rubinstein" title="John Rubinstein">John Rubinstein</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Michael_Moriarty" title="Michael Moriarty">Michael Moriarty</ref>, with <ref target="/wiki/Jay_O._Sanders" title="Jay O. Sanders">Jay O. Sanders</ref> as Maryk. Former <ref target="/wiki/New_York_Jets" title="New York Jets">New York Jets</ref> quarterback <ref target="/wiki/Joe_Namath" title="Joe Namath">Joe Namath</ref> (widely known as "Broadway Joe") replaced Sanders during the run of the show, marking his only appearance on Broadway.</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Charlton_Heston" title="Charlton Heston">Charlton Heston</ref> directed a critically acclaimed production in <ref target="/wiki/Los_Angeles" title="Los Angeles">Los Angeles</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/London" title="London">London</ref> in 1984 in which he starred as Queeg. Heston later brought the production to the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Kennedy_Center" title="Kennedy Center">Kennedy Center's</ref> <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Kennedy_Center#Eisenhower_Theater" title="Kennedy Center">Eisenhower Theater</ref>,<ref target="#cite_note-1">[1]</ref> where it again garnered critical acclaim.
<p>The play was first presented on television live in 1955, with Lloyd Nolan and <ref target="/wiki/Robert_Gist" title="Robert Gist">Robert Gist</ref> repeating their stage roles as Queeg and Lt. Keefer, respectively, but with <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Barry_Sullivan_(actor)" title="Barry Sullivan (actor)">Barry Sullivan</ref> as Greenwald and <ref target="/wiki/Frank_Lovejoy" title="Frank Lovejoy">Frank Lovejoy</ref> as Lt. Maryk. It was staged as an episode of the anthology series <ref target="/wiki/Ford_Star_Jubilee" title="Ford Star Jubilee">Ford Star Jubilee</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-2">[2]</ref></p>
<p>In 1988, <ref target="/wiki/Robert_Altman" title="Robert Altman">Robert Altman</ref> directed another made-for-television version of The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial for CBS. The cast included <ref target="/wiki/Eric_Bogosian" title="Eric Bogosian">Eric Bogosian</ref> as Barney Greenwald, <ref target="/wiki/Jeff_Daniels" title="Jeff Daniels">Jeff Daniels</ref> as Steve Maryk, <ref target="/wiki/Brad_Davis_(actor)" title="Brad Davis (actor)">Brad Davis</ref> as Philip Francis Queeg, <ref target="/wiki/Peter_Gallagher" title="Peter Gallagher">Peter Gallagher</ref> as John Challee, <ref target="/wiki/Kevin_J._O%27Connor_(actor)" title="Kevin J. O'Connor (actor)">Kevin J. O'Connor</ref> as Tom Keefer, <ref target="/wiki/Daniel_Jenkins" title="Daniel Jenkins">Daniel Jenkins</ref> as Willie Keith, and Altman regular <ref target="/wiki/Michael_Murphy_(actor)" title="Michael Murphy (actor)">Michael Murphy</ref> as Captain Blakely. The production was first broadcast on May 8, 1988 and was subsequently released on VHS, laserdisc, and DVD.</p>
<p>The play was again revived on Broadway in 2006 at the <ref target="/wiki/Gerald_Schoenfeld_Theatre" title="Gerald Schoenfeld Theatre">Gerald Schoenfeld Theatre</ref> in a production directed by <ref target="/wiki/Jerry_Zaks" title="Jerry Zaks">Jerry Zaks</ref>, starring <ref target="/wiki/%C5%BDeljko_Ivanek" title="Željko Ivanek">Željko Ivanek</ref> as Queeg, <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Timothy_Daly" title="Timothy Daly">Timothy Daly</ref> as prosecutor Lt. Cmdr. John Challee and <ref target="/wiki/David_Schwimmer" title="David Schwimmer">David Schwimmer</ref> as Greenwald.</p>

<h2>Characters[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Characters">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Stephen Maryk: Queeg's second-in-command on the Caine, and the officer who relieved Queeg of duty</p>
<p>Barney Greenwald: Maryk's defense attorney</p>
<p>Willis Keith: a junior officer on the Caine</p>
<p>Lt. Commander Philip Francis Queeg: commanding officer of the Caine</p>
<p>Thomas Keefer: an erudite, educated junior officer on the Caine</p>
<p>John Challee: the prosecutor</p>
<p>Randolph Patterson Southard: a Navy captain, called as an expert witness on destroyers</p>
<p>Dr. Allen Winston Bird & Dr. Forrest Lundeen: a pair of psychiatrists called to testify about Queeg's mental fitness</p>
<p>Junius Hannaford Urban: a young signalman on the Caine, called as a witness to the mutiny</p>
<h2>Plot[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Plot">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>The action takes place in The General Court-Martial Room of the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Twelfth_Naval_district" title="Twelfth Naval district">Twelfth Naval District</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/San_Francisco" title="San Francisco">San Francisco</ref> and in the banquet room of the <ref target="/wiki/Fairmont_San_Francisco" title="Fairmont San Francisco">Fairmont Hotel</ref>, San Francisco in February, 1945.</p>

<h3>Act 1: The Prosecution[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: Act 1: The Prosecution">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Lieutenant Stephen Maryk of the United States Naval Reserve is on trial for mutiny, because he relieved Lt. Commander Philip Francis Queeg of duty as captain of the U.S.S. Caine during <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Typhoon_Cobra_(1944)" title="Typhoon Cobra (1944)">a typhoon on December 18, 1944</ref>. Maryk insists that Queeg had gone over the edge mentally, and that his paranoid delusions were putting the ship in danger. Maryk took command, applying Article 184 of Navy Regulations, and steered the Caine directly INTO the storm—the opposite of what Queeg had wanted. The Caine and her entire crew survived, which Maryk thinks is proof that he acted appropriately.</p>
<p>Maryk's lawyer, Lt. Barney Greenwald, indicates that he thinks Maryk, whom he would much rather have prosecuted in the court-martial, was guilty. But he is determined to offer a strong defense nonetheless.</p>
<p>Philip Francis Queeg is the first witness for the prosecution, being conducted by Lt. Commander John Challee. Queeg states that, while the Caine was going through a typhoon, Steve Maryk, a disloyal and dIsgruntled officer, rebelled against him and relieved him of command without justification.</p>
<p>At this stage of the court-martial, Queeg seems like a typical tough military disciplinarian—perhaps a bit too tough, but giving no good reason to believe he has psychological problems. He is confident and articulate, and seems to be in full possession of his faculties.</p>
<p>A young signalman, Junius Urban, who was present on the bridge at the time Maryk took control, is called to testify about what happened. Urban provides a measure of comic relief, as he is poorly educated, extremely nervous, and confused about exactly what happened. His testimony tells the jury very little, but on cross-examination he lets slip that Queeg was "a nut" on numerous small matters of discipline and tidiness.</p>
<p>Captain Randolph Southard, an experienced naval officer called as an expert on destroyer ship-handling, testifies that, under the weather circumstances described on the night of the mutiny, Queeg took all the proper measures, and did exactly what a commanding officer should have done. Thus, in Southard's view, Maryk's actions were completely unjustified. However, under cross examination from Greenwald, Southard concedes that there are rare, extreme circumstances under which sailing directly into the storm would be the only way to avoid sinking.</p>
<p>Two psychiatrists who have examined Queeg, Dr. Forrest Lundeen and Dr. Allen Bird, testify that, while Queeg is far from being an ideal officer, in that he can be arrogant, overly defensive, nervous, and a bit of a bully, he is not mentally ill. Under cross-examination from Greenwald, however, each of them, Dr. Lundeen in particular, acknowledges that some of Queeg's traits do come close to the textbook definition of <ref target="/wiki/Paranoia" title="Paranoia">paranoia</ref>.</p>
<p>Willis Keith, a friend of Maryk's, testifies as to the events leading to the mutiny. Keith says that Queeg was a coward, that he was giving panicky, conflicting orders during the typhoon, requiring Maryk to take action. During cross-examination, Greenwald gets Keith to tell numerous stories of Queeg's ineptitude, vanity, dishonesty, pettiness and seeming cowardice; indeed, one such incident led the Caine's officers to give Queeg the nickname "Old Yellowstain."</p>
<p>Lt. Thomas Keefer, another friend of Maryk's, is a much less helpful witness from the defense standpoint. Keefer, an intellectual who was a writer in civilian life, having published some of his short stories in national magazines, indicates that Queeg was not insane, and that Maryk was ill-advised to relieve him of command. Maryk is stunned by Keefer's betrayal, since to a large extent, Keefer was the one who convinced Maryk that Queeg might be insane in the first place, and Maryk wants Greenwald to cross-examine him vigorously. Instead, Greenwald has no questions for Keefer, explaining to Maryk, "Implicating Keefer harms you." He wants one hero, not two mutineers.</p>
<p>As the trial adjourns for the day, Maryk expresses dissatisfaction with Greenwald's defense. Greenwald explains that he has good reasons for not asking Keefer any questions, and states once again that he thinks Maryk is guilty. Even if Queeg was far from an ideal officer, Greenwald believes, Maryk's first duty was to carry on fighting the war, and doing his best to keep the Caine in action. All authority figures tend to look like irrational tyrants to their subordinates, Greenwald says, whether they are or not.</p>

<h3>Act 2: The Defense[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: Act 2: The Defense">edit</ref>]</h3>
<h4>Scene 1[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: Scene 1">edit</ref>]</h4>
<p>As Greenwald begins his defense the following morning, he calls Steve Maryk as the first of his two witnesses.</p>
<p>Maryk explains in great detail what a petty, vindictive, isolated and paranoid commanding officer Queeg was. In particular, Maryk dwells on "The Strawberry Incident," which convinced much of the crew that Queeg was insane. Shortly after the Caine received a shipment of strawberries from another ship, a large portion went missing. Because the circumstances were superficially similar to another incident that occurred during peacetime under Queeg's command, he drew the same conclusion: someone must have stolen them from the locked cabinets using a copy of the original key. Queeg's steadfast belief that this was a repeat of the same <ref target="/wiki/Modus_operandi" title="Modus operandi">MO</ref> as the first thief led him to divert extraordinary amounts of manpower to search the ship for copy of the locked cabinet key. When several of the enlisted men confessed to Maryk that they simply stole it from the cabinets when they were unlocked and that no duplicate key existed, Queeg's refusal to accept their confession and dedication to proving his theory convinces the officers that Queeg is trying to reenact the circumstances of his prior success against all evidence to the contrary. Finally, Maryk describes the events of the night of the mutiny itself. Maryk says the Caine was foundering, on the verge of sinking, and that Queeg was too frightened and paranoid to take the proper steps to save the ship. Only at this most desperate moment did Maryk see fit to take command. After the ship was out of danger, Maryk wrote a full account of his actions in the ship's log. He claims that Queeg came to him and proposed erasing this embarrassing incident from the log—a serious breach of Naval ethics. Maryk refused to do so, electing instead to take full responsibility for his actions.</p>
<p>The prosecuting attorney, John Challee, asks Maryk about his background. Maryk answers that he is a fisherman's son, and has been around boats his whole life. However, Maryk confesses that he was only an average student in high school and a poor student in college. It becomes clear in Challee's cross-examination that, while Maryk uses words like "paranoid," he really knows little about psychology, and was not truly qualified to judge anyone's mental health.</p>
<p>At this point, Greenwald calls Queeg as his second and final defense witness. Under intense cross-examination, Queeg is asked to justify each and every one of his questionable actions as commanding officer of the Caine. He becomes nervous and testy, and starts playing with a pair of steel balls that he uses to control his nerves. He tells a few small lies to cover up petty offenses. When his lies are revealed, his demeanor changes, and he becomes angry and combative. When asked about Maryk's charge that Queeg had wanted to alter the ship's log, an enraged Queeg rants that he was surrounded by disloyal officers, and looks exactly like the panicky paranoid that Maryk had described.</p>
<p>When the defense rests, Queeg is a broken man, and everyone else present knows that Maryk will be acquitted. Maryk is relieved if not totally ecstatic, and invites Greenwald to a celebration party that Tom Keefer is hosting later that evening. (Keefer has written a novel about the war, titled Multitudes, Multitudes, and even though it is still not finished, he has received an advance of one thousand dollars from a publisher.) Greenwald looks dejected and far from triumphant, but he reluctantly agrees to attend the party.</p>

<h4>Scene 2[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: Scene 2">edit</ref>]</h4>
<p>At the party, Keefer, Keith, Maryk and their friends are celebrating both Maryk's acquittal and the large advance that Keefer has received on Multitudes, Multitudes, when Greenwald walks in, heavily intoxicated from a number of drinks he and Challee had shared before he showed up to the party, over which they had discussed details Greenwald had left out of the case at the end of the trial. (The two men had been law-school classmates, and good friends, before both had enlisted. Challee had accused Greenwald, during the trial, of "shyster tactics," and Greenwald had invited Challee for drinks after the trial to smooth things over and to provide such details. These had resulted in Challee understanding the reasons for Greenwald's trial strategy, and the two had once again parted as friends.) Greenwald proposes a toast to "Old Yellowstain." Unlike the Caine's junior officers, Greenwald feels deep regret over what he did to Queeg on the witness stand. To Greenwald, though Phil Queeg was a weak man, perhaps he was still an admirable one, and Queeg and career military men like him are actually heroic figures, since they were the ones putting their lives on the line to defend America - something none of the others were doing because they knew they could never truly enrich themselves financially in the armed forces. Greenwald, who is Jewish, understands what the consequences would have been had the Axis won World War II. He refers to Nazi atrocities, declaring, at one point, that it is men like Queeg who have saved his own mother, Mrs. Greenwald, from having been "melted down to a bar of soap." He points out to Maryk, "Steve, this dinner's a phony. You're guilty. 'Course you're only half guilty. There's another guy who's stayed very neatly out of the picture."</p>
<p>Greenwald feels sorry for Queeg, because he sees that Queeg was not wrong about being surrounded by disloyal officers. Greenwald believes that Tom Keefer is the guiltiest party in the whole affair. Maryk, after all, really knew very little about psychology or psychiatry, so where would he have obtained any of his half-formed ideas about paranoia and mental illness, if not from Keefer?</p>
<p>Greenwald had defended Maryk to the best of his abilities, which had led him to destroy Queeg on the witness stand, because he had seen that Maryk was essentially a decent man trying to do the right thing. He views Keefer, on the other hand, as an upper-class intellectual snob who had regarded himself as superior to Queeg, the career military man, and had helped turn Maryk and the rest of the crew against him. Greenwald suggests that Maryk could even have reasoned with Queeg during the typhoon had Keefer not poisoned the atmosphere in the first place.</p>
<p>Greenwald denounces Keefer, and throws a glassful of yellow wine into his face (echoing the insulting nickname of "Old Yellowstain" the crew members had given to Queeg), before walking out of the party, an act which ruins it.</p>

<h2>See also[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=8" title="Edit section: See also">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Caine_Mutiny" title="The Caine Mutiny">The Caine Mutiny</ref> - Herman Wouk's original novel
<ref target="/wiki/The_Caine_Mutiny_(film)" title="The Caine Mutiny (film)">The Caine Mutiny (film)</ref> - the 1954 film based on it
<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=9" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>


<ref target="#cite_ref-1">^</ref> King, Wayne; Molotsky, Irvin (12 June 1986). <ref class="external text" href="https://www.nytimes.com/1986/06/12/us/briefing-cannes-on-the-potomac.html" rel="nofollow">"BRIEFING; Cannes on the Potomac"</ref> – via NYTimes.com..mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:"\"""\"""'""'"}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}

<ref target="#cite_ref-2">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0581148/" rel="nofollow">"The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial"</ref> – via www.imdb.com.


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit&section=10" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.ibdb.com/broadway-production/4224" rel="nofollow">The Caine Mutiny Court Martial</ref> at the <ref target="/wiki/Internet_Broadway_Database" title="Internet Broadway Database">Internet Broadway Database</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0046816/" rel="nofollow">The Caine Mutiny</ref> on <ref target="/wiki/IMDb" title="IMDb">IMDb</ref> (1954 film)




<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&oldid=897971284">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&oldid=897971284</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:1953_plays" title="Category:1953 plays">1953 plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:American_plays" title="Category:American plays">American plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Courts-martial_in_fiction" title="Category:Courts-martial in fiction">Courts-martial in fiction</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Courtroom_drama_plays" title="Category:Courtroom drama plays">Courtroom drama plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Military_courtroom_dramas" title="Category:Military courtroom dramas">Military courtroom dramas</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Doubleday_(publisher)_books" title="Category:Doubleday (publisher) books">Doubleday (publisher) books</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Works_about_ships" title="Category:Works about ships">Works about ships</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Adaptations_of_works_by_Herman_Wouk" title="Category:Adaptations of works by Herman Wouk">Adaptations of works by Herman Wouk</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Works_by_Herman_Wouk" title="Category:Works by Herman Wouk">Works by Herman Wouk</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_needing_additional_references_from_August_2011" title="Category:Articles needing additional references from August 2011">Articles needing additional references from August 2011</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:All_articles_needing_additional_references" title="Category:All articles needing additional references">All articles needing additional references</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_IBDb_links" title="Category:Articles with IBDb links">Articles with IBDb links</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&oldid=897971284" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7720941" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&id=897971284" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=The+Caine+Mutiny+Court-Martial&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>



<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7720941#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Add interlanguage links">Add links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 20 May 2019, at 14:48 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.384","walltime":"0.511","ppvisitednodes":{"value":449,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":11652,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":303,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":8,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":1,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":1,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":5534,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":1,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 421.524 1 -total"," 43.71% 184.251 1 Template:Reflist"," 38.13% 160.743 2 Template:Cite_web"," 27.76% 117.033 1 Template:More_citations_needed"," 23.82% 100.418 1 Template:Ambox"," 14.53% 61.235 1 Template:IMDb_title"," 11.93% 50.298 1 Template:Find_sources_mainspace"," 10.28% 43.316 1 Template:Italic_title"," 4.04% 17.043 1 Template:EditAtWikidata"," 2.77% 11.671 2 Template:Str_len"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.200","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":3158552,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1241","timestamp":"20190911190400","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/The_Caine_Mutiny_Court-Martial","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7720941","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7720941","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2006-11-06T21:23:30Z","dateModified":"2019-05-20T14:48:53Z","image":"https:\/\/upload.wikimedia.org\/wikipedia\/en\/2\/2c\/CaineMutinyCourtMartial.JPG","headline":"play"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":119,"wgHostname":"mw1255"});});</p>


