



<p>Three Days of Rain - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"Three_Days_of_Rain","wgTitle":"Three Days of Rain","wgCurRevisionId":918664507,"wgRevisionId":918664507,"wgArticleId":4400802,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["CS1 maint: archived copy as title","2006 plays","Broadway plays","Plays by Richard Greenberg"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"Three_Days_of_Rain","wgRelevantArticleId":4400802,"wgRequestId":</p>
<p>"XZEJAQpAADkAAA9zkrQAAAAR","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q7797440","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready",</p>
<p>"mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP",</p>
<p>"ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>

























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>Three Days of Rain</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<p>Not to be confused with <ref target="/wiki/Three_Days_of_Rain_(film)" title="Three Days of Rain (film)">Three Days of Rain (film)</ref>.</p>
<p>Three Days RainWritten by<ref target="/wiki/Richard_Greenberg" title="Richard Greenberg">Richard Greenberg</ref>Characters2 male, 1 femaleDate premiered1997Place premiered<ref target="/wiki/South_Coast_Repertory" title="South Coast Repertory">South Coast Repertory</ref><ref target="/wiki/Costa_Mesa,_California" title="Costa Mesa, California">Costa Mesa, California</ref>Original languageEnglishGenreDramaSetting<ref target="/wiki/Manhattan" title="Manhattan">Manhattan</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/United_States" title="United States">United States</ref></p>
<p>Three Days of Rain is a play by <ref target="/wiki/Richard_Greenberg" title="Richard Greenberg">Richard Greenberg</ref> that was commissioned and produced by <ref target="/wiki/South_Coast_Repertory" title="South Coast Repertory">South Coast Repertory</ref> in 1997. The title comes from a line from <ref target="/wiki/W._S._Merwin" title="W. S. Merwin">W. S. Merwin</ref>'s poem, "For the Anniversary of My Death" (1967). The play has often been called <ref target="/wiki/Tom_Stoppard" title="Tom Stoppard">Stoppardian</ref> but Greenberg says he wasn't aware of Stoppard's work before he wrote the play but instead claims <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/The_Forsyte_Saga_(1967_series)" title="The Forsyte Saga (1967 series)">1967 BBC series The Forsyte Saga</ref> was a much greater influence.<ref target="#cite_note-1">[1]</ref> Three Days of Rain was nominated for the 1998 <ref target="/wiki/Pulitzer_Prize_for_Drama" title="Pulitzer Prize for Drama">Pulitzer Prize for Drama</ref>.</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Plot">1 Plot</ref>
<ref target="#Characters">2 Characters</ref>
<ref target="#Productions">3 Productions</ref>

<ref target="#New_York_premiere">3.1 New York premiere</ref>
<ref target="#UK_Premiere">3.2 UK Premiere</ref>
<ref target="#Steppenwolf">3.3 Steppenwolf</ref>
<ref target="#Broadway">3.4 Broadway</ref>
<ref target="#Seattle_Public_Theater_Production">3.5 Seattle Public Theater Production</ref>
<ref target="#West_End">3.6 West End</ref>
<ref target="#The_Very_Little_Theater_Production">3.7 The Very Little Theater Production</ref>
<ref target="#South_Coast_Repertory">3.8 South Coast Repertory</ref>
<ref target="#Carte_Blanche_Stage_Company">3.9 Carte Blanche Stage Company</ref>
<ref target="#defunkt_theatre">3.10 defunkt theatre</ref>
<ref target="#Portland_Center_Stage">3.11 Portland Center Stage</ref>
<ref target="#Sweetline_Theatre_Company">3.12 Sweetline Theatre Company</ref>


<ref target="#References">4 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">5 External links</ref>


<h2>Plot[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Plot">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Walker<ref target="#cite_note-2">[2]</ref> and his sister Nan meet in an unoccupied studio in lower <ref target="/wiki/Manhattan" title="Manhattan">Manhattan</ref> in 1995. Walker, who had disappeared the day after his father's funeral, now months later is living in this apartment where his father Ned Janeway and business partner, Theo Wexler, once lived and worked designing the famous "Janeway House". Walker has found their father's journal and attempts to use it to understand the relationship between Ned and Theo. Nan and Walker's childhood friend Pip (Theo's son) meets with them after the reading of Ned's Will, where the three have learned that Janeway House was left to Pip rather than Ned's children. Walker is furious and accuses Pip of "working on" Ned to bequeath him the house. Pip denies this and protests that he does not understand why the house was not left to Nan and Walker as next of kin. Pip reveals that he doesn't even like the house, which prompts another tirade in Walker. Fed up with Walker's ranting, Pip fights back at Walker verbally. Pip accuses Walker of having been secretly in love with him for 18 years and reveals that he (Pip) and Nan were secretly sleeping with one another (behind Walker's back) when they were young. Walker runs off into the night. Pip says he may have gone too far and agrees with Nan to sell Walker the house. Nan tries to find Walker to tell him. Distraught when unable to find him, Nan decides to stay at the studio until he returns. After Walker returns, Nan apologizes and the two of them continue to parse Ned's concise and mysterious journal which opens with the entry: "1960, April 3–5. Three days of rain". Walker believes he's found a confession from Ned, hidden within the pages of the book, to the effect that Ned took credit for Theo's work on the house after Theo's death in 1966. Nan does not accept this interpretation but acquiesces to calm her brother. She tells Walker that Pip would sell him the house, but Walker's new-found "revelation" changes his mind about wanting it. Walker burns the diary, much to Nan's chagrin.</p>
<p>The second act shifts to an earlier time, with the same three actors portraying members of the previous generation in the same studio apartment, during April 1960 when Janeway House was designed. The actor portraying Walker becoming Walker's father Ned, the actor portraying Pip becoming Pip's father Theo, and the actor portraying Nan becoming Nan and Walker's mother, Lina. The assumptions made in the first half about the parents are shown to be wildly inaccurate. Ned is not the callous, silent patriarch he seemed to the children. Instead he is a shy stutterer, who, while an immensely talented architect, has trouble making eye contact or holding a conversation with anyone. Theo is revealed to be a charismatic man, more concerned with fame and the idea of art, than the creation of any original art itself. Lina, a bohemian southern belle, is dating Theo and their arguments are loud enough to inform the entire neighborhood. Theo and Ned attempt to design a house commissioned by Ned's parents, but Ned recognizes Theo's design as plagiarizing an existing house. Ned and Theo fight, and Theo leaves for a few days to try to work in solitude.</p>
<p>A few days later, Ned runs into Lina during a rainstorm, and they return to the apartment to escape the downpour. Ned invites Lina to stay for dinner, which leads each to reveal issues plaguing them. Lina resolves to leave before succumbing to Ned's unintentional shy sweetness, only to overhear Ned practicing telling Lina that he secretly loves her. Lina confronts Ned, and they spend three days in bed. Theo returns earlier than expected from his work retreat, finding Ned and Lina together in the apartment. He is embarrassed and leaves, with Ned trailing him. Ned attempts to apologize, but learns Theo is upset not about Lina but about failing to return with an original design. Lina persuades Ned that Theo will be okay, and that Ned should apply his emotions to draw the house she knows he imagines. He sits down to draw, suggesting that it was he who designed Janeway House and not Theo, as Walker had concluded.</p>

<h2>Characters[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Characters">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Walker/Ned</p>
<p>Walker: A quirky and unstable young man, haunted by what he sees as a destructive and unloving relationship with his parents. He has a habit of disappearing suddenly in order to avoid dealing with real life.</p>
<p>Ned: Walker and Nan's father, despite his son's depiction of him as cold and uncaring, in his youth he was a stuttering, shy, and talented architect.</p>
<p>Pip/Theo</p>
<p>Pip: A proudly naïve TV actor and family friend of the Janeway's. Handsome, and not as dumb as he looks, he is constantly frustrated by others taking their lives so seriously, and can't fathom why people see the need to incite drama.</p>
<p>Theo: Pip's father and Ned's business partner. A very charismatic man who is more interested in fame and the accolades that come with it, than creating the art that would earn it.</p>
<p>Nan/Lina</p>
<p>Nan: A practical, kind woman. Caring about her family and friends, she finds it difficult to balance her frustration at her brother Walker's craziness and Pip's naiveté. </p>
<p>Lina: Nan and Walker's mother. A southern belle, easily changeable and tempestuous, beginning to show some of the signposts of mental instability.</p>

<h2>Productions[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Productions">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Three Days of Rain premiered at the <ref target="/wiki/South_Coast_Repertory" title="South Coast Repertory">South Coast Repertory</ref> Second Stage, <ref target="/wiki/Costa_Mesa,_California" title="Costa Mesa, California">Costa Mesa, California</ref> in March 1997. The director was Evan Yionoulis, with the cast that featured </p>
<ref target="/wiki/John_Slattery" title="John Slattery">John Slattery</ref> (Walker/Ned), <ref target="/wiki/Patricia_Clarkson" title="Patricia Clarkson">Patricia Clarkson</ref> (Nan/Lina), <ref target="/wiki/Jon_Tenney" title="Jon Tenney">Jon Tenney</ref> (Pip/Theo), and Julia Pearlstein.<ref target="#cite_note-3">[3]</ref>

<h3>New York premiere[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: New York premiere">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The play received its <ref target="/wiki/Off-Broadway" title="Off-Broadway">Off-Broadway</ref> premiere at the <ref target="/wiki/Manhattan_Theatre_Club" title="Manhattan Theatre Club">Manhattan Theatre Club</ref>, at City Center Stage II, running from November 12, 1997 to January 4, 1998. Directed by Evan Yionoulis the cast featured Patricia Clarkson, John Slattery and <ref target="/wiki/Bradley_Whitford" title="Bradley Whitford">Bradley Whitford</ref>. The play won the 1998 <ref target="/wiki/Obie_Award" title="Obie Award">Obie Award</ref>, Direction, and was 1998 Drama Critics' Circle Award Runner-Up, Best American Play.<ref target="#cite_note-4">[4]</ref></p>
<p>The play was a finalist for the 1998 <ref target="/wiki/Pulitzer_Prize_for_Drama" title="Pulitzer Prize for Drama">Pulitzer Prize for Drama</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-5">[5]</ref></p>
<p>The play has enjoyed many subsequent productions in regional theatres across the United States and abroad.</p>

<h3>UK Premiere[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: UK Premiere">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>It received its <ref target="/wiki/United_Kingdom" title="United Kingdom">British</ref> premiere in 1999 at the <ref target="/wiki/Donmar_Warehouse" title="Donmar Warehouse">Donmar Warehouse</ref> with <ref target="/wiki/Colin_Firth" title="Colin Firth">Colin Firth</ref>,<ref target="#cite_note-6">[6]</ref> <ref target="/wiki/David_Morrissey" title="David Morrissey">David Morrissey</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Elizabeth_McGovern" title="Elizabeth McGovern">Elizabeth McGovern</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-7">[7]</ref></p>

<h3>Steppenwolf[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: Steppenwolf">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The <ref class="external text" href="https://www.steppenwolf.org/tickets--events/seasons/199899/three-days-of-rain/" rel="nofollow">Steppenwolf Theater Company</ref> produced the play opening February 11, 1999. It starred Tony award winner <ref target="/wiki/Tracy_Letts" title="Tracy Letts">Tracy Letts</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Amy_Morton" title="Amy Morton">Amy Morton</ref> and Ian Bradford and was directed by Tony award winner <ref target="/wiki/Anna_D._Shapiro" title="Anna D. Shapiro">Anna D. Shapiro</ref>. Richard Christiansen, critic for the Chicago tribune, wrote "In Three Days of Rain, Greenberg has constructed an almost perfect showcase for his considerable talents, and Steppenwolf has responded with a director, Anna D. Shapiro, and a cast -- Tracy Letts, Amy Morton and Ian Barford -- that gives his script a lovely, burnished glow in performance."</p>

<h3>Broadway[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: Broadway">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Arguably the most famous production to date was on <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref>, with <ref target="/wiki/Julia_Roberts" title="Julia Roberts">Julia Roberts</ref> making her stage debut. The <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/New_York_Times" title="New York Times">New York Times</ref> reviewer wrote: "And though Ms. Roberts gives a genuinely humble performance, there is no way that this show is not going to be all about Julia."<ref target="#cite_note-julia-8">[8]</ref></p>
<p>Opening on April 2006 at the <ref target="/wiki/Bernard_B._Jacobs_Theatre" title="Bernard B. Jacobs Theatre">Bernard B. Jacobs Theatre</ref>, Roberts co-starred with <ref target="/wiki/Paul_Rudd" title="Paul Rudd">Paul Rudd</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Bradley_Cooper" title="Bradley Cooper">Bradley Cooper</ref>. Although it may have been the most eagerly awaited show of the Broadway season in the popular press, it met with poor response from theatrical reviewers and closed as scheduled in June 2006. The New York Times reviewer summed up the experience: "Some movie fans may have the same fear about seeing Ms. Roberts in the flesh. They shouldn't. She looks every inch the magnetic (if theatrically challenged) movie star. Fans of Mr. Greenberg, on the other hand, should definitely stay home."<ref target="#cite_note-julia-8">[8]</ref></p>

<h3>Seattle Public Theater Production[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=8" title="Edit section: Seattle Public Theater Production">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The Seattle Public Theater (at Green Lake) produced Three Days of Rain in February 2008. The dual role of Walker/Ned was played by Evan Whitfield, with Peter Dylan O'Connor as Theo/Pip and Nan/Lina, played by Sheila Daniels, the recently named Associate Director of the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Intiman_Theater" title="Intiman Theater">Intiman Theater</ref> in Seattle. The production was directed by Aimée Bruneau.</p>

<h3>West End[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=9" title="Edit section: West End">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>A production of Three Days Of Rain, directed by <ref target="/wiki/Jamie_Lloyd_(director)" title="Jamie Lloyd (director)">Jamie Lloyd</ref> played at the <ref target="/wiki/Apollo_Theatre" title="Apollo Theatre">Apollo Theatre</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/London" title="London">London</ref> from February to May 2009, starring <ref target="/wiki/James_McAvoy" title="James McAvoy">James McAvoy</ref> as Walker/Ned, <ref target="/wiki/Nigel_Harman" title="Nigel Harman">Nigel Harman</ref> as Pip/Theo and <ref target="/wiki/Lyndsey_Marshal" title="Lyndsey Marshal">Lyndsey Marshal</ref> as Nan/Lina.<ref target="#cite_note-9">[9]</ref></p>

<h3>The Very Little Theater Production[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=10" title="Edit section: The Very Little Theater Production">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The <ref target="/wiki/Eugene,_Oregon#Performing_arts" title="Eugene, Oregon">Very Little Theater in Eugene, Oregon</ref> produced Three Days of Rain in April 2011.<ref target="#cite_note-10">[10]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-11">[11]</ref> The cast consisted of Jay Hash as Walker/Ned, Sydney Behrends as Nan/Lina, and James Lee as Theo/Pip. The production was directed by Sarah Etherton.</p>

<h3>South Coast Repertory[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=11" title="Edit section: South Coast Repertory">edit</ref>]</h3>
<ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=David_Emmes_(director)&action=edit&redlink=1" title="David Emmes (director) (page does not exist)">David Emmes</ref> was the director of the production at SCR in <ref target="/wiki/Orange_County,_California" title="Orange County, California">Orange County</ref>, beginning in May 2011. It starred <ref target="/wiki/Kevin_Rahm" title="Kevin Rahm">Kevin Rahm</ref> as Walker/Ned, <ref target="/wiki/Brendan_Hines" title="Brendan Hines">Brendan Hines</ref> as Pip/Theo, and <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Susannah_Schulman&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Susannah Schulman (page does not exist)">Susannah Schulman</ref> as Nan/Lina. This is the first time the play has returned to SCR after its premiere in 1997.<ref target="#cite_note-12">[12]</ref>

<h3>Carte Blanche Stage Company[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=12" title="Edit section: Carte Blanche Stage Company">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Three Days of Rain was produced by Carte Blanche Stage Company in Milwaukee, Wisconsin in January 2013. Directed by Bo Johnson, starring Nathanael Press as Walker/Ned, Rebecca Segal as Nan/Lina, and Matt Wickey as Pip/Theo. </p>

<h3>defunkt theatre[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=13" title="Edit section: defunkt theatre">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Three Days of Rain was produced by Portland, Oregon's acclaimed <ref class="external text" href="http://www.defunktheatre.com/" rel="nofollow">defunkt theatre</ref> in the winter of 2013. Directed by Tom Moorman, starring Matthew Kern as Walker/Ned, Christy Bigelow as Nan/Lina and Spencer Conway as Pip/Theo.</p>

<h3>Portland Center Stage[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=14" title="Edit section: Portland Center Stage">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Three Days of Rain was presented at Portland Center Stage in May 2015, with two stars from the <ref target="/wiki/NBC" title="NBC">NBC</ref> drama 'Grimm' in the cast: Sasha Roiz and Silas Weir Mitchell.<ref target="#cite_note-13">[13]</ref></p>

<h3>Sweetline Theatre Company[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=15" title="Edit section: Sweetline Theatre Company">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Three Days of Rain was presented by <ref class="external text" href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/sweetlinetheatre/about/?ref=page_internal" rel="nofollow">Sweetline Theatre</ref> in St. John's, Newfoundland, in November 2016. Directed by Danielle Irvine, it starred <ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm1747559/" rel="nofollow">Aiden Flynn</ref> as Walker/Ned, <ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm7403977/" rel="nofollow">Alexis Koetting</ref> as Nan/Lina, and <ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm3778293/?ref_=nv_sr_1" rel="nofollow">Paul Wilson</ref> as Pip/Theo.</p>

<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=16" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>


<ref target="#cite_ref-1">^</ref> Wolf, Matt. <ref class="external text" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/theatre/4536556/Richard-Greenberg-the-invisible-playwright.html" rel="nofollow">"Richard Greenberg: the invisible playwright"</ref> Telegraph, 09 February 2009

<ref target="#cite_ref-2">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://books.google.com/books?id=Uw635WVwyxIC&printsec=frontcover&dq=three+days+rain+richard+greenberg&source=bl&ots=aLWq_H0JuC&sig=8PiJ-GhuCnlIeorfScqyddz9EGo&hl=en&ei=kUxcTMCFJ4GRjAfB9tnxAw&sa=X&oi=book_result&ct=result&resnum=8&ved=0CDQQ6AEwBw" rel="nofollow">Richard Greenberg, Three Days of Rain: A Play, New York: Grove, 1997. P. 1.</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-3">^</ref> Isherwood, Charles. <ref class="external text" href="https://variety.com/1997/legit/reviews/three-days-of-rain-1200449133/" rel="nofollow">"Review. 'Three Days of Rain'"</ref> Variety, March 22, 1997

<ref target="#cite_ref-4">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.lortel.org/lla_archive/index.cfm?search_by=show&id=388" rel="nofollow">"'Three Days of Rain' 1997"</ref> Lortel.org, accessed November 15, 2015

<ref target="#cite_ref-5">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.pulitzer.org/bycat/Drama" rel="nofollow">"Pulitzer Prize for Drama"</ref> Pulitzer.org, accessed November 15, 2015

<ref target="#cite_ref-6">^</ref> Karen. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.firth.com/filmdis/3dor/3dor-part2.html" rel="nofollow">"Colin Firth in Three Days of Rain - a discussion of the play (part 2)"</ref>. Firth.com. Retrieved 7 August 2018..mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:"\"""\"""'""'"}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}

<ref target="#cite_ref-7">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.officiallondontheatre.co.uk/london_shows/show/item102655/Three-Days-Of-Rain/" rel="nofollow">"Official London Theatre - Theatre Tickets, News & Guides"</ref>. Officiallondontheatre.co.uk. Retrieved 7 August 2018.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-julia_8-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-julia_8-1">b</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://theater.nytimes.com/2006/04/20/theater/reviews/20rain.html" rel="nofollow">"Theater Review - 'Three Days of Rain'</ref> <ref target="/wiki/The_New_York_Times" title="The New York Times">The New York Times</ref>, April 20, 2006</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-9">^</ref> Billington, Michael. <ref class="external text" href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2009/feb/11/theatre" rel="nofollow">"Review. 'Three Days of Rain'"</ref> The Guardian, February 10, 2009

<ref target="#cite_ref-10">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110504023834/http://www.registerguard.com/web/entertainmentarts/26165887-41/walker-ned-act-lina-rain.html.csp" rel="nofollow">"Archived copy"</ref>. Archived from <ref class="external text" href="http://www.registerguard.com/web/entertainmentarts/26165887-41/walker-ned-act-lina-rain.html.csp" rel="nofollow">the original</ref> on 2011-05-04. Retrieved 2011-05-03.CS1 maint: archived copy as title (<ref target="/wiki/Category:CS1_maint:_archived_copy_as_title" title="Category:CS1 maint: archived copy as title">link</ref>)

<ref target="#cite_ref-11">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130913135547/http://www.eugeneweekly.com/2011/04/28/theater.html" rel="nofollow">"Archived copy"</ref>. Archived from <ref class="external text" href="http://www.eugeneweekly.com/2011/04/28/theater.html" rel="nofollow">the original</ref> on 2013-09-13. Retrieved 2011-05-03.CS1 maint: archived copy as title (<ref target="/wiki/Category:CS1_maint:_archived_copy_as_title" title="Category:CS1 maint: archived copy as title">link</ref>)

<ref target="#cite_ref-12">^</ref> McNulty, Charles. <ref class="external text" href="http://latimesblogs.latimes.com/culturemonster/2011/05/theater-review-three-days-of-rain-at-south-coast-repertory.html" rel="nofollow">"Theater review: 'Three Days of Rain' at South Coast Repertory"</ref> Los Angeles Times, May 22, 2011

<ref target="#cite_ref-13">^</ref> Wells, Carol. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.oregonlive.com/performance/index.ssf/2015/05/portland_center_stages_three_d.html" rel="nofollow">"Review"</ref> oregonlive.com, May 23, 2015


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit&section=17" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.lortel.org/Archives/Production/320" rel="nofollow">Three Days of Rain</ref> at the <ref target="/wiki/Lortel_Archives" title="Lortel Archives">Internet Off-Broadway Database</ref>




<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&oldid=918664507">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&oldid=918664507</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:2006_plays" title="Category:2006 plays">2006 plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Broadway_plays" title="Category:Broadway plays">Broadway plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_by_Richard_Greenberg" title="Category:Plays by Richard Greenberg">Plays by Richard Greenberg</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:CS1_maint:_archived_copy_as_title" title="Category:CS1 maint: archived copy as title">CS1 maint: archived copy as title</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=Three+Days+of+Rain" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=Three+Days+of+Rain" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/Three_Days_of_Rain" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:Three_Days_of_Rain" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/Three_Days_of_Rain">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/Three_Days_of_Rain" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/Three_Days_of_Rain" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&oldid=918664507" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7797440" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=Three_Days_of_Rain&id=918664507" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=Three+Days+of+Rain">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=Three+Days+of+Rain&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ko.wikipedia.org/wiki/%EC%8A%A4%EB%A6%AC_%EB%8D%B0%EC%9D%B4%EC%8A%A4_%EC%98%A4%EB%B8%8C_%EB%A0%88%EC%9D%B8" hreflang="ko" lang="ko" title="스리 데이스 오브 레인 – Korean">한국어</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7797440#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 29 September 2019, at 19:41 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Three_Days_of_Rain&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.200","walltime":"0.261","ppvisitednodes":{"value":642,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":9997,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":245,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":8,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":0,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":1,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":16236,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":0,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 208.153 1 -total"," 55.15% 114.805 1 Template:Reflist"," 43.07% 89.644 4 Template:Cite_web"," 21.87% 45.531 1 Template:Infobox_play"," 19.28% 40.130 1 Template:Infobox"," 12.22% 25.434 1 Template:Distinguish"," 5.91% 12.294 1 Template:Iobdb_title"," 2.99% 6.223 1 Template:PAGENAMEBASE"," 1.41% 2.934 1 Template:Template_other"," 1.32% 2.738 1 Template:Trim"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.089","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":2566961,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1287","timestamp":"20190929194136","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"Three Days of Rain","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Three_Days_of_Rain","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7797440","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7797440","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2006-03-15T15:11:41Z","dateModified":"2019-09-29T19:41:36Z","headline":"play by Richard Greenberg"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":85,"wgHostname":"mw1262"});});</p>


