



<p>Amazing Grace - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"Amazing_Grace","wgTitle":"Amazing Grace","wgCurRevisionId":917404387,"wgRevisionId":917404387,"wgArticleId":1395,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["EngvarB from May 2019","Use dmy dates from May 2019","Featured articles","Articles with short description","Articles with hAudio microformats","Wikipedia articles with GND identifiers","Wikipedia articles with LCCN identifiers","Wikipedia articles with MusicBrainz work identifiers","Wikipedia articles with VIAF identifiers","Wikipedia articles with WorldCat-VIAF identifiers","1772 songs","18th-century hymns","1970 singles","1971 singles","1972 singles","2007 singles","British patriotic songs","Elvis Presley songs","Joan Baez songs","Irish Singles Chart number-one singles","Number-one singles in Australia",</p>
<p>"RPM Top Singles number-one singles","Number-one singles in South Africa","UK Singles Chart number-one singles","British poems","English Christian hymns","Gospel songs","Okeh Records singles"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"Amazing_Grace","wgRelevantArticleId":1395,"wgRequestId":"XZl0gApAICoAAEfy94gAAABD","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{</p>
<p>"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q210211","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","ext.tmh.thumbnail.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready",</p>
<p>"skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["ext.cite.ux-enhancements","mw.MediaWikiPlayer.loader","mw.PopUpMediaTransform","mw.TMHGalleryHook.js","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head","mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>


























<ref id="top"></ref>


<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Featured_articles" title="This is a featured article. Click here for more information."></ref>

<p>Amazing Grace</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<p>For other uses, see <ref class="mw-disambig" href="/wiki/Amazing_Grace_(disambiguation)" title="Amazing Grace (disambiguation)">Amazing Grace (disambiguation)</ref>.</p>



<p>Christian hymn</p>
<p>Amazing Grace<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Olney_Hymns_page_53_Amazing_Grace.jpg"></ref>The bottom of page 53 of <ref target="/wiki/Olney_Hymns" title="Olney Hymns">Olney Hymns</ref> shows the first stanza of the hymn beginning "Amazing Grace!"Genre<ref target="/wiki/Hymn" title="Hymn">Hymn</ref>Written1779Text<ref target="/wiki/John_Newton" title="John Newton">John Newton</ref>Meter8.6.8.6 (<ref target="/wiki/Common_metre" title="Common metre">Common metre</ref>)MelodyNew Britain</p>
<p>"Amazing Grace" is a Christian <ref target="/wiki/Hymn" title="Hymn">hymn</ref> published in 1779, with words written in 1772 by the English poet and Anglican clergyman <ref target="/wiki/John_Newton" title="John Newton">John Newton</ref> (1725–1807).</p>
<p>Newton wrote the words from personal experience. He grew up without any particular religious conviction, but his life's path was formed by a variety of twists and coincidences that were often put into motion by others' reactions to what they took as his recalcitrant insubordination. </p>
<p>He was <ref target="/wiki/Impressment" title="Impressment">pressed</ref> (conscripted) into service in the <ref target="/wiki/Royal_Navy" title="Royal Navy">Royal Navy</ref>. After leaving the service, he became involved in the <ref target="/wiki/Atlantic_slave_trade" title="Atlantic slave trade">Atlantic slave trade</ref>. In 1748, a violent storm battered his vessel off the coast of <ref target="/wiki/County_Donegal" title="County Donegal">County Donegal</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Kingdom_of_Ireland" title="Kingdom of Ireland">Ireland</ref>, so severely that he called out to God for mercy. This moment marked <ref target="/wiki/John_Newton#Spiritual_conversion" title="John Newton">his spiritual conversion</ref> but he continued slave trading until 1754 or 1755, when he ended his seafaring altogether. He began studying <ref target="/wiki/Christian_theology" title="Christian theology">Christian theology</ref>.</p>
<p>Ordained in the <ref target="/wiki/Church_of_England" title="Church of England">Church of England</ref> in 1764, Newton became <ref target="/wiki/Curate" title="Curate">curate</ref> of <ref target="/wiki/Olney,_Buckinghamshire" title="Olney, Buckinghamshire">Olney, Buckinghamshire</ref>, where he began to write hymns with poet <ref target="/wiki/William_Cowper" title="William Cowper">William Cowper</ref>. "Amazing Grace" was written to illustrate a sermon on New Year's Day of 1773. It is unknown if there was any music accompanying the verses; it may have been chanted by the congregation. It debuted in print in 1779 in Newton and Cowper's <ref target="/wiki/Olney_Hymns" title="Olney Hymns">Olney Hymns</ref> but settled into relative obscurity in England. In the United States, "Amazing Grace" became a popular song used by Baptist and Methodist preachers as part of their evangelizing, especially in the South, during the <ref target="/wiki/Second_Great_Awakening" title="Second Great Awakening">Second Great Awakening</ref> of the early 19th century. It has been associated with more than 20 melodies. In 1835, American composer <ref target="/wiki/William_Walker_(composer)" title="William Walker (composer)">William Walker</ref> set it to the tune known as "New Britain" in a shape-note format. This is the version most frequently sung today.</p>
<p>With the message that forgiveness and redemption are possible regardless of sins committed and that the soul can be delivered from despair through the mercy of God, "Amazing Grace" is one of the most recognisable songs in the English-speaking world. Author <ref target="/wiki/Gilbert_Chase" title="Gilbert Chase">Gilbert Chase</ref> writes that it is "without a doubt the most famous of all the folk hymns."<ref target="#cite_note-1">[1]</ref> Jonathan Aitken, a Newton biographer, estimates that the song is performed about 10 million times annually.<ref target="#cite_note-aitken224-2">[2]</ref> It has had particular influence in <ref target="/wiki/Folk_music" title="Folk music">folk music</ref>, and has become an emblematic black <ref target="/wiki/Spiritual_(music)" title="Spiritual (music)">spiritual</ref>. Its universal message has been a significant factor in its crossover into secular music. "Amazing Grace" became newly popular during a revival of folk music in the US during the 1960s, and it has been recorded thousands of times during and since the 20th century, in versions that have occasionally ranked on popular music charts.</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#John_Newton's_conversion">1 John Newton's conversion</ref>
<ref target="#Olney_curate">2 Olney curate</ref>

<ref target="#Olney_Hymns">2.1 Olney Hymns</ref>
<ref target="#Critical_analysis">2.2 Critical analysis</ref>


<ref target="#Dissemination">3 Dissemination</ref>

<ref target='#"New_Britain"_tune'>3.1 "New Britain" tune</ref>
<ref target="#Urban_revival">3.2 Urban revival</ref>


<ref target="#Recorded_versions">4 Recorded versions</ref>
<ref target="#In_popular_culture">5 In popular culture</ref>
<ref target="#Modern_interpretations">6 Modern interpretations</ref>
<ref target="#Notes">7 Notes</ref>
<ref target="#References">8 References</ref>

<ref target="#Citations">8.1 Citations</ref>
<ref target="#Sources">8.2 Sources</ref>


<ref target="#External_links">9 External links</ref>


<h2>John Newton's conversion[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: John Newton's conversion">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>.mw-parser-output .quotebox{background-color:#F9F9F9;border:1px solid #aaa;box-sizing:border-box;padding:10px;font-size:88%;max-width:100%}.mw-parser-output .quotebox.floatleft{margin:0.5em 1.4em 0.8em 0}.mw-parser-output .quotebox.floatright{margin:0.5em 0 0.8em 1.4em}.mw-parser-output .quotebox.centered{margin:0.5em auto 0.8em auto}.mw-parser-output .quotebox.floatleft p,.mw-parser-output .quotebox.floatright p{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .quotebox-title{background-color:#F9F9F9;text-align:center;font-size:larger;font-weight:bold}.mw-parser-output .quotebox-quote.quoted:before{font-family:"Times New Roman",serif;font-weight:bold;font-size:large;color:gray;content:" “ ";vertical-align:-45%;line-height:0}.mw-parser-output .quotebox-quote.quoted:after{font-family:"Times New Roman",serif;font-weight:bold;font-size:large;color:gray;content:" ” ";line-height:0}.mw-parser-output .quotebox .left-aligned{text-align:left}.mw-parser-output .quotebox .right-aligned{text-align:right}.mw-parser-output .quotebox .center-aligned{text-align:center}.mw-parser-output .quotebox cite{display:block;font-style:normal}@media screen and (max-width:360px){.mw-parser-output .quotebox{min-width:100%;margin:0 0 0.8em!important;float:none!important}}</p>
<p>How industrious is Satan served. I was formerly one of his active undertemptors and had my influence been equal to my wishes I would have carried all the human race with me. A common drunkard or profligate is a petty sinner to what I was.</p>
<p>John Newton, 1778<ref target="#cite_note-moyers-3">[3]</ref></p>


<p>According to the Dictionary of American Hymnology, "Amazing Grace" is <ref target="/wiki/John_Newton" title="John Newton">John Newton</ref>'s spiritual autobiography in verse.<ref target="#cite_note-dah-4">[4]</ref></p>
<p>In 1725, Newton was born in <ref target="/wiki/Wapping" title="Wapping">Wapping</ref>, a district in London near the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Thames" title="Thames">Thames</ref>. His father was a shipping merchant who was brought up as a <ref target="/wiki/Catholic_Church" title="Catholic Church">Catholic</ref> but had <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Protestant" title="Protestant">Protestant</ref> sympathies, and his mother was a devout Independent, unaffiliated with the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Anglican_Church" title="Anglican Church">Anglican Church</ref>. She had intended Newton to become a clergyman, but she died of <ref target="/wiki/Tuberculosis" title="Tuberculosis">tuberculosis</ref> when he was six years old.<ref target="#cite_note-5">[5]</ref> For the next few years, while his father was at sea Newton was raised by his emotionally distant stepmother. He was also sent to boarding school, where he was mistreated.<ref target="#cite_note-6">[6]</ref> At the age of eleven, he joined his father on a ship as an apprentice; his seagoing career would be marked by headstrong disobedience.</p>
<p>As a youth, Newton began a pattern of coming very close to death, examining his relationship with God, then relapsing into bad habits. As a sailor, he denounced his faith after being influenced by a shipmate who discussed with him Characteristics of Men, Manners, Opinions, Times, a book by the <ref target="/wiki/Anthony_Ashley-Cooper,_3rd_Earl_of_Shaftesbury" title="Anthony Ashley-Cooper, 3rd Earl of Shaftesbury">Third Earl of Shaftesbury</ref>. In a series of letters Newton later wrote, "Like an unwary sailor who quits his port just before a rising storm, I renounced the hopes and comforts of the <ref target="/wiki/Gospel" title="Gospel">Gospel</ref> at the very time when every other comfort was about to fail me."<ref target="#cite_note-7">[7]</ref> His disobedience caused him to be <ref target="/wiki/Impressment" title="Impressment">pressed</ref> into the Royal Navy, and he took advantage of opportunities to overstay his leave. </p>
<p>He deserted the navy to visit Mary "Polly" Catlett, a family friend with whom he had fallen in love.<ref target="#cite_note-8">[8]</ref> After enduring humiliation for deserting,<ref target="#cite_note-9">[a]</ref> he was traded as crew to a slave ship. </p>
<p>He began a career in slave trading.<ref target="#cite_note-10">[b]</ref></p>

<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Newton_j.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:Newton_j.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref><ref target="/wiki/John_Newton" title="John Newton">John Newton</ref> in his later years
<p>Newton often openly mocked the captain by creating obscene poems and songs about him, which became so popular that the crew began to join in.<ref target="#cite_note-11">[9]</ref> His disagreements with several colleagues resulted in his being starved almost to death, imprisoned while at sea, and chained like the slaves they carried. He was himself enslaved and forced to work on a plantation in the British colony <ref target="/wiki/Sierra_Leone" title="Sierra Leone">Sierra Leone</ref> near the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Sherbro_River" title="Sherbro River">Sherbro River</ref>. After several months he came to think of Sierra Leone as his home, but his father intervened after Newton sent him a letter describing his circumstances, and crew from another ship happened to find him.<ref target="#cite_note-12">[c]</ref> Newton claimed the only reason he left the colony was because of Polly.<ref target="#cite_note-13">[10]</ref></p>
<p>While aboard the ship Greyhound, Newton gained notoriety for being one of the most profane men the captain had ever met. In a culture where sailors commonly used oaths and swore, Newton was admonished several times for not only using the worst words the captain had ever heard, but creating new ones to exceed the limits of verbal debauchery.<ref target="#cite_note-14">[11]</ref> In March 1748, while the Greyhound was in the North Atlantic, a violent storm came upon the ship that was so rough it swept overboard a crew member who was standing where Newton had been moments before.<ref target="#cite_note-15">[d]</ref> After hours of the crew emptying water from the ship and expecting to be capsized, Newton and another mate tied themselves to the ship's pump to keep from being washed overboard, working for several hours.<ref target="#cite_note-Martin73-16">[12]</ref> After proposing the measure to the captain, Newton had turned and said, "If this will not do, then Lord have mercy upon us!"<ref target="#cite_note-17">[13]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-18">[14]</ref> Newton rested briefly before returning to the deck to steer for the next eleven hours. During his time at the wheel, he pondered his divine challenge.<ref target="#cite_note-Martin73-16">[12]</ref></p>
<p>About two weeks later, the battered ship and starving crew landed in <ref target="/wiki/Lough_Swilly" title="Lough Swilly">Lough Swilly</ref>, Ireland. For several weeks before the storm, Newton had been reading The Christian's Pattern, a summary of the 15th-century <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/The_Imitation_of_Christ_(book)" title="The Imitation of Christ (book)">The Imitation of Christ</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Thomas_%C3%A0_Kempis" title="Thomas à Kempis">Thomas à Kempis</ref>. The memory of his own "Lord have mercy upon us!" uttered during a moment of desperation in the storm did not leave him; he began to ask if he was worthy of God's mercy or in any way redeemable. Not only had he neglected his faith but directly opposed it, mocking others who showed theirs, deriding and denouncing God as a myth. He came to believe that God had sent him a profound message and had begun to work through him.<ref target="#cite_note-19">[15]</ref></p>
<p>Newton's conversion was not immediate, but he contacted Polly's family and announced his intentions to marry her. Her parents were hesitant as he was known to be unreliable and impetuous. They knew he was profane, but they allowed him to write to Polly, and he set to begin to submit to authority for her sake.<ref target="#cite_note-martin82-85-20">[16]</ref> He sought a place on a slave ship bound for Africa, and Newton and his crewmates participated in most of the same activities he had written about before; the only immorality from which he was able to free himself was profanity. After a severe illness his resolve was renewed, yet he retained the same attitude towards slavery as was held by his contemporaries.<ref target="#cite_note-21">[e]</ref> Newton continued in the slave trade through several voyages where he sailed up rivers in Africa – , now as a captain – , procured slaves being offered for sale in larger ports, and subsequently transported them to North America. </p>
<p>In between voyages, he married Polly in 1750, and he found it more difficult to leave her at the beginning of each trip. After three shipping voyages in the slave trade, Newton was promised a position as ship's captain with cargo unrelated to slavery. But at the age of thirty, he collapsed and never sailed again.<ref target="#cite_note-22">[17]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-23">[f]</ref></p>

<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Olney_vicarage.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:Olney_vicarage.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref>The vicarage in Olney, where Newton wrote the hymn that would become "Amazing Grace"
<h2>Olney curate[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Olney curate">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Working as a customs agent in <ref target="/wiki/Liverpool" title="Liverpool">Liverpool</ref> starting in 1756, Newton began to teach himself Latin, Greek, and theology. He and Polly immersed themselves in the church community, and Newton's passion was so impressive that his friends suggested he become a priest in the Church of England. He was turned down by <ref target="/wiki/John_Gilbert_(archbishop_of_York)" title="John Gilbert (archbishop of York)">John Gilbert</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Archbishop_of_York" title="Archbishop of York">Archbishop of York</ref>, in 1758, ostensibly for having no university degree,<ref target="#cite_note-24">[18]</ref> although the more likely reasons were his leanings toward <ref target="/wiki/Evangelism" title="Evangelism">evangelism</ref> and tendency to socialise with <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Methodist" title="Methodist">Methodists</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-25">[19]</ref> Newton continued his devotions, and after being encouraged by a friend, he wrote about his experiences in the slave trade and his conversion. <ref target="/wiki/William_Legge,_2nd_Earl_of_Dartmouth" title="William Legge, 2nd Earl of Dartmouth">William Legge, 2nd Earl of Dartmouth</ref>, impressed with his story, sponsored Newton for ordination by <ref target="/wiki/John_Green_(bishop)" title="John Green (bishop)">John Green</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Bishop_of_Lincoln" title="Bishop of Lincoln">Bishop of Lincoln</ref>, and offered him the <ref target="/wiki/Curate" title="Curate">curacy</ref> of <ref target="/wiki/Olney,_Buckinghamshire" title="Olney, Buckinghamshire">Olney, Buckinghamshire</ref>, in 1764.<ref target="#cite_note-26">[20]</ref></p>

<h3>Olney Hymns[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Olney Hymns">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Main article: <ref target="/wiki/Olney_Hymns" title="Olney Hymns">Olney Hymns</ref></p>


<p>Amazing grace! (how sweet the sound)</p>
   That sav'd a wretch like me!
<p>I once was lost, but now am found,</p>
   Was blind, but now I see.

<p>'Twas grace that taught my heart to fear,</p>
   And grace my fears reliev'd;
<p>How precious did that grace appear</p>
   The hour I first believ'd!

<p>Thro' many dangers, toils, and snares,</p>
   I have already come;
<p>'Tis grace hath brought me safe thus far,</p>
   And grace will lead me home.

<p>The Lord has promis'd good to me,</p>
   His word my hope secures;
<p>He will my shield and portion be</p>
   As long as life endures.

<p>Yes, when this flesh and heart shall fail,</p>
   And mortal life shall cease;
<p>I shall possess, within the veil,</p>
   A life of joy and peace.

<p>The earth shall soon dissolve like snow,</p>
   The sun forbear to shine;
<p>But God, who call'd me here below,</p>
   Will be forever mine.


<p>John Newton, <ref target="/wiki/Olney_Hymns" title="Olney Hymns">Olney Hymns</ref>, 1779</p>


<p>Olney was a village of about 2,500 residents whose main industry was making lace by hand. The people were mostly illiterate and many of them were poor.<ref target="#cite_note-aitken224-2">[2]</ref> Newton's preaching was unique in that he shared many of his own experiences from the pulpit; many clergy preached from a distance, not admitting any intimacy with temptation or sin. He was involved in his parishioners' lives and was much loved, although his writing and delivery were sometimes unpolished.<ref target="#cite_note-27">[21]</ref> But his devotion and conviction were apparent and forceful, and he often said his mission was to "break a hard heart and to heal a broken heart".<ref target="#cite_note-pollock-28">[22]</ref> He struck a friendship with <ref target="/wiki/William_Cowper" title="William Cowper">William Cowper</ref>, a gifted writer who had failed at a career in law and suffered bouts of insanity, attempting suicide several times. Cowper enjoyed Olney – and Newton's company; he was also new to Olney and had gone through a spiritual conversion similar to Newton's. Together, their effect on the local congregation was impressive. In 1768, they found it necessary to start a weekly prayer meeting to meet the needs of an increasing number of parishioners. They also began writing lessons for children.<ref target="#cite_note-29">[23]</ref></p>
<p>Partly from Cowper's literary influence, and partly because learned vicars were expected to write verses, Newton began to try his hand at hymns, which had become popular through the language, made plain for common people to understand. Several prolific hymn writers were at their most productive in the 18th century, including <ref target="/wiki/Isaac_Watts" title="Isaac Watts">Isaac Watts</ref> – whose hymns Newton had grown up hearing<ref target="#cite_note-30">[24]</ref> – and <ref target="/wiki/Charles_Wesley" title="Charles Wesley">Charles Wesley</ref>, with whom Newton was familiar. Wesley's brother <ref target="/wiki/John_Wesley" title="John Wesley">John</ref>, the eventual founder of the Methodist Church, had encouraged Newton to go into the clergy.<ref target="#cite_note-31">[g]</ref> Watts was a pioneer in English hymn writing, basing his work after the <ref target="/wiki/Psalms" title="Psalms">Psalms</ref>. The most prevalent hymns by Watts and others were written in the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Common_meter" title="Common meter">common meter</ref> in 8.6.8.6: the first line is eight syllables and the second is six.<ref target="#cite_note-turner77-79-32">[25]</ref></p>
<p>Newton and Cowper attempted to present a poem or hymn for each prayer meeting. The lyrics to "Amazing Grace" were written in late 1772 and probably used in a prayer meeting for the first time on 1 January 1773.<ref target="#cite_note-turner77-79-32">[25]</ref> A collection of the poems Newton and Cowper had written for use in services at Olney was bound and published anonymously in 1779 under the title <ref target="/wiki/Olney_Hymns" title="Olney Hymns">Olney Hymns</ref>. Newton contributed 280 of the 348 texts in Olney Hymns; "1 Chronicles 17:16–17, Faith's Review and Expectation" was the title of the poem with the first line "Amazing grace! (how sweet the sound)".<ref target="#cite_note-dah-4">[4]</ref></p>

<h3>Critical analysis[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: Critical analysis">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The general impact of Olney Hymns was immediate and it became a widely popular tool for evangelicals in Britain for many years. Scholars appreciated Cowper's poetry somewhat more than Newton's plaintive and plain language, expressing his forceful personality. The most prevalent themes in the verses written by Newton in Olney Hymns are faith in salvation, wonder at <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Grace_(Christianity)" title="Grace (Christianity)">God's grace</ref>, his love for Jesus, and his cheerful exclamations of the joy he found in his faith.<ref target="#cite_note-33">[26]</ref> As a reflection of Newton's connection to his parishioners, he wrote many of the hymns in <ref target="/wiki/First-person_narrative" title="First-person narrative">first person</ref>, admitting his own experience with sin. Bruce Hindmarsh in Sing Them Over Again To Me: Hymns and Hymnbooks in America considers "Amazing Grace" an excellent example of Newton's testimonial style afforded by the use of this perspective.<ref target="#cite_note-hindmarsh6-34">[27]</ref> Several of Newton's hymns were recognised as great work ("Amazing Grace" was not among them), while others seem to have been included to fill in when Cowper was unable to write.<ref target="#cite_note-35">[28]</ref> Jonathan Aitken calls Newton, specifically referring to "Amazing Grace", an "unashamedly middlebrow lyricist writing for a lowbrow congregation", noting that only twenty-one of the nearly 150 words used in all six verses have more than one syllable.<ref target="#cite_note-36">[29]</ref></p>
<p>William Phipps in the <ref target="/wiki/Anglican_Theological_Review" title="Anglican Theological Review">Anglican Theological Review</ref> and author James Basker have interpreted the first stanza of "Amazing Grace" as evidence of Newton's realisation that his participation in the slave trade was his wretchedness, perhaps representing a wider common understanding of Newton's motivations.<ref target="#cite_note-phipps-37">[30]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-basker281-38">[31]</ref> Newton joined forces with a young man named <ref target="/wiki/William_Wilberforce" title="William Wilberforce">William Wilberforce</ref>, the British Member of Parliament who led the Parliamentarian campaign to abolish the slave trade in the British Empire, culminating in the <ref target="/wiki/Slave_Trade_Act_1807" title="Slave Trade Act 1807">Slave Trade Act 1807</ref>. But Newton did not become an ardent and outspoken <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Abolitionist" title="Abolitionist">abolitionist</ref> until after he left Olney in the 1780s; he is not known to have connected writing the hymn known as "Amazing Grace" to anti-slavery sentiments.<ref target="#cite_note-39">[32]</ref></p>
<p>The lyrics in Olney Hymns were arranged by their association to the Biblical verses that would be used by Newton and Cowper in their prayer meetings, and did not address any political objective. For Newton, the beginning of the year was a time to reflect on one's spiritual progress. At the same time he completed a diary – which has since been lost – that he had begun 17 years before, two years after he quit sailing. The last entry of 1772 was a recounting of how much he had changed since then.<ref target="#cite_note-aitken227-40">[33]</ref></p>


<p>And David the king came and sat before the LORD, and said, Who am I, O LORD God, and what is mine house, that thou hast brought me hitherto? And yet this was a small thing in thine eyes, O God; for thou hast also spoken of thy servant's house for a great while to come, and hast regarded me according to the estate of a man of high degree, O LORD God.</p>
<p>1 Chronicles 17:16–17, <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/King_James_Bible" title="King James Bible">King James Version</ref></p>


<p>The title ascribed to the hymn, "<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/1_Chronicles" title="1 Chronicles">1 Chronicles</ref> 17:16–17", refers to <ref target="/wiki/David" title="David">David</ref>'s reaction to the prophet <ref target="/wiki/Nathan_(prophet)" title="Nathan (prophet)">Nathan</ref> telling him that God intends to maintain his family line forever. Some Christians interpret this as a prediction that Jesus Christ, as a descendant of David, was promised by God as the salvation for all people.<ref target="#cite_note-hindmarsh8-41">[34]</ref> Newton's sermon on that January day in 1773 focused on the necessity to express one's gratitude for God's guidance, that God is involved in the daily lives of Christians though they may not be aware of it, and that patience for deliverance from the daily trials of life is warranted when the glories of eternity await.<ref target="#cite_note-42">[35]</ref> Newton saw himself a sinner like David who had been chosen, perhaps undeservedly,<ref target="#cite_note-watson215-43">[36]</ref> and was humbled by it. According to Newton, unconverted sinners were "blinded by the god of this world" until "mercy came to us not only undeserved but undesired ... our hearts endeavored to shut him out till he overcame us by the power of his grace."<ref target="#cite_note-aitken227-40">[33]</ref></p>
<p>The <ref target="/wiki/New_Testament" title="New Testament">New Testament</ref> served as the basis for many of the lyrics of "Amazing Grace". The first verse, for example, can be traced to the story of the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Prodigal_Son" title="Prodigal Son">Prodigal Son</ref>. In the <ref target="/wiki/Gospel_of_Luke" title="Gospel of Luke">Gospel of Luke</ref> the father says, "For this son of mine was dead and is alive again; he was lost, and is found". The story of Jesus <ref target="/wiki/Miracles_of_Jesus#The_blind" title="Miracles of Jesus">healing a blind man</ref> who tells the <ref target="/wiki/Pharisees" title="Pharisees">Pharisees</ref> that he can now see is told in the <ref target="/wiki/Gospel_of_John" title="Gospel of John">Gospel of John</ref>. Newton used the words "I was blind but now I see" and declared "Oh to grace how great a debtor!" in his letters and diary entries as early as 1752.<ref target="#cite_note-aitken228-44">[37]</ref> The effect of the lyrical arrangement, according to Bruce Hindmarsh, allows an instant release of energy in the exclamation "Amazing grace!", to be followed by a qualifying reply in "how sweet the sound". In An Annotated Anthology of Hymns, Newton's use of an exclamation at the beginning of his verse is called "crude but effective" in an overall composition that "suggest(s) a forceful, if simple, statement of faith".<ref target="#cite_note-watson215-43">[36]</ref> Grace is recalled three times in the following verse, culminating in Newton's most personal story of his conversion, underscoring the use of his personal testimony with his parishioners.<ref target="#cite_note-hindmarsh6-34">[27]</ref></p>
<p>The sermon preached by Newton was his last of those that William Cowper heard in Olney, since Cowper's mental instability returned shortly thereafter. Steve Turner, author of Amazing Grace: The Story of America's Most Beloved Song, suggests Newton may have had his friend in mind, employing the themes of assurance and deliverance from despair for Cowper's benefit.<ref target="#cite_note-45">[38]</ref></p>

<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:New_Britain_Southern_Harmony_Amazing_Grace.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:New_Britain_Southern_Harmony_Amazing_Grace.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref>An 1847 publication of <ref target="/wiki/Southern_Harmony" title="Southern Harmony">Southern Harmony</ref>, showing the title "New Britain" and <ref target="/wiki/Shape_note" title="Shape note">shape note</ref> music.
<h2>Dissemination[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: Dissemination">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Although it had its roots in England, "Amazing Grace" became an integral part of the Christian tapestry in the United States. More than 60 of Newton and Cowper's hymns were republished in other British hymnals and magazines, but "Amazing Grace" was not, appearing only once in a 1780 hymnal sponsored by the <ref target="/wiki/Selina_Hastings,_Countess_of_Huntingdon" title="Selina Hastings, Countess of Huntingdon">Countess of Huntingdon</ref>. Scholar <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/John_D._Julian" title="John D. Julian">John Julian</ref> commented in his 1892 <ref target="/wiki/A_Dictionary_of_Hymnology" title="A Dictionary of Hymnology">A Dictionary of Hymnology</ref> that outside of the United States, the song was unknown and it was "far from being a good example of Newton's finest work".<ref target="#cite_note-46">[39]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-47">[h]</ref> Between 1789 and 1799, four variations of Newton's hymn were published in the US in <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Baptist" title="Baptist">Baptist</ref>, <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Dutch_Reformed" title="Dutch Reformed">Dutch Reformed</ref>, and <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Congregationalist" title="Congregationalist">Congregationalist</ref> hymnodies;<ref target="#cite_note-hindmarsh8-41">[34]</ref> by 1830 <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Presbyterian" title="Presbyterian">Presbyterians</ref> and <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Methodist" title="Methodist">Methodists</ref> also included Newton's verses in their hymnals.<ref target="#cite_note-hindmarsh10-48">[40]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-49">[41]</ref></p>
<p>The greatest influences in the 19th century that propelled "Amazing Grace" to spread across the US and become a staple of religious services in many denominations and regions were the <ref target="/wiki/Second_Great_Awakening" title="Second Great Awakening">Second Great Awakening</ref> and the development of <ref target="/wiki/Shape_note" title="Shape note">shape note</ref> singing communities. A tremendous religious movement swept the US in the early 19th century, marked by the growth and popularity of churches and religious revivals that got their start on the frontier in Kentucky and Tennessee. Unprecedented gatherings of thousands of people attended <ref target="/wiki/Camp_meeting" title="Camp meeting">camp meetings</ref> where they came to experience salvation; preaching was fiery and focused on saving the sinner from temptation and backsliding.<ref target="#cite_note-turner115-116-50">[42]</ref> Religion was stripped of ornament and ceremony, and made as plain and simple as possible; sermons and songs often used repetition to get across to a rural population of poor and mostly uneducated people the necessity of turning away from sin. Witnessing and testifying became an integral component to these meetings, where a congregation member or stranger would rise and recount his turn from a sinful life to one of piety and peace.<ref target="#cite_note-hindmarsh10-48">[40]</ref> "Amazing Grace" was one of many hymns that punctuated fervent sermons, although the contemporary style used a refrain, borrowed from other hymns, that employed simplicity and repetition such as:</p>

<p>.mw-parser-output .templatequote{overflow:hidden;margin:1em 0;padding:0 40px}.mw-parser-output .templatequote .templatequotecite{line-height:1.5em;text-align:left;padding-left:1.6em;margin-top:0}</p>
<p>Amazing grace! How sweet the sound</p>
<p>That saved a wretch like me.</p>
<p>I once was lost, but now am found,</p>
<p>Was blind but now I see.</p>

<p>Shout, shout for glory,</p>
<p>Shout, shout aloud for glory;</p>
<p>Brother, sister, mourner,</p>
<p>All shout glory hallelujah.<ref target="#cite_note-turner115-116-50">[42]</ref></p>



<p>Simultaneously, an unrelated movement of communal singing was established throughout the South and Western states. A format of teaching music to illiterate people appeared in 1800. It used four sounds to symbolise the basic scale: fa-sol-la-fa-sol-la-mi-fa. Each sound was accompanied by a specifically shaped note and thus became known as shape note singing. The method was simple to learn and teach, so schools were established throughout the South and West. Communities would come together for an entire day of singing in a large building where they sat in four distinct areas surrounding an open space, one member directing the group as a whole. Other groups would sing outside, on benches set up in a square. Preachers used <ref target="/wiki/Shape_note" title="Shape note">shape note</ref> hymns to teach people on the frontier and to raise the emotion of camp meetings. Most of the music was Christian, but the purpose of communal singing was not primarily spiritual. Communities either could not afford music accompaniment or rejected it out of a <ref target="/wiki/Calvinism" title="Calvinism">Calvinistic</ref> sense of simplicity, so the songs were sung <ref target="/wiki/A_cappella" title="A cappella">a cappella</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-51">[43]</ref></p>

<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:William_Walker,_American_composer.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:William_Walker,_American_composer.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref><ref target="/wiki/William_Walker_(composer)" title="William Walker (composer)">William Walker</ref>, the American composer who first set John Newton's verses to the "New Britain" tune, creating version of the song known as "Amazing Grace"
<h3>"New Britain" tune[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=6" title='Edit section: "New Britain" tune'>edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>When originally used in Olney, it is unknown what music, if any, accompanied the verses written by John Newton. Contemporary hymnbooks did not contain music and were simply small books of religious poetry. The first known instance of Newton's lines joined to music was in A Companion to the Countess of Huntingdon's Hymns (London, 1808), where it is set to the tune "Hephzibah" by English composer <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=John_Jenkins_Husband_(composer)&action=edit&redlink=1" title="John Jenkins Husband (composer) (page does not exist)">John Husband</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-52">[44]</ref> Common meter hymns were interchangeable with a variety of tunes; more than twenty musical settings of "Amazing Grace" circulated with varying popularity until 1835, when American composer <ref target="/wiki/William_Walker_(composer)" title="William Walker (composer)">William Walker</ref> assigned Newton's words to a traditional song named "New Britain". This was an amalgamation of two melodies ("Gallaher" and "St. Mary"), first published in the Columbian Harmony by Charles H. Spilman and Benjamin Shaw (Cincinnati, 1829). Spilman and Shaw, both students at Kentucky's <ref target="/wiki/Centre_College" title="Centre College">Centre College</ref>, compiled their tunebook both for public worship and revivals, to satisfy "the wants of the Church in her triumphal march". Most of the tunes had been previously published, but "Gallaher" and "St. Mary" had not.<ref target="#cite_note-53">[45]</ref> As neither tune is attributed and both show elements of oral transmission, scholars can only speculate that they are possibly of British origin.<ref target="#cite_note-54">[46]</ref> A manuscript from 1828 by <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Lucius_Chapin&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Lucius Chapin (page does not exist)">Lucius Chapin</ref>, a famous hymn writer of that time, contains a tune very close to "St. Mary", but that does not mean that he wrote it.<ref target="#cite_note-55">[47]</ref></p>
<p>"Amazing Grace", with the words written by Newton and joined with "New Britain", the melody most currently associated with it, appeared for the first time in Walker's shape note tunebook <ref target="/wiki/Southern_Harmony" title="Southern Harmony">Southern Harmony</ref> in 1847.<ref target="#cite_note-hindmarsh11-56">[48]</ref> It was, according to author Steve Turner, a "marriage made in heaven ... The music behind 'amazing' had a sense of awe to it. The music behind 'grace' sounded graceful. There was a rise at the point of confession, as though the author was stepping out into the open and making a bold declaration, but a corresponding fall when admitting his blindness."<ref target="#cite_note-57">[49]</ref> Walker's collection was enormously popular, selling about 600,000 copies all over the US when the total population was just over 20 million. Another shape note tunebook named <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/The_Sacred_Harp" title="The Sacred Harp">The Sacred Harp</ref> (1844) by Georgia residents <ref target="/wiki/Benjamin_Franklin_White" title="Benjamin Franklin White">Benjamin Franklin White</ref> and Elisha J. King became widely influential and continues to be used.<ref target="#cite_note-turner126-58">[50]</ref></p>
<p>Another verse was first recorded in <ref target="/wiki/Harriet_Beecher_Stowe" title="Harriet Beecher Stowe">Harriet Beecher Stowe</ref>'s immensely influential 1852 anti-slavery novel <ref target="/wiki/Uncle_Tom%27s_Cabin" title="Uncle Tom's Cabin">Uncle Tom's Cabin</ref>. Three verses were emblematically sung by Tom in his hour of deepest crisis.<ref target="#cite_note-59">[51]</ref> He sings the sixth and fifth verses in that order, and Stowe included another verse, not written by Newton, that had been passed down orally in African-American communities for at least 50 years. It was one of between 50 and 70 verses of a song titled "Jerusalem, My Happy Home", which was first published in a 1790 book called A Collection of Sacred Ballads:</p>


<p>When we've been there ten thousand years,</p>
<p>Bright shining as the sun,</p>
<p>We've no less days to sing God's praise,</p>
<p>Than when we first begun.<ref target="#cite_note-60">[52]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-61">[53]</ref></p>







<ref target="/wiki/File:Amazing_Grace_-_Sacred_Harp_Singing_Society.ogg" title="File:Amazing Grace - Sacred Harp Singing Society.ogg">Shape note version of "Amazing Grace" recorded by Alan and John Lomax in Birmingham, Alabama, 1942</ref>

<p>This version also includes Newton's sixth verse, which is uncommon in recordings. This recording was made for the American Folklife Center and is in the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/U.S._Library_of_Congress" title="U.S. Library of Congress">U.S. Library of Congress</ref></p>
<p>Problems playing this file? See <ref target="/wiki/Help:Media" title="Help:Media">media help</ref>.</p>

<p>"Amazing Grace" came to be an emblem of a Christian movement and a symbol of the US itself as the country was involved in a great political experiment, attempting to employ democracy as a means of government. Shape-note singing communities, with all the members sitting around an open center, each song employing a different song leader, illustrated this in practice. Simultaneously, the US began to expand westward into previously unexplored territory that was often wilderness. The "dangers, toils, and snares" of Newton's lyrics had both literal and figurative meanings for Americans.<ref target="#cite_note-turner126-58">[50]</ref> This became poignantly true during the most serious test of American cohesion in the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/U.S._Civil_War" title="U.S. Civil War">U.S. Civil War</ref> (1861–1865). "Amazing Grace", set to "New Britain", was included in two hymnals distributed to soldiers. With death so real and imminent, religious services in the military became commonplace.<ref target="#cite_note-62">[54]</ref> The hymn was translated into other languages as well: while on the <ref target="/wiki/Trail_of_Tears" title="Trail of Tears">Trail of Tears</ref>, the <ref target="/wiki/Cherokee" title="Cherokee">Cherokee</ref> sang Christian hymns as a way of coping with the ongoing tragedy, and a version of the song by <ref target="/wiki/Samuel_Worcester" title="Samuel Worcester">Samuel Worcester</ref> that had been translated into the <ref target="/wiki/Cherokee_language" title="Cherokee language">Cherokee language</ref> became very popular.<ref target="#cite_note-63">[55]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-64">[56]</ref></p>

<h3>Urban revival[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: Urban revival">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Although "Amazing Grace" set to "New Britain" was popular, other versions existed regionally. <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Primitive_Baptist" title="Primitive Baptist">Primitive Baptists</ref> in the Appalachian region often used "New Britain" with other hymns, and sometimes sing the words of "Amazing Grace" to other folk songs, including titles such as "<ref target="/wiki/In_the_Pines" title="In the Pines">In the Pines</ref>", "Pisgah", "Primrose", and "Evan", as all are able to be sung in common meter, of which the majority of their repertoire consists.<ref target="#cite_note-65">[57]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-66">[58]</ref> In the late 19th century, Newton's verses were sung to a tune named "Arlington" as frequently as to "New Britain" for a time.</p>
<p>Two musical arrangers named <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Dwight_Moody" title="Dwight Moody">Dwight Moody</ref> and <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Ira_Sankey" title="Ira Sankey">Ira Sankey</ref> heralded another religious revival in the cities of the US and Europe, giving the song international exposure. Moody's preaching and Sankey's musical gifts were significant; their arrangements were the forerunners of <ref target="/wiki/Gospel_music" title="Gospel music">gospel music</ref>, and churches all over the US were eager to acquire them.<ref target="#cite_note-67">[59]</ref> Moody and Sankey began publishing their compositions in 1875, and "Amazing Grace" appeared three times with three different melodies, but they were the first to give it its title; hymns were typically published using the first line of the lyrics, or the name of the tune such as "New Britain". Publisher <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Edwin_Othello_Excell" title="Edwin Othello Excell">Edwin Othello Excell</ref> gave the version of "Amazing Grace" set to "New Britain" immense popularity by publishing it in a series of hymnals that were used in urban churches. Excell altered some of Walker's music, making it more contemporary and European, giving "New Britain" some distance from its rural folk-music origins. Excell's version was more palatable for a growing urban middle class and arranged for larger church choirs. Several editions featuring Newton's first three stanzas and the verse previously included by Harriet Beecher Stowe in Uncle Tom's Cabin were published by Excell between 1900 and 1910. His version of "Amazing Grace" became the standard form of the song in American churches.<ref target="#cite_note-68">[60]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-69">[61]</ref></p>





<ref target="/wiki/File:Amazing_grace2.ogg" title="File:Amazing grace2.ogg">"Amazing Grace" a cappella with hymn lining</ref>

<p>This recording of three singers was done for the Archive of American Folk-Song in Livingston, Alabama, in 1939, and is in the U.S. Library of Congress.</p>
<p>Problems playing this file? See <ref target="/wiki/Help:Media" title="Help:Media">media help</ref>.</p>

<h2>Recorded versions[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=8" title="Edit section: Recorded versions">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>With the advent of recorded music and radio, "Amazing Grace" began to cross over from primarily a gospel standard to secular audiences. The ability to record combined with the marketing of records to specific audiences allowed "Amazing Grace" to take on thousands of different forms in the 20th century. Where Edwin Othello Excell sought to make the singing of "Amazing Grace" uniform throughout thousands of churches, records allowed artists to improvise with the words and music specific to each audience. <ref target="/wiki/AllMusic" title="AllMusic">AllMusic</ref> lists over 1,000 recordings – including re-releases and compilations – as of 2019.<ref target="#cite_note-70">[62]</ref> Its first recording is an <ref target="/wiki/A_cappella" title="A cappella">a cappella</ref> version from 1922 by the Sacred Harp Choir. It was included from 1926 to 1930 in <ref target="/wiki/Okeh_Records" title="Okeh Records">Okeh Records</ref>' catalogue, which typically concentrated strongly on blues and jazz. Demand was high for black gospel recordings of the song by H. R. Tomlin and <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/J._M._Gates" title="J. M. Gates">J. M. Gates</ref>. A poignant sense of nostalgia accompanied the recordings of several gospel and blues singers in the 1940s and 1950s who used the song to remember their grandparents, traditions, and family roots.<ref target="#cite_note-71">[63]</ref> It was recorded with musical accompaniment for the first time in 1930 by <ref target="/wiki/Fiddlin%27_John_Carson" title="Fiddlin' John Carson">Fiddlin' John Carson</ref>, although to another folk hymn named "At the Cross", not to "New Britain".<ref target="#cite_note-loclist-72">[64]</ref> "Amazing Grace" is emblematic of several kinds of folk music styles, often used as the standard example to illustrate such musical techniques as <ref target="/wiki/Lining_out" title="Lining out">lining out</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Call_and_response" title="Call and response">call and response</ref>, that have been practised in both black and white folk music.<ref target="#cite_note-tallmadge-73">[65]</ref></p>


<p>Those songs come out of conviction and suffering. The worst voices can get through singing them 'cause they're telling their experiences.</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Mahalia_Jackson" title="Mahalia Jackson">Mahalia Jackson</ref><ref target="#cite_note-74">[66]</ref>


<ref target="/wiki/Mahalia_Jackson" title="Mahalia Jackson">Mahalia Jackson</ref>'s 1947 version received significant radio airplay, and as her popularity grew throughout the 1950s and 1960s, she often sang it at public events such as concerts at <ref target="/wiki/Carnegie_Hall" title="Carnegie Hall">Carnegie Hall</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-75">[67]</ref> Author James Basker states that the song has been employed by African Americans as the "paradigmatic Negro spiritual" because it expresses the joy felt at being delivered from slavery and worldly miseries.<ref target="#cite_note-basker281-38">[31]</ref> Anthony Heilbut, author of The Gospel Sound, states that the "dangers, toils, and snares" of Newton's words are a "universal testimony" of the African American experience.<ref target="#cite_note-76">[68]</ref> During the <ref target="/wiki/Civil_rights_movement" title="Civil rights movement">civil rights movement</ref> and <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Opposition_to_the_Vietnam_War" title="Opposition to the Vietnam War">opposition to the Vietnam War</ref>, the song took on a political tone. Mahalia Jackson employed "Amazing Grace" for Civil Rights marchers, writing that she used it "to give magical protection – a charm to ward off danger, an incantation to the angels of heaven to descend ... I was not sure the magic worked outside the church walls ... in the open air of Mississippi. But I wasn't taking any chances."<ref target="#cite_note-77">[69]</ref> Folk singer <ref target="/wiki/Judy_Collins" title="Judy Collins">Judy Collins</ref>, who knew the song before she could remember learning it, witnessed <ref target="/wiki/Fannie_Lou_Hamer" title="Fannie Lou Hamer">Fannie Lou Hamer</ref> leading marchers in <ref target="/wiki/Freedom_Summer" title="Freedom Summer">Mississippi in 1964</ref>, singing "Amazing Grace". Collins also considered it a <ref class="extiw" href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/talisman" title="wikt:talisman">talisman</ref> of sorts, and saw its equal emotional impact on the marchers, witnesses, and law enforcement who opposed the civil rights demonstrators.<ref target="#cite_note-moyers-3">[3]</ref> According to fellow folk singer <ref target="/wiki/Joan_Baez" title="Joan Baez">Joan Baez</ref>, it was one of the most requested songs from her audiences, but she never realised its origin as a hymn; by the time she was singing it in the 1960s she said it had "developed a life of its own".<ref target="#cite_note-78">[70]</ref> It even made an appearance at the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Woodstock_Music_Festival" title="Woodstock Music Festival">Woodstock Music Festival</ref> in 1969 during <ref target="/wiki/Arlo_Guthrie" title="Arlo Guthrie">Arlo Guthrie</ref>'s performance.<ref target="#cite_note-79">[71]</ref>





<ref target="/wiki/File:Amazing_Grace_-_Judy_Collins_1970.ogg" title="File:Amazing Grace - Judy Collins 1970.ogg">Sample of Judy Collins' version of "Amazing Grace"</ref>

<p>Collins transitions from her solo voice to the chorus backing her up</p>
<ref target="/wiki/File:Amazing_Grace-The_Royal_Scots_Dragoon_Guards_1972.ogg" title="File:Amazing Grace-The Royal Scots Dragoon Guards 1972.ogg">Sample of the Royal Scots Dragoon Guards' version of "Amazing Grace"</ref>

<p>A lone bagpipe transitions to a chorus of pipes and drums, similar to Collins' version</p>
<p>Problems playing these files? See <ref target="/wiki/Help:Media" title="Help:Media">media help</ref>.</p>

<p>Collins decided to record it in the late 1960s amid an atmosphere of counterculture introspection; she was part of an <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Encounter_group" title="Encounter group">encounter group</ref> that ended a contentious meeting by singing "Amazing Grace" as it was the only song to which all the members knew the words. Her producer was present and suggested she include a version of it on her 1970 album <ref target="/wiki/Whales_%26_Nightingales" title="Whales & Nightingales">Whales & Nightingales</ref>. Collins, who had a history of alcohol abuse, claimed that the song was able to "pull her through" to recovery.<ref target="#cite_note-moyers-3">[3]</ref> It was recorded in <ref target="/wiki/St._Paul%27s_Chapel_(Columbia_University)" title="St. Paul's Chapel (Columbia University)">St. Paul's</ref>, the chapel at <ref target="/wiki/Columbia_University" title="Columbia University">Columbia University</ref>, chosen for the acoustics. She chose an a cappella arrangement that was close to Edwin Othello Excell's, accompanied by a chorus of amateur singers who were friends of hers. Collins connected it to the Vietnam War, to which she objected: "I didn't know what else to do about the war in Vietnam. I had marched, I had voted, I had gone to jail on political actions and worked for the candidates I believed in. The war was still raging. There was nothing left to do, I thought ... but sing 'Amazing Grace'."<ref target="#cite_note-80">[72]</ref> Gradually and unexpectedly, the song began to be played on the radio, and then be requested. It rose to number 15 on the <ref target="/wiki/Billboard_Hot_100" title="Billboard Hot 100">Billboard Hot 100</ref>, remaining on the charts for 15 weeks,<ref target="#cite_note-81">[73]</ref> as if, she wrote, her fans had been "waiting to embrace it".<ref target="#cite_note-82">[74]</ref> In the UK, it charted 8 times between 1970 and 1972, peaking at number 5 and spending a total of 75 weeks on popular music charts.<ref target="#cite_note-83">[75]</ref> Her rendition also reached number 5 in New Zealand<ref target="#cite_note-84">[76]</ref> and number 12 in Ireland in 1971.<ref target="#cite_note-85">[77]</ref></p>
<p>Although Collins used it as a catharsis for her opposition to the Vietnam War, two years after her rendition, the <ref target="/wiki/Royal_Scots_Dragoon_Guards" title="Royal Scots Dragoon Guards">Royal Scots Dragoon Guards</ref>, senior <ref target="/wiki/Scottish_regiment" title="Scottish regiment">Scottish regiment</ref> of the <ref target="/wiki/British_Army" title="British Army">British Army</ref>, recorded an instrumental version featuring a <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Bagpipe" title="Bagpipe">bagpipe</ref> soloist accompanied by a <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Pipe_and_drum" title="Pipe and drum">pipe and drum</ref> band. The tempo of their arrangement was slowed to allow for the bagpipes, but it was based on Collins': it began with a bagpipe solo introduction similar to her lone voice, then it was accompanied by the band of bagpipes and horns, whereas in her version she is backed up by a chorus. It topped the <ref target="/wiki/RPM_(magazine)" title="RPM (magazine)">RPM</ref> national singles chart in Canada for three weeks,<ref target="#cite_note-86">[78]</ref> and rose as high as number 11 in the US<ref target="#cite_note-87">[79]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-88">[80]</ref> It is also a controversial instrumental, as it combined pipes with a military band. The <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Pipe_Major" title="Pipe Major">Pipe Major</ref> of the Royal Scots Dragoon Guards was summoned to <ref target="/wiki/Edinburgh_Castle" title="Edinburgh Castle">Edinburgh Castle</ref> and chastised for demeaning the bagpipes.<ref target="#cite_note-89">[81]</ref></p>
<ref target="/wiki/Aretha_Franklin" title="Aretha Franklin">Aretha Franklin</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Rod_Stewart" title="Rod Stewart">Rod Stewart</ref> also recorded "Amazing Grace" around the same time, and both of their renditions were popular.<ref target="#cite_note-90">[i]</ref> All four versions were marketed to distinct types of audiences thereby assuring its place as a pop song.<ref target="#cite_note-91">[82]</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Johnny_Cash" title="Johnny Cash">Johnny Cash</ref> recorded it on his 1975 album <ref target="/wiki/Sings_Precious_Memories" title="Sings Precious Memories">Sings Precious Memories</ref>, dedicating it to his older brother Jack, who had been killed in a mill accident when they were boys in <ref target="/wiki/Dyess,_Arkansas" title="Dyess, Arkansas">Dyess, Arkansas</ref>. Cash and his family sang it to themselves while they worked in the cotton fields following Jack's death. Cash often included the song when he toured prisons, saying "For the three minutes that song is going on, everybody is free. It just frees the spirit and frees the person."<ref target="#cite_note-moyers-3">[3]</ref>
<p>The <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/U.S._Library_of_Congress" title="U.S. Library of Congress">U.S. Library of Congress</ref> has a collection of 3,000 versions of and songs inspired by "Amazing Grace", some of which were first-time recordings by folklorists <ref target="/wiki/Alan_Lomax" title="Alan Lomax">Alan and John Lomax</ref>, a father and son team who in 1932 travelled thousands of miles across the South to capture the different regional styles of the song. More contemporary renditions include samples from such popular artists as <ref target="/wiki/Sam_Cooke" title="Sam Cooke">Sam Cooke</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/The_Soul_Stirrers" title="The Soul Stirrers">the Soul Stirrers</ref> (1963), <ref target="/wiki/The_Byrds" title="The Byrds">the Byrds</ref> (1970), <ref target="/wiki/Elvis_Presley" title="Elvis Presley">Elvis Presley</ref> (1971), <ref target="/wiki/Skeeter_Davis" title="Skeeter Davis">Skeeter Davis</ref> (1972), <ref target="/wiki/Mighty_Clouds_of_Joy" title="Mighty Clouds of Joy">Mighty Clouds of Joy</ref> (1972), <ref target="/wiki/Amazing_Rhythm_Aces" title="Amazing Rhythm Aces">Amazing Rhythm Aces</ref> (1975), <ref target="/wiki/Willie_Nelson" title="Willie Nelson">Willie Nelson</ref> (1976), <ref target="/wiki/The_Lemonheads" title="The Lemonheads">the Lemonheads</ref> (1992) and <ref target="/wiki/MNL48" title="MNL48">MNL48</ref> (2018).<ref target="#cite_note-loclist-72">[64]</ref></p>


<p>Somehow, "Amazing Grace" [embraced] core American values without ever sounding triumphant or jingoistic. It was a song that could be sung by young and old, Republican and Democrat, Southern Baptist and Roman Catholic, African American and Native American, high-ranking military officer and anticapitalist campaigner.</p>
<p>Steve Turner, 2002<ref target="#cite_note-92">[83]</ref></p>


<h2>In popular culture[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=9" title="Edit section: In popular culture">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Following the appropriation of the hymn in secular music, "Amazing Grace" became such an icon in American culture that it has been used for a variety of secular purposes and marketing campaigns, placing it in danger of becoming a <ref target="/wiki/Clich%C3%A9" title="Cliché">cliché</ref>. It has been mass-produced on souvenirs, lent its name to a <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Amazing_Grace_(comics)" title="Amazing Grace (comics)">Superman villain</ref>, appeared on <ref target="/wiki/The_Simpsons" title="The Simpsons">The Simpsons</ref> to demonstrate the redemption of a murderous character named <ref target="/wiki/Sideshow_Bob" title="Sideshow Bob">Sideshow Bob</ref>, incorporated into <ref target="/wiki/International_Society_for_Krishna_Consciousness" title="International Society for Krishna Consciousness">Hare Krishna</ref> chants and adapted for <ref target="/wiki/Wicca" title="Wicca">Wicca</ref> ceremonies.<ref target="#cite_note-93">[84]</ref> It can also be sung to the theme from <ref target="/wiki/The_Mickey_Mouse_Club" title="The Mickey Mouse Club">The Mickey Mouse Club</ref>, as <ref target="/wiki/Garrison_Keillor" title="Garrison Keillor">Garrison Keillor</ref> has observed.<ref target="#cite_note-94">[85]</ref> The hymn has been employed in several films, including <ref target="/wiki/Alice%27s_Restaurant_(film)" title="Alice's Restaurant (film)">Alice's Restaurant</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Invasion_of_the_Body_Snatchers_(1978_film)" title="Invasion of the Body Snatchers (1978 film)">Invasion of the Body Snatchers</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Coal_Miner%27s_Daughter_(film)" title="Coal Miner's Daughter (film)">Coal Miner's Daughter</ref>, and <ref target="/wiki/Silkwood" title="Silkwood">Silkwood</ref>. It is referenced in the 2006 film <ref target="/wiki/Amazing_Grace_(2006_film)" title="Amazing Grace (2006 film)">Amazing Grace</ref>, which highlights Newton's influence on the leading British abolitionist <ref target="/wiki/William_Wilberforce" title="William Wilberforce">William Wilberforce</ref>,<ref target="#cite_note-Noll15-95">[86]</ref> and in the film biography of Newton, <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Newton%27s_Grace_(film)" title="Newton's Grace (film)">Newton's Grace</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-Journal_Now_Article-96">[87]</ref> The 1982 science fiction film <ref target="/wiki/Star_Trek_II:_The_Wrath_of_Khan" title="Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan">Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan</ref> used "Amazing Grace" amid a context of Christian symbolism, to memorialise <ref target="/wiki/Spock" title="Spock">Mr. Spock</ref> following his death,<ref target="#cite_note-Noll15-95">[86]</ref> but more practically, because the song has become "instantly recognizable to many in the audience as music that sounds appropriate for a funeral" according to a Star Trek scholar.<ref target="#cite_note-porter157-97">[88]</ref> Since 1954, when an organ instrumental of "New Britain" became a best-seller, "Amazing Grace" has been associated with funerals and memorial services.<ref target="#cite_note-98">[89]</ref> It has become a song that inspires hope in the wake of tragedy, becoming a sort of "spiritual national anthem" according to authors Mary Rourke and Emily Gwathmey.<ref target="#cite_note-99">[90]</ref> For example, President <ref target="/wiki/Barack_Obama" title="Barack Obama">Barack Obama</ref> recited and then sang the hymn at the memorial service for <ref target="/wiki/Clementa_C._Pinckney" title="Clementa C. Pinckney">Clementa Pinckney</ref>, one of the victims of the <ref target="/wiki/Charleston_church_shooting" title="Charleston church shooting">2015 Charleston church shooting</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-100">[91]</ref></p>

<h2>Modern interpretations[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=10" title="Edit section: Modern interpretations">edit</ref>]</h2>




<ref target="/wiki/File:Amazing_Grace_(USAFB_strings).ogg" title="File:Amazing Grace (USAFB strings).ogg">"Amazing Grace" (string version)</ref>

<p>"Amazing Grace" string version by the United States Air Force Band, Strolling Strings</p>
<p>Problems playing this file? See <ref target="/wiki/Help:Media" title="Help:Media">media help</ref>.</p>





<ref target="/wiki/File:Amazing_Grace_(USAFB_jazz_vocal).ogg" title="File:Amazing Grace (USAFB jazz vocal).ogg">"Amazing Grace" (jazz vocal version)</ref>

<p>"Amazing Grace" jazz vocal version by the United States Air Force Band</p>
<p>Problems playing this file? See <ref target="/wiki/Help:Media" title="Help:Media">media help</ref>.</p>

<p>In recent years, the words of the hymn have been changed in some religious publications to downplay a sense of imposed self-loathing by its singers. The second line, "That saved a wretch like me!" has been rewritten as "That saved and strengthened me", "save a soul like me", or "that saved and set me free".<ref target="#cite_note-101">[92]</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Kathleen_Norris_(poet)" title="Kathleen Norris (poet)">Kathleen Norris</ref> in her book Amazing Grace: A Vocabulary of Faith characterises this transformation of the original words as "wretched English" making the line that replaces the original "laughably bland".<ref target="#cite_note-102">[93]</ref> Part of the reason for this change has been the altered interpretations of what wretchedness and grace means. Newton's <ref target="/wiki/Calvinism" title="Calvinism">Calvinistic</ref> view of <ref target="/wiki/Redemption_(theology)" title="Redemption (theology)">redemption</ref> and <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Grace_(Christianity)" title="Grace (Christianity)">divine grace</ref> formed his perspective that he considered himself a sinner so vile that he was <ref target="/wiki/Total_depravity" title="Total depravity">unable to change his life</ref> or be redeemed without God's help. Yet his lyrical subtlety, in Steve Turner's opinion, leaves the hymn's meaning open to a variety of Christian and non-Christian interpretations.<ref target="#cite_note-103">[94]</ref> "Wretch" also represents a period in Newton's life when he saw himself outcast and miserable, as he was when he was enslaved in Sierra Leone; his own arrogance was matched by how far he had fallen in his life.<ref target="#cite_note-104">[95]</ref></p>

<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Afghanistan_bagpiper.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:Afghanistan_bagpiper.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref>A Canadian <ref target="/wiki/Bagpipes" title="Bagpipes">bagpiper</ref> playing "Amazing Grace" during a memorial service, 29 October 2009, at Forward Operating Base Wilson, Afghanistan
<p>Due to its immense popularity and iconic nature, the meaning behind the words of "Amazing Grace" has become as individual as the singer or listener.<ref target="#cite_note-105">[96]</ref> Bruce Hindmarsh suggests that the secular popularity of "Amazing Grace" is due to the absence of any mention of God in the lyrics until the fourth verse (by Excell's version, the fourth verse begins "When we've been there ten thousand years"), and that the song represents the ability of humanity to transform itself instead of a transformation taking place at the hands of God. "Grace", however, had a clearer meaning to John Newton, as he used the word to represent God or the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Grace_(Christianity)" title="Grace (Christianity)">power of God</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-106">[97]</ref></p>
<p>The transformative power of the song was investigated by journalist <ref target="/wiki/Bill_Moyers" title="Bill Moyers">Bill Moyers</ref> in a documentary released in 1990. Moyers was inspired to focus on the song's power after watching a performance at <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lincoln_Center" title="Lincoln Center">Lincoln Center</ref>, where the audience consisted of Christians and non-Christians, and he noticed that it had an equal impact on everybody in attendance, unifying them.<ref target="#cite_note-pollock-28">[22]</ref> James Basker also acknowledged this force when he explained why he chose "Amazing Grace" to represent a collection of anti-slavery poetry: "there is a transformative power that is applicable ... : the transformation of sin and sorrow into grace, of suffering into beauty, of alienation into empathy and connection, of the unspeakable into imaginative literature."<ref target="#cite_note-107">[98]</ref></p>
<p>Moyers interviewed Collins, Cash, opera singer <ref target="/wiki/Jessye_Norman" title="Jessye Norman">Jessye Norman</ref>, Appalachian folk musician <ref target="/wiki/Jean_Ritchie" title="Jean Ritchie">Jean Ritchie</ref> and her family, white Sacred Harp singers in Georgia, black Sacred Harp singers in Alabama, and a prison choir at the <ref target="/wiki/Huntsville_Unit" title="Huntsville Unit">Texas State Penitentiary at Huntsville</ref>. Collins, Cash, and Norman were unable to discern if the power of the song came from the music or the lyrics. Norman, who once notably sang it at the end of a large outdoor <ref target="/wiki/Nelson_Mandela_70th_Birthday_Tribute" title="Nelson Mandela 70th Birthday Tribute">rock concert for Nelson Mandela's 70th birthday</ref>, stated, "I don't know whether it's the text – I don't know whether we're talking about the lyrics when we say that it touches so many people – or whether it's that tune that everybody knows." A prisoner interviewed by Moyers explained his literal interpretation of the second verse: "'Twas grace that taught my heart to fear, and grace my fears relieved" by saying that the fear became immediately real to him when he realised he may never get his life in order, compounded by the loneliness and restriction in prison. Gospel singer <ref target="/wiki/Marion_Williams" title="Marion Williams">Marion Williams</ref> summed up its effect: "That's a song that gets to everybody".<ref target="#cite_note-moyers-3">[3]</ref></p>
<p>The Dictionary of American Hymnology claims it is included in more than a thousand published hymnals, and recommends its use for "occasions of worship when we need to confess with joy that we are saved by God's grace alone; as a hymn of response to forgiveness of sin or as an assurance of pardon; as a confession of faith or after the sermon".<ref target="#cite_note-dah-4">[4]</ref></p>

<h2>Notes[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=11" title="Edit section: Notes">edit</ref>]</h2>


<ref target="#cite_ref-9">^</ref> Stripped of his rank, whipped in public, and subjected to the abuses directed to prisoners and other press-ganged men in the Navy, he demonstrated insolence and rebellion during his service for the next few months, remarking that the only reason he did not murder the captain or commit suicide was because he did not want Polly to think badly of him. (Martin [1950], pp. 41–47.)

<ref target="#cite_ref-10">^</ref> Newton kept a series of detailed journals as a slave trader; these are perhaps the first primary source of the <ref target="/wiki/Atlantic_slave_trade" title="Atlantic slave trade">Atlantic slave trade</ref> from the perspective of a merchant (Moyers). Women, naked or nearly so, upon their arrival on ship were claimed by the sailors, and Newton alluded to sexual misbehavior in his writings that has since been interpreted by historians to mean that he, along with other sailors, took (and presumably raped) whomever he chose. (Martin [1950], pp. 82–85)(Aitken, p. 64.)

<ref target="#cite_ref-12">^</ref> Newton's father was friends with Joseph Manesty, who intervened several times in Newton's life. Newton was supposed to go to Jamaica on Manesty's ship, but missed it while he was with the Catletts. When Newton's father got his son's letter detailing his conditions in Sierra Leone, he asked Manesty to find Newton. Manesty sent the Greyhound, which travelled along the African coast trading at various stops. An associate of Newton lit a fire, signalling to ships he was interested in trading just 30 minutes before the Greyhound appeared. (Aitken, pp. 34–35, 64–65.)

<ref target="#cite_ref-15">^</ref> Several retellings of Newton's life story claim that he was carrying slaves during the voyage in which he experienced his conversion, but the ship was carrying livestock, wood, and beeswax from the coast of Africa. (Aitken, p. 76.)

<ref target="#cite_ref-21">^</ref> When Newton began his journal in 1750, not only was slave trading seen as a respectable profession by the majority of Britons, its necessity to the overall prosperity of the kingdom was communally understood and approved. Only <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Quaker" title="Quaker">Quakers</ref>, who were much in the minority and perceived as eccentric, had raised any protest about the practice. (Martin and Spurrell [1962], pp. xi–xii.)

<ref target="#cite_ref-23">^</ref> Newton's biographers and Newton himself does not put a name to this episode other than a "fit" in which he became unresponsive, suffering dizziness and a headache. His doctor advised him not to go to sea again, and Newton complied. Jonathan Aitken called it a stroke or <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Seizure" title="Seizure">seizure</ref>, but its cause is unknown. (Martin [1950], pp. 140–141.)(Aitken, p. 125.)

<ref target="#cite_ref-31">^</ref> Watts had previously written a hymn named "Alas! And Did My Saviour Bleed" that contained the lines "Amazing pity! Grace unknown!/ And love beyond degree!". <ref target="/wiki/Philip_Doddridge" title="Philip Doddridge">Philip Doddridge</ref>, another well-known hymn writer, wrote another in 1755 titled "The Humiliation and Exaltation of God's Israel" that began "Amazing grace of God on high!" and included other similar wording to Newton's verses. Newton biographer Jonathan Aitken states that Watts had inspired most of Newton's compositions. (Turner, pp. 82–83.)(Aitken, pp. 28–29.)

<ref target="#cite_ref-47">^</ref> Only since the 1950s has it gained some popularity in the UK; not until 1964 was it published with the music most commonly associated with it. (Noll and Blumhofer, p. 8)

<ref target="#cite_ref-90">^</ref> Franklin's version is a prime example of "long meter" rendition: she sings several notes representing a syllable and the vocals are more dramatic and lilting. Her version lasts over ten minutes in comparison to the Royal Scots Dragoon Guards' that lasts under three minutes. (Tallmadge)(Turner, pp. 150–151.)


<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=12" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>
<h3>Citations[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=13" title="Edit section: Citations">edit</ref>]</h3>


<ref target="#cite_ref-1">^</ref> Chase, p. 181.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-aitken224_2-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-aitken224_2-1">b</ref> Aitken, p. 224.</p>

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-moyers_3-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-moyers_3-1">b</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-moyers_3-2">c</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-moyers_3-3">d</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-moyers_3-4">e</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Bill_Moyers" title="Bill Moyers">Moyers, Bill</ref> (director). Amazing Grace with Bill Moyers, Public Affairs Television, Inc. (1990).</p>

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-dah_4-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-dah_4-1">b</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-dah_4-2">c</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.hymnary.org/text/amazing_grace_how_sweet_the_sound" rel="nofollow">"Amazing Grace How Sweet the Sound"</ref>, Dictionary of American Hymnology. Retrieved 31 October 2009.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-5">^</ref> Martin (1950), pp. 8–9.

<ref target="#cite_ref-6">^</ref> Newton (1824), p. 12.

<ref target="#cite_ref-7">^</ref> Newton (1824), pp. 21–22.

<ref target="#cite_ref-8">^</ref> Martin (1950), p. 23.

<ref target="#cite_ref-11">^</ref> Martin (1950), pp. 51–52.

<ref target="#cite_ref-13">^</ref> Martin (1950), p. 63.

<ref target="#cite_ref-14">^</ref> Martin (1950), pp. 67–68.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Martin73_16-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Martin73_16-1">b</ref> Martin (1950), p. 73.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-17">^</ref> Newton (1824), p. 41.

<ref target="#cite_ref-18">^</ref> Martin (1950), pp. 70–71.

<ref target="#cite_ref-19">^</ref> Aitken, pp. 81–84.

<ref target="#cite_ref-martin82-85_20-0">^</ref> Martin (1950), pp. 82–85.

<ref target="#cite_ref-22">^</ref> Aitken, p. 125.

<ref target="#cite_ref-24">^</ref> Martin (1950), pp. 166–188.

<ref target="#cite_ref-25">^</ref> Aitken, pp. 153–154.

<ref target="#cite_ref-26">^</ref> Martin (1950), pp. 198–200.

<ref target="#cite_ref-27">^</ref> Martin (1950), pp. 208–217.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-pollock_28-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-pollock_28-1">b</ref> Pollock, John (2009). "Amazing Grace: The great Sea Change in the Life of John Newton", The Trinity Forum Reading, The Trinity Forum.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-29">^</ref> Turner, p. 76.

<ref target="#cite_ref-30">^</ref> Aitken, p. 28.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-turner77-79_32-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-turner77-79_32-1">b</ref> Turner, pp. 77–79.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-33">^</ref> Benson, p. 339.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-hindmarsh6_34-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-hindmarsh6_34-1">b</ref> Noll and Blumhofer, p. 6.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-35">^</ref> Benson, p. 338.

<ref target="#cite_ref-36">^</ref> Aitken, p. 226.

<ref target="#cite_ref-phipps_37-0">^</ref> Phipps, William (Summer 1990). " 'Amazing Grace' in the hymnwriter's life", <ref target="/wiki/Anglican_Theological_Review" title="Anglican Theological Review">Anglican Theological Review</ref>, 72 (3), pp. 306–313.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-basker281_38-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-basker281_38-1">b</ref> Basker, p. 281.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-39">^</ref> Aitken, p. 231.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-aitken227_40-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-aitken227_40-1">b</ref> Aitken, p. 227.</p>

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-hindmarsh8_41-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-hindmarsh8_41-1">b</ref> Noll and Blumhofer, p. 8.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-42">^</ref> Turner, p. 81.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-watson215_43-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-watson215_43-1">b</ref> Watson, p. 215.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-aitken228_44-0">^</ref> Aitken, p. 228.

<ref target="#cite_ref-45">^</ref> Turner, p. 86.

<ref target="#cite_ref-46">^</ref> Julian, p. 55.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-hindmarsh10_48-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-hindmarsh10_48-1">b</ref> Noll and Blumhofer, p. 10.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-49">^</ref> Aitken, pp. 232–233.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-turner115-116_50-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-turner115-116_50-1">b</ref> Turner, pp. 115–116.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-51">^</ref> Turner, p. 117.

<ref target="#cite_ref-52">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://hymntune.library.uiuc.edu/" rel="nofollow">The Hymn Tune Index</ref>, Search="Hephzibah". University of Illinois at Champaign-Urbana Library website. Retrieved 31 December 2010.

<ref target="#cite_ref-53">^</ref> Turner, pp. 120–122.

<ref target="#cite_ref-54">^</ref> Turner, p. 123.

<ref target="#cite_ref-55">^</ref> Rachel Wells Hall (12 May 2015). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.shenandoahharmony.com/2015/did-lucius-chapin-write-the-amazing-grace-tune/" rel="nofollow">"Did Lucius Chapin write the Amazing Grace tune?"</ref>..mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:"\"""\"""'""'"}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}

<ref target="#cite_ref-hindmarsh11_56-0">^</ref> Noll and Blumhofer, p. 11.

<ref target="#cite_ref-57">^</ref> Turner, p. 124.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-turner126_58-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-turner126_58-1">b</ref> Turner, p. 126.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-59">^</ref> Stowe, p. 417.

<ref target="#cite_ref-60">^</ref> Aitken, p. 235.

<ref target="#cite_ref-61">^</ref> Watson, p. 216.

<ref target="#cite_ref-62">^</ref> Turner, pp. 127–128.

<ref target="#cite_ref-63">^</ref> Duvall, p. 35.

<ref target="#cite_ref-64">^</ref> Swiderski, p. 91.

<ref target="#cite_ref-65">^</ref> Patterson, p. 137.

<ref target="#cite_ref-66">^</ref> Sutton, Brett (January 1982). "Shape-Note Tune Books and Primitive Hymns", Ethnomusicology, 26 (1), pp. 11–26.

<ref target="#cite_ref-67">^</ref> Turner, pp. 133–135.

<ref target="#cite_ref-68">^</ref> Noll and Blumhofer, p. 13.

<ref target="#cite_ref-69">^</ref> Turner, pp. 137–138, 140–145.

<ref target="#cite_ref-70">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://allmusic.com/" rel="nofollow">AllMusic search=Amazing Grace Song</ref>, AllMusic. Retrieved 12 January 2019.

<ref target="#cite_ref-71">^</ref> Turner, pp. 154–155.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-loclist_72-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-loclist_72-1">b</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://memory.loc.gov/diglib/ihas/html/grace/grace-timeline.html" rel="nofollow">Amazing Grace: Special Presentation: Amazing Grace Timeline</ref> United States Library of Congress Performing Arts Encyclopedia. Retrieved 1 November 2008.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-tallmadge_73-0">^</ref> Tallmadge, William (May 1961). "Dr. Watts and Mahalia Jackson: The Development, Decline, and Survival of a Folk Style in America", Ethnomusicology, 5 (2), pp. 95–99.

<ref target="#cite_ref-74">^</ref> Turner, p. 157.

<ref target="#cite_ref-75">^</ref> "Mahalia Jackson". Dictionary of American Biography, Supplement 9: 1971–1975. Charles Scribner's Sons, 1994.

<ref target="#cite_ref-76">^</ref> Turner, p. 148.

<ref target="#cite_ref-77">^</ref> Aitken, p. 236.

<ref target="#cite_ref-78">^</ref> Turner, p. 162.

<ref target="#cite_ref-79">^</ref> Turner, p. 175.

<ref target="#cite_ref-80">^</ref> Collins, p. 165.

<ref target="#cite_ref-81">^</ref> Whitburn, p. 144.

<ref target="#cite_ref-82">^</ref> Collins, p. 166.

<ref target="#cite_ref-83">^</ref> Brown, Kutner, and Warwick p. 179.

<ref target="#cite_ref-84">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.flavourofnz.co.nz/index.php?qpageID=search%20listener&qartistid=731#n_view_location" rel="nofollow">Flavour of New Zealand – search listener</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-85">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.irishcharts.ie/search/placement" rel="nofollow">The Irish Charts – All there is to know</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-86">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.collectionscanada.gc.ca/rpm/028020-119.01-e.php?brws_s=1&file_num=nlc008388.7697&type=1&interval=24&PHPSESSID=aeah0de49c35ruvtairkt88i52" rel="nofollow">Top Singles – Volume 17, No. 17, June 10 1972</ref> RPM Magazine (10 June 1972). Retrieved 4 November 2011.

<ref target="#cite_ref-87">^</ref> Brown, Kutner, and Warwick p. 757.

<ref target="#cite_ref-88">^</ref> Whitburn, p. 610.

<ref target="#cite_ref-89">^</ref> Turner, p. 188.

<ref target="#cite_ref-91">^</ref> Turner, p. 192.

<ref target="#cite_ref-92">^</ref> Turner, p. 205.

<ref target="#cite_ref-93">^</ref> Turner, pp. 195–205.

<ref target="#cite_ref-94">^</ref> Keillor, Garrison (1 May 2008). <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20141121171711/http://www.publicradio.org/columns/prairiehome/posthost/2008/05/01/amazing_grace.php" rel="nofollow">"A Prairie Home Companion: Amazing Grace"</ref>. publicradio.org. American Public Media. Archived from <ref class="external text" href="http://www.publicradio.org/columns/prairiehome/posthost/2008/05/01/amazing_grace.php" rel="nofollow">the original</ref> on 21 November 2014. Retrieved 2 October 2016.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Noll15_95-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Noll15_95-1">b</ref> Noll and Blumhofer, p. 15.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-Journal_Now_Article_96-0">^</ref> Young, Wesley (1 August 2013), <ref class="external text" href="http://www.journalnow.com/news/local/article_705f44c2-fb12-11e2-9027-001a4bcf6878.html" rel="nofollow">"A tale of grace: Local filmmaker bringing story of John Newton to life"</ref>. Winston-Salem Journal.

<ref target="#cite_ref-porter157_97-0">^</ref> Porter and McLaren, p. 157.

<ref target="#cite_ref-98">^</ref> Turner, p. 159.

<ref target="#cite_ref-99">^</ref> Rourke and Gwathmey, p. 108.

<ref target="#cite_ref-100">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.msnbc.com/msnbc-live/watch/president-obama-eulogizes-rev.-pinckney-471964227800" rel="nofollow">"President Obama: Emanuel AME 'a phoenix rising from the ashes'"</ref>. MSNBC. 17 September 2014. Retrieved 28 June 2015.

<ref target="#cite_ref-101">^</ref> Saunders, William (2003). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.catholiceducation.org/articles/religion/re0250.html" rel="nofollow">Lenten Music</ref> Arlington Catholic Herald. Retrieved 7 February 2010.

<ref target="#cite_ref-102">^</ref> Norris, p. 66.

<ref target="#cite_ref-103">^</ref> Turner, pp. 213–214.

<ref target="#cite_ref-104">^</ref> Bruner and Ware, pp. 31–32.

<ref target="#cite_ref-105">^</ref> Turner, pp. 218–220.

<ref target="#cite_ref-106">^</ref> Noll and Blumhofer, p. 16.

<ref target="#cite_ref-107">^</ref> Basker, p. xxxiv.


<h3>Sources[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=14" title="Edit section: Sources">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>.mw-parser-output .refbegin{font-size:90%;margin-bottom:0.5em}.mw-parser-output .refbegin-hanging-indents>ul{list-style-type:none;margin-left:0}.mw-parser-output .refbegin-hanging-indents>ul>li,.mw-parser-output .refbegin-hanging-indents>dl>dd{margin-left:0;padding-left:3.2em;text-indent:-3.2em;list-style:none}.mw-parser-output .refbegin-100{font-size:100%}</p>

<p>Aitken, Jonathan (2007). John Newton: From Disgrace to Amazing Grace, Crossway Books. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/1-58134-848-7" title="Special:BookSources/1-58134-848-7">1-58134-848-7</ref></p>
<p>Basker, James (2002). Amazing Grace: An Anthology of Poems About Slavery, 1660–1810, Yale University Press. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-300-09172-9" title="Special:BookSources/0-300-09172-9">0-300-09172-9</ref></p>
<p>Benson, Louis (1915). The English Hymn: Its Development and Use in Worship, The Presbyterian Board of Publication, Philadelphia.</p>
<p>Bradley, Ian (ed.)(1989). The Book of Hymns, The Overlook Press. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-87951-346-2" title="Special:BookSources/0-87951-346-2">0-87951-346-2</ref></p>
<p>Brown, Tony; Kutner, Jon; Warwick, Neil (2000). Complete Book of the British Charts: Singles & Albums, Omnibus. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-7119-7670-8" title="Special:BookSources/0-7119-7670-8">0-7119-7670-8</ref></p>
<p>Bruner, Kurt; Ware, Jim (2007). Finding God in the Story of Amazing Grace, Tyndale House Publishers, Inc. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/1-4143-1181-8" title="Special:BookSources/1-4143-1181-8">1-4143-1181-8</ref></p>
<p>Chase, Gilbert (1987). America's Music, From the Pilgrims to the Present, McGraw-Hill. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-252-00454-X" title="Special:BookSources/0-252-00454-X">0-252-00454-X</ref></p>
<ref target="/wiki/Judy_Collins" title="Judy Collins">Collins, Judy</ref> (1998). Singing Lessons: A Memoir of Love, Loss, Hope, and Healing , Pocket Books. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-671-02745-X" title="Special:BookSources/0-671-02745-X">0-671-02745-X</ref>
<p>Duvall, Deborah (2000). Tahlequah and the Cherokee Nation, Arcadia Publishing. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-7385-0782-2" title="Special:BookSources/0-7385-0782-2">0-7385-0782-2</ref></p>
<p>Julian, John (ed.)(1892). A Dictionary of Hymnology, Charles Scribner's Sons, New York.</p>
<p>Martin, Bernard (1950). John Newton: A Biography, William Heineman, Ltd., London.</p>
<p>Martin, Bernard and Spurrell, Mark, (eds.)(1962). The Journal of a Slave Trader (John Newton), The Epworth Press, London.</p>
<ref target="/wiki/John_Newton" title="John Newton">Newton, John</ref> (1811). Thoughts Upon the African Slave Trade, Samuel Whiting and Co., London.
<p>Newton, John (1824). The Works of the Rev. John Newton Late Rector of the United Parishes of St. Mary Woolnoth and St. Mary Woolchurch Haw, London: Volume 1, Nathan Whiting, London.</p>
<p>Noll, Mark A.; Blumhofer, Edith L. (eds.) (2006). Sing Them Over Again to Me: Hymns and Hymnbooks in America, University of Alabama Press. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-8173-1505-5" title="Special:BookSources/0-8173-1505-5">0-8173-1505-5</ref></p>
<ref target="/wiki/Kathleen_Norris_(poet)" title="Kathleen Norris (poet)">Norris, Kathleen</ref> (1999). Amazing Grace: A Vocabulary of Faith, Riverhead. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/1-57322-078-7" title="Special:BookSources/1-57322-078-7">1-57322-078-7</ref>
<p>Patterson, Beverly Bush (1995). The Sound of the Dove: Singing in Appalachian Primitive Baptist Churches, University of Illinois Press. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-252-02123-1" title="Special:BookSources/0-252-02123-1">0-252-02123-1</ref></p>
<p>Porter, Jennifer; McLaren, Darcee (eds.)(1999). Star Trek and Sacred Ground: Explorations of Star Trek, Religion, and American Culture, State University of New York Press, <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-585-29190-X" title="Special:BookSources/0-585-29190-X">0-585-29190-X</ref></p>
<p>Rourke, Mary; Gwathmey, Emily (1996). Amazing Grace in America: Our Spiritual National Anthem, Angel City Press. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/1-883318-30-0" title="Special:BookSources/1-883318-30-0">1-883318-30-0</ref></p>
<ref target="/wiki/Harriet_Beecher_Stowe" title="Harriet Beecher Stowe">Stowe, Harriet Beecher</ref> (1899). <ref target="/wiki/Uncle_Tom%27s_Cabin" title="Uncle Tom's Cabin">Uncle Tom's Cabin</ref>, or Life Among the Lowly, R. F. Fenno & Company, New York City.
<p>Swiderski, Richard (1996). The Metamorphosis of English: Versions of Other Languages, Greenwood Publishing Group. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-89789-468-5" title="Special:BookSources/0-89789-468-5">0-89789-468-5</ref></p>
<p>Turner, Steve (2002). Amazing Grace: The Story of America's Most Beloved Song, HarperCollins. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-06-000219-0" title="Special:BookSources/0-06-000219-0">0-06-000219-0</ref></p>
<p>Watson, J. R. (ed.)(2002). An Annotated Anthology of Hymns, Oxford University Press. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-19-826973-0" title="Special:BookSources/0-19-826973-0">0-19-826973-0</ref></p>
<ref target="/wiki/Joel_Whitburn" title="Joel Whitburn">Whitburn, Joel</ref> (2003). Joel Whitburn's Top Pop Singles, 1955–2002, Record Research, Inc. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-89820-155-1" title="Special:BookSources/0-89820-155-1">0-89820-155-1</ref>


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit&section=15" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Amazing Graceat Wikipedia's <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Wikimedia_sister_projects" title="Wikipedia:Wikimedia sister projects">sister projects</ref><ref class="extiw" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Amazing_Grace" title="c:Category:Amazing Grace">Media</ref> from Wikimedia Commons</p>
<ref class="extiw" href="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Special:Search/Amazing_Grace" title="s:Special:Search/Amazing Grace">Texts</ref> from Wikisource
<ref class="extiw" href="https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Biblical_Studies/Christianity/Christian_music" title="b:Biblical Studies/Christianity/Christian music">Textbooks</ref> from Wikibooks


<ref class="external text" href="http://www.hymnary.org/text/amazing_grace_how_sweet_the_sound" rel="nofollow">Amazing Grace</ref> at <ref target="/wiki/Hymnary.org" title="Hymnary.org">Hymnary.org</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150419181334/http://www.estudobiblico.org/en/biblical-comment/873-the-amazing-grace" rel="nofollow">The Amazing Grace</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://memory.loc.gov/diglib/ihas/html/grace/grace-home.html" rel="nofollow">U.S. Library of Congress Amazing Grace collection</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.cowperandnewtonmuseum.org.uk" rel="nofollow">Cowper & Newton Museum</ref> in Olney, England
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.markrhoads.com/amazingsite/index.htm" rel="nofollow">Amazing Grace: Some Early Tunes Anthology of the American Hymn-Tune Repertory</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.amazinggrace.ie" rel="nofollow">Amazing Grace: The story behind the song and its connection to Lough Swilly</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0erGAmnLoYA" rel="nofollow">Amazing Grace Sound Recording</ref> Completely original music by composer Michael John Trotta.
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Authority_control" title="Help:Authority control">Authority control</ref> <ref target="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q210211" title="Edit this at Wikidata"></ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Integrated_Authority_File" title="Integrated Authority File">GND</ref>: <ref class="external text" href="https://d-nb.info/gnd/4740885-6" rel="nofollow">4740885-6</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Library_of_Congress_Control_Number" title="Library of Congress Control Number">LCCN</ref>: <ref class="external text" href="https://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n85212481" rel="nofollow">n85212481</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/MusicBrainz" title="MusicBrainz">MusicBrainz</ref> work: <ref class="external text" href="https://musicbrainz.org/work/a5393197-4f8e-31f3-a535-2de2ff275133" rel="nofollow">a5393197-4f8e-31f3-a535-2de2ff275133</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Virtual_International_Authority_File" title="Virtual International Authority File">VIAF</ref>: <ref class="external text" href="https://viaf.org/viaf/185526626" rel="nofollow">185526626</ref>
 <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/WorldCat_Identities" title="WorldCat Identities">WorldCat Identities</ref> (via VIAF): <ref class="external text" href="https://www.worldcat.org/identities/containsVIAFID/185526626" rel="nofollow">185526626</ref>

<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Audio_a.svg"></ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Music" title="Portal:Music">Music portal</ref><ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:P_christianity.svg"></ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Christianity" title="Portal:Christianity">Christianity portal</ref>




<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&oldid=917404387">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&oldid=917404387</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:1772_songs" title="Category:1772 songs">1772 songs</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:18th-century_hymns" title="Category:18th-century hymns">18th-century hymns</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:1970_singles" title="Category:1970 singles">1970 singles</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:1971_singles" title="Category:1971 singles">1971 singles</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:1972_singles" title="Category:1972 singles">1972 singles</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:2007_singles" title="Category:2007 singles">2007 singles</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:British_patriotic_songs" title="Category:British patriotic songs">British patriotic songs</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Elvis_Presley_songs" title="Category:Elvis Presley songs">Elvis Presley songs</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Joan_Baez_songs" title="Category:Joan Baez songs">Joan Baez songs</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Irish_Singles_Chart_number-one_singles" title="Category:Irish Singles Chart number-one singles">Irish Singles Chart number-one singles</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Number-one_singles_in_Australia" title="Category:Number-one singles in Australia">Number-one singles in Australia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:RPM_Top_Singles_number-one_singles" title="Category:RPM Top Singles number-one singles">RPM Top Singles number-one singles</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Number-one_singles_in_South_Africa" title="Category:Number-one singles in South Africa">Number-one singles in South Africa</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:UK_Singles_Chart_number-one_singles" title="Category:UK Singles Chart number-one singles">UK Singles Chart number-one singles</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:British_poems" title="Category:British poems">British poems</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:English_Christian_hymns" title="Category:English Christian hymns">English Christian hymns</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Gospel_songs" title="Category:Gospel songs">Gospel songs</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Okeh_Records_singles" title="Category:Okeh Records singles">Okeh Records singles</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:EngvarB_from_May_2019" title="Category:EngvarB from May 2019">EngvarB from May 2019</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Use_dmy_dates_from_May_2019" title="Category:Use dmy dates from May 2019">Use dmy dates from May 2019</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Featured_articles" title="Category:Featured articles">Featured articles</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_short_description" title="Category:Articles with short description">Articles with short description</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_hAudio_microformats" title="Category:Articles with hAudio microformats">Articles with hAudio microformats</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Wikipedia_articles_with_GND_identifiers" title="Category:Wikipedia articles with GND identifiers">Wikipedia articles with GND identifiers</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Wikipedia_articles_with_LCCN_identifiers" title="Category:Wikipedia articles with LCCN identifiers">Wikipedia articles with LCCN identifiers</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Wikipedia_articles_with_MusicBrainz_work_identifiers" title="Category:Wikipedia articles with MusicBrainz work identifiers">Wikipedia articles with MusicBrainz work identifiers</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Wikipedia_articles_with_VIAF_identifiers" title="Category:Wikipedia articles with VIAF identifiers">Wikipedia articles with VIAF identifiers</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Wikipedia_articles_with_WorldCat-VIAF_identifiers" title="Category:Wikipedia articles with WorldCat-VIAF identifiers">Wikipedia articles with WorldCat-VIAF identifiers</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=Amazing+Grace" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=Amazing+Grace" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/Amazing_Grace" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:Amazing_Grace" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/Amazing_Grace">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/Amazing_Grace" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/Amazing_Grace" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&oldid=917404387" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q210211" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=Amazing_Grace&id=917404387" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>In other projects</h3></p>


<ref target="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Amazing_Grace" hreflang="en">Wikimedia Commons</ref><ref target="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="en">Wikisource</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=Amazing+Grace">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=Amazing+Grace&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ar.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D8%A3%D9%85%D8%A7%D8%B2%D9%8A%D9%86%D8%BA_%D8%BA%D8%B1%D9%8A%D8%B3" hreflang="ar" lang="ar" title="أمازينغ غريس – Arabic">العربية</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ast.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="ast" lang="ast" title="Amazing Grace – Asturian">Asturianu</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ca.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="ca" lang="ca" title="Amazing Grace – Catalan">Català</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://cs.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="cs" lang="cs" title="Amazing Grace – Czech">Čeština</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://da.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="da" lang="da" title="Amazing Grace – Danish">Dansk</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="de" lang="de" title="Amazing Grace – German">Deutsch</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://nv.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jooba%CA%BC_T%CA%BC%C3%B3%C3%B3_Nizh%C3%B3n%C3%AD" hreflang="nv" lang="nv" title="Joobaʼ Tʼóó Nizhóní – Navajo">Diné bizaad</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="es" lang="es" title="Amazing Grace – Spanish">Español</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://eo.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="eo" lang="eo" title="Amazing Grace – Esperanto">Esperanto</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://eu.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="eu" lang="eu" title="Amazing Grace – Basque">Euskara</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="fr" lang="fr" title="Amazing Grace – French">Français</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ko.wikipedia.org/wiki/%EC%96%B4%EB%A9%94%EC%9D%B4%EC%A7%95_%EA%B7%B8%EB%A0%88%EC%9D%B4%EC%8A%A4" hreflang="ko" lang="ko" title="어메이징 그레이스 – Korean">한국어</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://id.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="id" lang="id" title="Amazing Grace – Indonesian">Bahasa Indonesia</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="it" lang="it" title="Amazing Grace – Italian">Italiano</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://he.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="he" lang="he" title="Amazing Grace – Hebrew">עברית</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://la.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="la" lang="la" title="Amazing Grace – Latin">Latina</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://hu.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="hu" lang="hu" title="Amazing Grace – Hungarian">Magyar</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://mk.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="mk" lang="mk" title="Amazing Grace – Macedonian">Македонски</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace_(hymne)" hreflang="nl" lang="nl" title="Amazing Grace (hymne) – Dutch">Nederlands</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E3%82%A2%E3%83%A1%E3%82%A4%E3%82%B8%E3%83%B3%E3%82%B0%E3%83%BB%E3%82%B0%E3%83%AC%E3%82%A4%E3%82%B9" hreflang="ja" lang="ja" title="アメイジング・グレイス – Japanese">日本語</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://no.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="no" lang="no" title="Amazing Grace – Norwegian">Norsk</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://nn.wikipedia.org/wiki/Forunderleg,_eit_vrak_som_meg" hreflang="nn" lang="nn" title="Forunderleg, eit vrak som meg – Norwegian Nynorsk">Norsk nynorsk</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://pl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="pl" lang="pl" title="Amazing Grace – Polish">Polski</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="pt" lang="pt" title="Amazing Grace – Portuguese">Português</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ro.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="ro" lang="ro" title="Amazing Grace – Romanian">Română</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D0%9E,_%D0%B1%D0%BB%D0%B0%D0%B3%D0%BE%D0%B4%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%8C" hreflang="ru" lang="ru" title="О, благодать – Russian">Русский</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="en-simple" lang="en-simple" title="Amazing Grace – Simple English">Simple English</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://sk.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="sk" lang="sk" title="Amazing Grace – Slovak">Slovenčina</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://sl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="sl" lang="sl" title="Amazing Grace – Slovenian">Slovenščina</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://sr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="sr" lang="sr" title="Amazing Grace – Serbian">Српски / srpski</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://sv.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="sv" lang="sv" title="Amazing Grace – Swedish">Svenska</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://th.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E0%B8%9E%E0%B8%A3%E0%B8%B0%E0%B8%84%E0%B8%B8%E0%B8%93%E0%B8%9E%E0%B8%A3%E0%B8%B0%E0%B9%80%E0%B8%88%E0%B9%89%E0%B8%B2" hreflang="th" lang="th" title="พระคุณพระเจ้า – Thai">ไทย</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://chr.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E1%8E%A4%E1%8F%81%E1%8E%B3%E1%8F%85%E1%8E%A2%E1%8E%A4%E1%8F%AA%E1%8F%A5" hreflang="chr" lang="chr" title="ᎤᏁᎳᏅᎢᎤᏪᏥ – Cherokee">ᏣᎳᎩ</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://uk.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D0%A7%D1%83%D0%B4%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%B0_%D0%BB%D0%B0%D1%81%D0%BA%D0%B0" hreflang="uk" lang="uk" title="Чудова ласка – Ukrainian">Українська</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://vi.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazing_Grace" hreflang="vi" lang="vi" title="Amazing Grace – Vietnamese">Tiếng Việt</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%A5%87%E7%95%B0%E6%81%A9%E5%85%B8" hreflang="zh" lang="zh" title="奇異恩典 – Chinese">中文</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q210211#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 23 September 2019, at 17:48 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Amazing_Grace&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"1.068","walltime":"1.338","ppvisitednodes":{"value":6518,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":54742,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":14026,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":13,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":14,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":1,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":87525,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":1,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 1023.988 1 -total"," 22.16% 226.893 2 Template:Reflist"," 20.42% 209.050 17 Template:ISBN"," 13.81% 141.430 3 Template:Cite_web"," 10.69% 109.511 1 Template:Authority_control"," 8.57% 87.785 17 Template:Catalog_lookup_link"," 5.88% 60.251 21 Template:Main_other"," 5.58% 57.167 1 Template:Featured_article"," 4.92% 50.342 1 Template:Infobox_musical_composition"," 4.73% 48.480 1 Template:Top_icon"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.311","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":5971699,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1238","timestamp":"20191006041611","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"Amazing Grace","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Amazing_Grace","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q210211","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q210211","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2001-08-11T05:48:17Z","dateModified":"2019-09-23T17:48:41Z","image":"https:\/\/upload.wikimedia.org\/wikipedia\/commons\/6\/68\/Olney_Hymns_page_53_Amazing_Grace.jpg","headline":"Christian hymn"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":104,"wgHostname":"mw1321"});});</p>


