



<p>End of the Rainbow - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"End_of_the_Rainbow","wgTitle":"End of the Rainbow","wgCurRevisionId":909880229,"wgRevisionId":909880229,"wgArticleId":21206403,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["Webarchive template wayback links","Articles with hAudio microformats","British plays","Judy Garland","Biographical plays about actors","2005 plays","Opera world premieres at Sydney Opera House"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],</p>
<p>"wgRelevantPageName":"End_of_the_Rainbow","wgRelevantArticleId":21206403,"wgRequestId":"XZaEwApAICoAABQkJj8AAAAK","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q1702654","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready",</p>
<p>"user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head","mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks",</p>
<p>"ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>

























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>End of the Rainbow</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<p>For 1930 German film, see <ref target="/wiki/End_of_the_Rainbow_(1930_film)" title="End of the Rainbow (1930 film)">End of the Rainbow (1930 film)</ref>.</p>
<p>For 1947 film with this title, see <ref target="/wiki/Northwest_Outpost" title="Northwest Outpost">Northwest Outpost</ref>.</p>
<p>Not to be confused with <ref target="/wiki/At_the_End_of_the_Rainbow" title="At the End of the Rainbow">At the End of the Rainbow</ref>.</p>
<p>End of the RainbowWritten by<ref target="/wiki/Peter_Quilter" title="Peter Quilter">Peter Quilter</ref>Characters<ref target="/wiki/Judy_Garland" title="Judy Garland">Judy Garland</ref>Anthony<ref target="/wiki/Mickey_Deans" title="Mickey Deans">Mickey Deans</ref>ConciergeStage ManagerBBC AnnouncerDate premiered2005Place premiered<ref target="/wiki/Sydney_Opera_House" title="Sydney Opera House">Sydney Opera House</ref><ref target="/wiki/Sydney" title="Sydney">Sydney</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Australia" title="Australia">Australia</ref>Original languageEnglishSubjectThe last months of Judy Garland's lifeGenreDrama / MusicalSettingLondon, December 1968</p>
<p>End of the Rainbow is a musical drama by <ref target="/wiki/Peter_Quilter" title="Peter Quilter">Peter Quilter</ref>, which focuses on <ref target="/wiki/Judy_Garland" title="Judy Garland">Judy Garland</ref> in the months leading up to her death in 1969. After a <ref target="/wiki/Sydney" title="Sydney">Sydney</ref> premiere in 2005, the show has played on the West End in <ref target="/wiki/London" title="London">London</ref> and a <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> production opened in 2012.</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Synopsis">1 Synopsis</ref>
<ref target="#Production_history">2 Production history</ref>
<ref target="#Musical_numbers">3 Musical numbers</ref>
<ref target="#Recording">4 Recording</ref>

<ref target="#Track_listing">4.1 Track listing</ref>


<ref target="#Awards_and_nominations">5 Awards and nominations</ref>

<ref target="#Original_Broadway_production">5.1 Original Broadway production</ref>


<ref target="#References">6 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">7 External links</ref>


<h2>Synopsis[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Synopsis">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Judy Garland is staying in London, along with young new fiancé <ref target="/wiki/Mickey_Deans" title="Mickey Deans">Mickey Deans</ref> and loyal friend and pianist Anthony, preparing for her five-week run of shows at <ref target="/wiki/Hippodrome,_London" title="Hippodrome, London">The Talk of the Town</ref>. Garland hopes that her act will help her maintain her star profile, especially considering a recent string of bad press against her. However, she still struggles with both her drug addictions and her strained relationships with the men around her.</p>

<h2>Production history[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Production history">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>End of the Rainbow evolved from an earlier Peter Quilter play entitled Last Song of the Nightingale which had starred <ref target="/wiki/Tracie_Bennett" title="Tracie Bennett">Tracie Bennett</ref> as a fictitious past-her-prime diva: premièring as a <ref target="/wiki/Fringe_theatre" title="Fringe theatre">London fringe</ref> production in the spring of 2001, Last Song... had encored (with Bennett) in 2003 at the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Edinburgh_Fringe_Festival" title="Edinburgh Fringe Festival">Edinburgh Fringe Festival</ref> and also <ref target="/wiki/Off_West_End" title="Off West End">Off West End</ref>. Although Quilter would state the play's protagonist was a gender-switch on an alcoholic male cruise ship performer of the playwright's acquaintance,<ref target="#cite_note-Wisconsin_Gazette-1">[1]</ref>Last Song... would be viewed by theater-goers and critics - and its star Tracie Bennett - as a theatrical Judy Garland <ref target="/wiki/Roman_%C3%A0_clef" title="Roman à clef">roman à clef</ref>:<ref target="#cite_note-Wisconsin_Gazette-1">[1]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-2">[2]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-3">[3]</ref> Quilter eventually decided to revise his original play to overtly focus on Garland, with the resultant End of the Rainbow premièring in August 2005 at the <ref target="/wiki/Sydney_Opera_House" title="Sydney Opera House">Sydney Opera House</ref> in Australia with <ref target="/wiki/Caroline_O%27Connor_(actress)" title="Caroline O'Connor (actress)">Caroline O’Connor</ref> as Garland,<ref target="#cite_note-4">[4]</ref> a role O'Connor reprised first in a May 2006 production at the Theatre Royal, Sydney<ref target="#cite_note-5">[5]</ref> and then at the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Edinburgh_Fringe_Festival" title="Edinburgh Fringe Festival">Edinburgh Fringe Festival</ref> engagement of End of the Rainbow in August 2006.<ref target="#cite_note-stage-6">[6]</ref> O'Connor won three Best Actress awards for her performances.</p>
<p>End of the Rainbow was then performed from February 5–20, 2010 at Northampton's Royal & Derngate Theatre. This production was directed by <ref target="/wiki/Terry_Johnson_(dramatist)" title="Terry Johnson (dramatist)">Terry Johnson</ref> and starred Tracie Bennett as Judy Garland, with <ref target="/wiki/Hilton_McRae" title="Hilton McRae">Hilton McRae</ref> as Anthony and Stephen Hagan as Mickey Deans.<ref target="#cite_note-7">[7]</ref> End of the Rainbow ran in the <ref target="/wiki/West_End_theatre" title="West End theatre">West End</ref> from 16 November 2010 to 21 May 2011 at <ref target="/wiki/Trafalgar_Studios" title="Trafalgar Studios">Trafalgar Studios</ref>, starring Tracie Bennett.<ref target="#cite_note-8">[8]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-Bway-9">[9]</ref> The West End production received nominations for four <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Olivier_Awards" title="Olivier Awards">Olivier Awards</ref>, including Best Actress for Bennett, Best Actor in a Supporting Role for McRae and Best New Play. The show then toured in the UK from 25 August and ending in December 2011 at Richmond Theatre. .<ref target="#cite_note-stage-6">[6]</ref></p>
<p>End of the Rainbow had its American premiere at the <ref target="/wiki/Guthrie_Theater" title="Guthrie Theater">Guthrie Theater</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/Minneapolis" title="Minneapolis">Minneapolis</ref>, running from January 28 to March 11, 2012. Directed by Terry Johnson, Tracie Bennett repeated her role as Garland.<ref target="#cite_note-10">[10]</ref> The play opened on <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> at the <ref target="/wiki/Belasco_Theatre" title="Belasco Theatre">Belasco Theatre</ref> on March 19, 2012 in previews and officially on April 2. In addition to Bennett, the cast featured <ref target="/wiki/Michael_Cumpsty" title="Michael Cumpsty">Michael Cumpsty</ref> as Anthony, <ref target="/wiki/Tom_Pelphrey" title="Tom Pelphrey">Tom Pelphrey</ref> as Mickey Deans, and Jay Russell.<ref target="#cite_note-Bway-9">[9]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-11">[11]</ref> Bennett and Cumpsty received <ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award" title="Tony Award">Tony Award</ref> nominations for their performances. Bennett also received the <ref target="/wiki/Outer_Critics_Circle_Award" title="Outer Critics Circle Award">Outer Critics Circle Award</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award" title="Drama Desk Award">Drama Desk Award</ref> for Outstanding Actress in a Play. The show ran 176 performances on Broadway and subsequently played a critically acclaimed season at the Ahmanson Theatre in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>End of the Rainbow (Al final del arcoíris) premiered in Madrid, January 2011, at the Teatro Marquina with <ref target="/wiki/Natalia_Dicenta" title="Natalia Dicenta">Natalia Dicenta</ref> as <ref target="/wiki/Judy_Garland" title="Judy Garland">Judy Garland</ref>, Miguel Rellán as Anthony and Javier Mora as Mickey Deans.</p>
<p>End of the Rainbow (O Fim do Arco-Íris) (<ref class="extiw" href="https://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judy_Garland_-_O_Fim_do_Arco-%C3%8Dris_(musical)" title="pt:Judy Garland - O Fim do Arco-Íris (musical)">pt</ref>) had its Portuguese première in January 2012 at the Teatro Politeama<ref target="#cite_note-12">[12]</ref> in Lisbon. The cast was led by <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Vanessa_Silva&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Vanessa Silva (page does not exist)">Vanessa Silva</ref> [<ref class="extiw" href="https://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vanessa_Silva" title="pt:Vanessa Silva">pt</ref>] as <ref target="/wiki/Judy_Garland" title="Judy Garland">Judy Garland</ref> with Carlos Quintas as <ref target="/wiki/Mickey_Deans" title="Mickey Deans">Mickey Deans</ref> and Hugo Rendas as <ref target="/wiki/Sidney_Luft" title="Sidney Luft">Sidney Luft</ref>.</p>
<p>The show was presented in Brazil, on November 11th, 2012 at the Fashion Mall shopping center's entertainment court, in <ref target="/wiki/Federal_District_(Brazil)" title="Federal District (Brazil)">Brasília, DF</ref> with Cláudia Netto as Judy and Igor Rickli as Mickey Deans.</p>
<p>There have also been successful productions of the show in Brisbane, Melbourne, Auckland, Florence, Amsterdam, Berlin, Hamburg, Copenhagen, Kraków, Prague, Sofia, Rotterdam and Helsinki. New productions played in the 2013-14 season in Christchurch, Rome, Klagenfurt, Miami, Atlanta, Denver and Milwaukee.</p>
<p>The 2014 Milwaukee Repertory Theatre production of End of the Rainbow starred <ref target="/wiki/Hollis_Resnik" title="Hollis Resnik">Hollis Resnik</ref> as Garland.</p>
<p>Kathy St. George played Garland in the 2014 Actors' Playhouse production of End of the Rainbow at the Miracle Theatre in Miami.</p>
<p>End of the Rainbow (Al final del arcoíris) premiered in Buenos Aires, Argentina February the 5th, 2014 starring Karina K as Garland, Antonio Grimau and Federico Amador as Mickey Deans.</p>
<p>Anna Gangai appeared as Garland in End of the Rainbow at the Cellar Theatre at San Antonio's The Playhouse in 2014.</p>
<p>Jeannie Shubitz played Garland in a production of End of the Rainbow that opened at the Phoenix Theatre in Phoenix, Arizona in May, 2015.</p>
<p>The show had its Canadian premiere in April 2015 at the Compagnie Jean Duceppe Theatre in Montreal. In the same year, the show had a 2nd run in Los Angeles, playing at the International City Theatre.</p>
<p>End of the Rainbow (El final del arcoíris) premiered in Mexico City on May 29th, 2015, at the Foro Cultural Coyoacanense Hugo Argüelles with Alejandra Desiderio starring as <ref target="/wiki/Judy_Garland" title="Judy Garland">Judy Garland</ref>, José Antonio López Tercero as Anthony and Mario Sepúlveda as Mickey Deans directed by Rosa Alicia Delain and is a production of Re-Crea Teatro under the supervision of Alis Ortega and Fernanda Prado. </p>
<p>With a revival at Foro Shakespeare in 2016 and another revival at Teatro Rafael Solana in 2018. </p>
<p>Leisa Way portrayed Garland in a summer stock production of End of the Rainbow in Bobcaygeon, Ontario, Canada in July, 2015.</p>
<p>Eileen Bowman portrayed Garland in End of the Rainbow in San Diego in November 2015.</p>
<p>Natasha Drena played Judy Garland in End of the Rainbow in January, 2016 at the Kavinoky Theatre in Buffalo, NY. Drena previously performed the role in Atlanta in 2014, winning a Best Actress award at that city's local theatre awards ceremony.</p>
<p>Carolyn Johnson plays Garland in End of the Rainbow in March/April, 2016 at Stages Repertory Theatre in Houston, Texas.</p>
<p>In April, 2016, Janelle Lutz plays Garland in the Uptown Players' production of End of The Rainbow in Dallas, Texas.</p>
<p>End of the Rainbow toured the UK for a 2nd time in 2016, with <ref target="/wiki/Lisa_Maxwell_(actress)" title="Lisa Maxwell (actress)">Lisa Maxwell</ref> in the role of Judy Garland.</p>
<p>In 2015, the show had a new production in Tokyo Japan, which was revived in 2016. </p>
<p>In November 2016, Porchlight Music Theatre presented the Chicago premiere of the production with Angela Ingersoll as Judy Garland.</p>
<p>In December 2016, the show had a new production in Moscow, Russia. The show also returned to Rome for a 2nd run, at the Teatro Sistina.</p>
<p>Melissa Minyard plays Garland in the FreeFall theatre production of the play in St. Petersburg, Florida in the Spring of 2017.</p>
<p>Ace Productions presented a new Canadian production in Vancouver in April 2017.</p>
<p>The Berlin production returned to the Schlosspark Theater for a 2nd run in September 2017.</p>
<p>The play returned to Los Angeles in 2017 for a run at the La Mirada Theatre. In summer 2018 it played its 4th LA run at Laguna Playhouse.</p>
<p>In June 2018 the show was produced by Max & Louie Productions in the historic Grandel Theater in St Louis, MO. The role of Judy Garland was performed by Angela Ingersoll.</p>
<p>In March 2018 filming began on <ref target="/wiki/Judy_(film)" title="Judy (film)">Judy</ref>, a film adaptation of End of the Rainbow. The film will star <ref target="/wiki/Ren%C3%A9e_Zellweger" title="Renée Zellweger">Renée Zellweger</ref> and is slated for a 2019 release.</p>
<p>In 2019 The <ref target="/wiki/State_Theatre_Company_of_South_Australia" title="State Theatre Company of South Australia">State Theatre Company of South Australia</ref> commemorated the 50th Anniversary of Garland's passing. </p>
<p>As part of the <ref target="/wiki/Adelaide_Cabaret_Festival" title="Adelaide Cabaret Festival">Adelaide Cabaret Festival</ref>,</p>
<p>this production of End Of The Rainbow starring <ref target="/wiki/Helen_Dallimore" title="Helen Dallimore">Helen Dallimore</ref> as Judy, Nic English as Micky, Stephen Sheehan as Anthony and </p>
<p>Directed by Elena Carapetis, concluded its engagement on June 22nd 2019.</p>

<h2>Musical numbers[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Musical numbers">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/I_Can%27t_Give_You_Anything_but_Love,_Baby" title="I Can't Give You Anything but Love, Baby">I Can't Give You Anything but Love, Baby</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Just_in_Time_(song)" title="Just in Time (song)">Just in Time</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/For_Me_and_My_Gal_(song)" title="For Me and My Gal (song)">For Me and My Gal</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/You_Made_Me_Love_You_(I_Didn%27t_Want_to_Do_It)" title="You Made Me Love You (I Didn't Want to Do It)">You Made Me Love You (I Didn't Want to Do It)</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/The_Trolley_Song" title="The Trolley Song">The Trolley Song</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/The_Man_that_Got_Away" title="The Man that Got Away">The Man that Got Away</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/When_You%27re_Smiling" title="When You're Smiling">When You're Smiling</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Come_Rain_or_Come_Shine" title="Come Rain or Come Shine">Come Rain or Come Shine</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Over_the_Rainbow" title="Over the Rainbow">Over the Rainbow</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Get_Happy_(song)" title="Get Happy (song)">Get Happy</ref>"</p>
<p>"By Myself"</p>
<h2>Recording[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: Recording">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>End of the Rainbow<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:End_of_the_Rainbow_album.jpg"></ref><ref target="/wiki/Album" title="Album">Studio album</ref> by Tracie BennettReleasedJanuary 31, 2011<ref target="/wiki/Music_genre" title="Music genre">Genre</ref><ref target="/wiki/Showtunes" title="Showtunes">Showtunes</ref></p>
<p>A <ref target="/wiki/Cast_recording" title="Cast recording">cast recording</ref> of the London production was released on January 31, 2011 by <ref target="/wiki/Angel_Recording_Studios" title="Angel Recording Studios">Angel Recording Studios</ref> featuring Tracie Bennett's renditions of both the play's songs and other Garland numbers.<ref target="#cite_note-13">[13]</ref></p>

<h3>Track listing[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: Track listing">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>All tracks performed by <ref target="/wiki/Tracie_Bennett" title="Tracie Bennett">Tracie Bennett</ref>, unless noted.</p>

<p>No.TitleLength1."I Can't Give You Anything But Love" / "Just In Time" (Medley) 2."<ref target="/wiki/I_Could_Go_On_Singing" title="I Could Go On Singing">I Could Go On Singing</ref>" 3."<ref target="/wiki/Smile_(Charlie_Chaplin_song)" title="Smile (Charlie Chaplin song)">Smile</ref>" 4.""The Bells Are Ringing for Me and My Girl" / "You Made Me Love You" / "The Trolley Song"" (Medley) 5."<ref target="/wiki/Zing!_Went_the_Strings_of_My_Heart" title="Zing! Went the Strings of My Heart">Zing! Went the Strings of My Heart</ref>" 6."<ref target="/wiki/The_Man_That_Got_Away" title="The Man That Got Away">The Man That Got Away</ref>" 7."Come Rain or Come Shine" 8."When You're Smiling" 9."Somewhere Over the Rainbow" 10."<ref target="/wiki/Theme_from_San_Francisco" title="Theme from San Francisco">San Francisco</ref>" 11."<ref target="/wiki/When_the_Sun_Comes_Out" title="When the Sun Comes Out">When the Sun Comes Out</ref>" 12."Get Happy" / "By Myself" (Medley) 13."Somewhere Over the Rainbow" (Piano solo by <ref target="/wiki/Simon_Lee_(conductor)" title="Simon Lee (conductor)">Simon Lee</ref>) </p>
<h2>Awards and nominations[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: Awards and nominations">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>4 <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Olivier_Award" title="Olivier Award">Olivier Award</ref> nominations in London's West End in 2011 - </p>
<p>BEST NEW PLAY, Best Actress, Best Sound, and Best Supporting Actor.</p>

<h3>Original Broadway production[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: Original Broadway production">edit</ref>]</h3>


<p>Year</p>

<p>Award ceremony</p>

<p>Category</p>

<p>Nominee</p>

<p>Result</p>


<p>2012</p>

<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award" title="Tony Award">Tony Award</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Actress_in_a_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Actress in a Play">Best Performance by a Leading Actress in a Play</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Tracie_Bennett" title="Tracie Bennett">Tracie Bennett</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Featured_Actor_in_a_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Featured Actor in a Play">Best Performance by a Featured Actor in a Play</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Michael_Cumpsty" title="Michael Cumpsty">Michael Cumpsty</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Sound_Design_of_a_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Sound Design of a Play">Best Sound Design of a Play</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Gareth_Owen_(sound_designer)" title="Gareth Owen (sound designer)">Gareth Owen</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award" title="Drama Desk Award">Drama Desk Award</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Actress_in_a_Play" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Actress in a Play">Outstanding Actress in a Play</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Tracie_Bennett" title="Tracie Bennett">Tracie Bennett</ref>

<p>Won</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Outer_Critics_Circle_Award" title="Outer Critics Circle Award">Outer Critics Circle Award</ref>

<p>Outstanding Actress in a Play</p>

<p>Won</p>

<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit&section=8" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>


<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Wisconsin_Gazette_1-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Wisconsin_Gazette_1-1">b</ref> <ref class="external free" href="https://www.wisconsingazette.com/entertainment/stage/playwright-peter-quilter-finds-the-pot-of-gold-at-the/article_660221a6-7a5e-5835-ba9c-78c7a32eda7e.html" rel="nofollow">https://www.wisconsingazette.com/entertainment/stage/playwright-peter-quilter-finds-the-pot-of-gold-at-the/article_660221a6-7a5e-5835-ba9c-78c7a32eda7e.html</ref></p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-2">^</ref> <ref class="external free" href="https://www.midsussextimes.co.uk/whats-on/theatre-and-comedy/review-end-of-the-rainbow-1-3136889" rel="nofollow">https://www.midsussextimes.co.uk/whats-on/theatre-and-comedy/review-end-of-the-rainbow-1-3136889</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-3">^</ref> <ref class="external free" href="https://www.newsshopper.co.uk/news/408513.tracie-bennett-interviewed-september-2003/" rel="nofollow">https://www.newsshopper.co.uk/news/408513.tracie-bennett-interviewed-september-2003/</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-4">^</ref> Hallett, Bruce.<ref class="external text" href="http://www.smh.com.au/news/arts/garlands-last-days-come-alive/2005/08/05/1123125897472.html" rel="nofollow">" 'End of the Rainbow', Ensemble Theatre, Opera House, August 4; Garland's last days come alive"</ref> smh.com.au, August 6, 2005

<ref target="#cite_ref-5">^</ref> Doran, Siobhán.<ref class="external text" href="http://www.sydneystage.com.au/content/view/90/" rel="nofollow">"'End of The Rainbow' "</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20060825070546/http://www.sydneystage.com.au/content/view/90/" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2006-08-25 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref> SydneyStage.com.au, 8 May 2006

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-stage_6-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-stage_6-1">b</ref> Girvan, Andrew.<ref class="external text" href="http://www.whatsonstage.com/news/theatre/london/E8831308828181/Bennett+Is+Garland+Again,+End+of+the+Rainbow+Tours+.html" rel="nofollow">Bennett Is Garland Again, End of the Rainbow Tours"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110627053817/http://www.whatsonstage.com/news/theatre/london/E8831308828181/Bennett+Is+Garland+Again%2C+End+of+the+Rainbow+Tours+.html" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2011-06-27 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref> whatsonstage.com, 23 June 2011</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-7">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/local/northampton/hi/people_and_places/arts_and_culture/newsid_8508000/8508547.stm" rel="nofollow">"Judy Garland drama shows her battle with drugs"</ref> BBC.com, February 10, 2010

<ref target="#cite_ref-8">^</ref> Staff. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.broadway.com/buzz/154851/end-of-the-rainbow-starring-olivier-winner-tracie-bennett-extends-west-end-run/" rel="nofollow">" 'End of the Rainbow' Starring Olivier Winner Tracie Bennett Extends West End Run"</ref> Broadway.com, January 7, 2011

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Bway_9-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Bway_9-1">b</ref> Healy, Patrick. <ref class="external text" href="http://artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/04/19/end-of-the-rainbow-producers-aim-for-broadway/" rel="nofollow">End of the Rainbow' Producers Aim for Broadway"</ref> <ref target="/wiki/The_New_York_Times" title="The New York Times">The New York Times</ref>, artsbeat.blogs, April 19, 2011</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-10">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.guthrietheater.org/media_room/releases/guthrie_announces_20112012_season" rel="nofollow">"Guthrie Theater Announces 2011-2012 Season"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110703000042/http://www.guthrietheater.org/media_room/releases/guthrie_announces_20112012_season" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2011-07-03 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref> GuthrieTheater.org, accessed March 19, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-11">^</ref> Hetrick, Adam.<ref class="external text" href="http://www.playbill.com/news/article/160827-Stormy-Weather-End-of-the-Rainbow-Begins-Broadway-Run-March-19-at-the-Belasco-Theatre" rel="nofollow">"Stormy Weather": End of the Rainbow Begins Broadway Run March 19 at the Belasco Theatre"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120320185632/http://www.playbill.com/news/article/160827-Stormy-Weather-End-of-the-Rainbow-Begins-Broadway-Run-March-19-at-the-Belasco-Theatre" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2012-03-20 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref> Playbill.com, March 19, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-12">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.filipelaferia.pt/o-fim-do-arco-iris/index.htm" rel="nofollow">Garland</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120121014647/http://filipelaferia.pt/o-fim-do-arco-iris/index.htm" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2012-01-21 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref> filipelaferia.pt, accessed March 19, 2012 (in Portuguese)

<ref target="#cite_ref-13">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.cduniverse.com/productinfo.asp?pid=8415481" rel="nofollow">"'End Of The Rainbow': Tracie Bennett Sings Judy CD"</ref> 
<p>cduniverse.com, accessed March 20, 2012</p>


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit&section=9" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.abouttheartists.com/plays/20216-end-of-the-rainbow-by-peter-quilter" rel="nofollow">About the Artists Production History</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.ibdb.com/production.php?id=491212" rel="nofollow">Internet Broadway Database Listing</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.endoftherainbowbroadway.com/" rel="nofollow">Official site of the Broadway 2012 production</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.peterquilter.net" rel="nofollow">official website of playwright Peter Quilter</ref>




<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&oldid=909880229">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&oldid=909880229</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:British_plays" title="Category:British plays">British plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Judy_Garland" title="Category:Judy Garland">Judy Garland</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Biographical_plays_about_actors" title="Category:Biographical plays about actors">Biographical plays about actors</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:2005_plays" title="Category:2005 plays">2005 plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Opera_world_premieres_at_Sydney_Opera_House" title="Category:Opera world premieres at Sydney Opera House">Opera world premieres at Sydney Opera House</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:Webarchive_template_wayback_links" title="Category:Webarchive template wayback links">Webarchive template wayback links</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_hAudio_microformats" title="Category:Articles with hAudio microformats">Articles with hAudio microformats</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=End+of+the+Rainbow" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=End+of+the+Rainbow" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/End_of_the_Rainbow" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:End_of_the_Rainbow" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/End_of_the_Rainbow">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/End_of_the_Rainbow" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/End_of_the_Rainbow" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&oldid=909880229" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q1702654" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=End_of_the_Rainbow&id=909880229" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=End+of+the+Rainbow">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=End+of+the+Rainbow&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/End_of_the_Rainbow" hreflang="it" lang="it" title="End of the Rainbow – Italian">Italiano</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q1702654#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 8 August 2019, at 06:47 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=End_of_the_Rainbow&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.248","walltime":"0.327","ppvisitednodes":{"value":1416,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":20221,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":855,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":11,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":2,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":0,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":8031,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":0,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 273.096 1 -total"," 35.38% 96.620 1 Template:Infobox_album"," 22.37% 61.091 2 Template:Infobox"," 14.09% 38.472 1 Template:Reflist"," 12.07% 32.972 1 Template:Infobox_play"," 11.16% 30.479 2 Template:For"," 8.32% 22.710 1 Template:Category_handler"," 7.89% 21.546 5 Template:Webarchive"," 5.43% 14.838 1 Template:Ill"," 3.93% 10.732 1 Template:Track_listing"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.077","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":2881442,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1321","timestamp":"20191003233112","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"End of the Rainbow","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/End_of_the_Rainbow","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q1702654","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q1702654","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2009-01-22T11:25:00Z","dateModified":"2019-08-08T06:47:47Z","headline":"play written by Peter Quilter"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":430,"wgHostname":"mw1321"});});</p>


