



<p>Lend Me a Tenor - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"Lend_Me_a_Tenor","wgTitle":"Lend Me a Tenor","wgCurRevisionId":919287345,"wgRevisionId":919287345,"wgArticleId":9022176,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["Webarchive template wayback links","1986 plays","Plays by Ken Ludwig","Broadway plays","Music of Cleveland"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"Lend_Me_a_Tenor","wgRelevantArticleId":9022176,"wgRequestId":</p>
<p>"XZfbOwpAMF0AAL2EbN8AAABM","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q16386653","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","mediawiki.page.gallery.styles":"ready","ext.cite.styles":"ready",</p>
<p>"mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["mediawiki.page.gallery","ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head","mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface",</p>
<p>"ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>


























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>Lend Me a Tenor</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<p>This article is about the play. For the musical adaption, see <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lend_Me_A_Tenor_(musical)" title="Lend Me A Tenor (musical)">Lend Me A Tenor (musical)</ref>.</p>
<p>Lend Me a Tenor<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:LendMeATenor.JPG"></ref>Written byKen LudwigDate premieredMarch 6, 1986Place premiered<ref target="/wiki/West_End_theatre" title="West End theatre">West End</ref>Original languageEnglishGenreComedySettingA hotel suite in Cleveland, Ohio in 1934.</p>
<p>Lend Me a Tenor is a <ref target="/wiki/Comedy" title="Comedy">comedy</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Ken_Ludwig" title="Ken Ludwig">Ken Ludwig</ref>. The play was produced on both the <ref target="/wiki/West_End_theatre" title="West End theatre">West End</ref> (1986) and <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> (1989). It received nine <ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award" title="Tony Award">Tony Award</ref> nominations and won for Best Actor (<ref target="/wiki/Philip_Bosco" title="Philip Bosco">Philip Bosco</ref>) and Best Director (<ref target="/wiki/Jerry_Zaks" title="Jerry Zaks">Jerry Zaks</ref>). A Broadway revival opened in 2010. Lend Me a Tenor has been translated into sixteen languages and produced in twenty-five countries. The title is a pun on "Lend me a tenner" (i.e., a ten-dollar bill).</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Synopsis">1 Synopsis</ref>

<ref target="#Act_I">1.1 Act I</ref>
<ref target="#Act_II">1.2 Act II</ref>


<ref target="#Productions">2 Productions</ref>
<ref target="#Characters">3 Characters</ref>
<ref target="#Adaptations">4 Adaptations</ref>
<ref target="#Awards_and_honors">5 Awards and honors</ref>

<ref target="#West_End_production">5.1 West End production</ref>
<ref target="#Broadway_production">5.2 Broadway production</ref>
<ref target="#Revival">5.3 Revival</ref>


<ref target="#References">6 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">7 External links</ref>


<h2>Synopsis[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Synopsis">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>The play takes place in 1934, in a <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Hotel_suite" title="Hotel suite">hotel suite</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/Cleveland" title="Cleveland">Cleveland</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Ohio" title="Ohio">Ohio</ref>. The <ref target="/wiki/Theatrical_scenery" title="Theatrical scenery">two-room set</ref> has a <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Sitting_room" title="Sitting room">sitting room</ref> with a sofa and chairs at right and a bedroom at left. A center "stage wall" divides the two rooms, with a door leading from one room to the other. (Throughout the play, the audience can see what's happening in both rooms at the same time.)</p>

<h3>Act I[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Act I">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>As Scene I of the play opens, Henry Saunders, general manager of the Cleveland Grand Opera Company, is anxiously awaiting the arrival of Tito Merelli, a world-famous Italian opera tenor, known as "Il Stupendo" to his many fans. Merelli is coming to Cleveland to sing the lead role in a performance of <ref target="/wiki/Giuseppe_Verdi" title="Giuseppe Verdi">Giuseppe Verdi</ref>'s <ref target="/wiki/Otello" title="Otello">Otello</ref>. It's the biggest event in the Cleveland Opera's history. A sellout crowd and the members of the Cleveland Opera Guild will be at the opera house that evening to see the great Merelli.</p>
<p>Saunders' harried assistant, Max, is also in the hotel suite. Saunders has charged Max with seeing to Merelli's needs, and with getting Merelli to the opera house in time for the performance. Also there is Maggie Saunders, Henry's daughter and Max's sometime girlfriend. Maggie is a fan of Tito Merelli, and hopes to meet him.</p>
<p>Tito finally arrives at the hotel suite, accompanied by his hot-tempered Italian wife, Maria, who is jealous because Tito flirts with other women. When she finds Maggie hiding in the bedroom closet, trying to get Tito's autograph, Maria angrily assumes that Maggie is Tito's secret lover. Maria writes Tito a "Dear John" letter, and leaves the hotel.</p>
<p>In the sitting room, Max gives Tito a tranquilizer-laced drink, trying to calm him down before the performance. (Unbeknownst to either of them, Tito accidentally takes a double-dose of tranquilizers.) When he learns that Max is an aspiring opera singer, Tito kindly gives Max a singing lesson, teaching him to "loosen up" and sing with more confidence. Tito and Max sing a duet together ("Dio, che nell'alma infondere" from Verdi's <ref target="/wiki/Don_Carlos" title="Don Carlos">Don Carlos</ref>).</p>
<p>When Tito returns to the bedroom, he finds Maria's note. Horrified that his wife has left him, Tito goes into a fit of passion and tries to "kill himself" with various non-lethal objects (e.g. trying to stab himself with a wine bottle). Max manages to calm Tito down, and takes the singer into the bedroom, where Tito lies down on the bed for a rest.</p>
<p>Much later (Scene II), Max is unable to wake Tito from his nap. Max finds an empty medicine bottle and Maria's "Dear John" letter, which is written in such a way ("By the time you read this, I will be gone.") that Max mistakenly thinks Tito has committed suicide. When Saunders arrives, Max tearfully tells him that Tito is dead.</p>
<p>Saunders is furious. The opera performance will have to be cancelled, and the audience will demand their money back. It will be a disaster for the Cleveland opera, and for Saunders himself.</p>
<p>However, Saunders comes up with a plan. Since no one else knows that Tito is dead, Max will step into the Othello role and pretend to be Tito. Wearing Tito's costume and makeup, Max will star in the opera performance. The audience will never know that it is not Tito Merelli, and they can announce Tito's death tomorrow morning. Max reluctantly agrees to the plan. He goes into the bathroom to change, and later returns, dressed as Othello, in a costume, wig, and <ref target="/wiki/Blackface" title="Blackface">blackface</ref> makeup. As the curtain falls on Act One, Saunders and Max leave for the performance, just as Tito wakes up in the bedroom.</p>



<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:2012_Otello_darf_nicht_platzen_-_K%C3%A4rlich_E09,_M%C3%BCller,_Rutschmann.jpg"></ref>

<p>Nightcap for Merelli</p>




<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:2012_Otello_darf_nicht_platzen_-_K%C3%A4rlich_F05,_Rutschmann,_M%C3%BCller.jpg"></ref>

<p>Singing lesson with the maestro</p>




<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:2012_Otello_darf_nicht_platzen_-_K%C3%A4rlich_R05,_M%C3%BCller_u._Rutschmann.JPG"></ref>

<p>Who is the right Otello?</p>




<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:2012_Otello_darf_nicht_platzen,_K%C3%A4rlich_V04_-_Astrid_Letsch,_Michael_M%C3%BCller.jpg"></ref>

<p>Max singing for Maggie</p>




<h3>Act II[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Act II">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>As the second act opens, Saunders and Max return to the hotel suite. Max's performance as Othello was a huge success, and no one suspected that he was not Tito. Then Saunders gets a phone call, telling him that the police are downstairs in the lobby. They are looking for "a lunatic dressed as Othello, who thinks he's Tito Merelli." During Max's performance, the "lunatic" tried to force his way into the opera house, hit a policeman who tried to stop him, and ran away.</p>
<p>Saunders tells Max to quickly change out of his Othello costume and makeup, while he goes downstairs to handle the police. Max returns to the bedroom, but is shocked and horrified to find Tito is missing from the bed. Still wearing his Othello costume, Max leaves the hotel suite and runs to find Saunders.</p>
<p>A few seconds later, Tito Merelli returns to the hotel suite, also dressed as Othello, in a costume, wig, and blackface makeup. Frantic and on the run from the police, Tito is even more confused when other characters in the play show up to congratulate him on his "magnificent performance" as Othello.</p>
<p>For the rest of the play, Max and Tito—who are identical in their Othello costumes and makeup—are repeatedly mistaken for each other, as they alternately run in and out of the hotel suite. Max is mistaken for Tito, and Tito is mistaken for Max by Saunders. Also, Tito and Max both find themselves being romantically pursued by Maggie Saunders, and by Diana, the Cleveland Opera's sexy and ambitious soprano. Eventually, Diana seduces Tito in the bedroom, while Maggie simultaneously seduces Max (who she thinks is Tito) in the living room.</p>
<p>At the end of the play, things are sorted out. Maria returns to the hotel and makes up with the bewildered Tito, while Max manages to step into the bathroom long enough to change out of his Othello costume and wig, and emerge as himself. Tito and Maria leave together, while Saunders accompanies Diana to a downstairs reception. Maggie realizes that not only was Max the "Tito" that she made love to, he was also the "Tito" who sang so passionately in tonight's opera performance. As the play closes, Max and Maggie share a kiss.</p>

<h2>Productions[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: Productions">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>The play, originally titled Opera Buffa, had been produced at a summer theater, American Stage Festival, Milford, NH. The English director David Gilmore read it and asked to direct; <ref target="/wiki/Andrew_Lloyd_Webber" title="Andrew Lloyd Webber">Andrew Lloyd Webber</ref> was the producer.<ref target="#cite_note-1">[1]</ref></p>
<p>The <ref target="/wiki/West_End_theatre" title="West End theatre">West End</ref> production opened on March 6, 1986 at the <ref target="/wiki/Gielgud_Theatre" title="Gielgud Theatre">Globe Theatre</ref>, where it ran for ten months, closing on January 10, 1987. The cast featured <ref target="/wiki/Ron_Holgate" title="Ron Holgate">Ron Holgate</ref> (Tito), Anna Nicholas (Maria), <ref target="/wiki/Edward_Hibbert" title="Edward Hibbert">Edward Hibbert</ref> (Bellhop), <ref target="/wiki/Denis_Lawson" title="Denis Lawson">Denis Lawson</ref> (Max), <ref target="/wiki/Jan_Francis" title="Jan Francis">Jan Francis</ref> (Maggie), <ref target="/wiki/John_Barron_(actor)" title="John Barron (actor)">John Barron</ref> (Saunders), Gwendolyn Humble (Diana), and Josephine Blake (Julia).<ref target="#cite_note-2">[2]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-3">[3]</ref></p>
<p>After sixteen previews, the <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> production, directed by <ref target="/wiki/Jerry_Zaks" title="Jerry Zaks">Jerry Zaks</ref>, opened on March 2, 1989 at the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Royale_Theatre" title="Royale Theatre">Royale Theatre</ref>, and closed on April 22, 1990 after 476 performances. The cast included <ref target="/wiki/Philip_Bosco" title="Philip Bosco">Philip Bosco</ref> (Saunders), <ref target="/wiki/Victor_Garber" title="Victor Garber">Victor Garber</ref> (Max), Ron Holgate, <ref target="/wiki/Tovah_Feldshuh" title="Tovah Feldshuh">Tovah Feldshuh</ref> (Maria), <ref target="/wiki/Caroline_Lagerfelt" title="Caroline Lagerfelt">Caroline Lagerfelt</ref> (Diana), <ref target="/wiki/Jane_Connell" title="Jane Connell">Jane Connell</ref> (Julia), J. Smith-Cameron (Maggie) and Jeff Brooks (Bellhop).<ref target="#cite_note-4">[4]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-5">[5]</ref></p>
<p>A Broadway revival began performances at the <ref target="/wiki/Music_Box_Theatre" title="Music Box Theatre">Music Box Theatre</ref> on March 13, 2010 in preview and officially opened on April 4, 2010. Directed by <ref target="/wiki/Stanley_Tucci" title="Stanley Tucci">Stanley Tucci</ref>, the cast starred <ref target="/wiki/Anthony_LaPaglia" title="Anthony LaPaglia">Anthony LaPaglia</ref> (Tito Merelli), Jay Klaitz (Frank the Bellhop), <ref target="/wiki/Justin_Bartha" title="Justin Bartha">Justin Bartha</ref> (Max), <ref target="/wiki/Jan_Maxwell" title="Jan Maxwell">Jan Maxwell</ref> (Maria), Mary Catherine Garrison (Maggie), <ref target="/wiki/Jennifer_Laura_Thompson" title="Jennifer Laura Thompson">Jennifer Laura Thompson</ref> (Diana), and husband and wife couple <ref target="/wiki/Tony_Shalhoub" title="Tony Shalhoub">Tony Shalhoub</ref> (Saunders) and <ref target="/wiki/Brooke_Adams_(actress)" title="Brooke Adams (actress)">Brooke Adams</ref> (Julia).<ref target="#cite_note-6">[6]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-7">[7]</ref> The revival closed its limited run on August 15, 2010.</p>
<p>The musical version, with book and lyrics by Peter Sham and Music by Brad Carroll opened at the Theatre Royal, Plymouth, on 24 September and ran until 6 October 2010, after which it transferred to London's West End on 15 June 2011 and closed on 6 August 2011, despite mostly good reviews but two months of poor ticket sales.</p>

<h2>Characters[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: Characters">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Henry Saunders – The Cleveland Grand Opera's general manager. Father to Maggie. A blowhard who often loses his temper at the slightest mishap.</p>
<p>Max – Saunders' long-suffering assistant, who is forced to take Tito's place in the role of Othello.</p>
<p>Maggie Saunders – Saunders' daughter, and Max's girlfriend. She has a great admiration for Tito.</p>
<p>Tito Merelli – The world's most renowned opera tenor, and notorious ladies man.</p>
<p>Maria – Tito's long-suffering wife, with an "Italian temper". Leaves Tito early in the play, but ultimately returns to him. Loves Tito, despite his philandering.</p>
<p>Diana – The opera's ingenue soprano, who is "flinging her way" to the top. A seductive woman (and she knows it).</p>
<p>Julia – Chairwoman of the Cleveland Opera Guild, who considers herself a "grande dame." She wears a silver dress which, Saunders says, makes her look "like the <ref target="/wiki/Chrysler_Building" title="Chrysler Building">Chrysler Building</ref>."</p>
<p>The Bellhop – A comic relief character who has an ongoing feud with Saunders. An obnoxious opera fan, the Bellhop keeps showing up at the hotel suite at the wrong moment, trying to get an autograph and a photo of Tito Merelli. Saunders ends up chasing the Bellhop around the hotel suite, and trying to strangle him.</p>
<h2>Adaptations[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: Adaptations">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>A <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lend_Me_A_Tenor_(musical)" title="Lend Me A Tenor (musical)">musical adaptation</ref> was presented in May 2006 as a staged reading as part of the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Utah_Shakespearean_Festival" title="Utah Shakespearean Festival">Utah Shakespearean Festival</ref>'s New American Playwright Project, in Cedar City, Utah, followed by rewrites and a production as part of USF's Summer 2007 repertory season, which received rave reviews.<ref target="#cite_note-8">[8]</ref> The musical opened in London's West End in June 2011, directed by Ian Talbot and choreographed by <ref target="/wiki/Randy_Skinner" title="Randy Skinner">Randy Skinner</ref>.</p>
<p>A sequel titled Comedy of Tenors was written by Ludwig.<ref target="#cite_note-9">[9]</ref></p>

<h2>Awards and honors[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: Awards and honors">edit</ref>]</h2>
<h3>West End production[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=8" title="Edit section: West End production">edit</ref>]</h3>


<p>Year</p>

<p>Award</p>

<p>Category</p>

<p>Nominee</p>

<p>Result</p>


<p>1986</p>

<ref target="/wiki/Laurence_Olivier_Award" title="Laurence Olivier Award">Laurence Olivier Award</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Laurence_Olivier_Award_for_Best_New_Comedy" title="Laurence Olivier Award for Best New Comedy">Best New Comedy</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Ken_Ludwig" title="Ken Ludwig">Ken Ludwig</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>

<h3>Broadway production[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=9" title="Edit section: Broadway production">edit</ref>]</h3>


<p>Year</p>

<p>Award</p>

<p>Category</p>

<p>Nominee</p>

<p>Result</p>


<p>1989</p>

<ref target="/wiki/43rd_Tony_Awards" title="43rd Tony Awards">Tony Award</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Play">Best Play</ref>

<p>Ken Ludwig</p>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Actor_in_a_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Actor in a Play">Best Actor</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Philip_Bosco" title="Philip Bosco">Philip Bosco</ref>

<p>Won</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Victor_Garber" title="Victor Garber">Victor Garber</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Featured_Actress_in_a_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Featured Actress in a Play">Best Featured Actress</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Tovah_Feldshuh" title="Tovah Feldshuh">Tovah Feldshuh</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Scenic_Design" title="Tony Award for Best Scenic Design">Best Scenic Design</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Walton" title="Tony Walton">Tony Walton</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Costume_Design" title="Tony Award for Best Costume Design">Best Costume Design</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/William_Ivey_Long" title="William Ivey Long">William Ivey Long</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Direction_of_a_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Direction of a Play">Best Direction</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Jerry_Zaks" title="Jerry Zaks">Jerry Zaks</ref>

<p>Won</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award" title="Drama Desk Award">Drama Desk Award</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Actor_in_a_Play" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Actor in a Play">Outstanding Actor</ref>

<p>Philip Bosco</p>

<p>Won</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Featured_Actress_in_a_Play" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Featured Actress in a Play">Outstanding Featured Actress</ref>

<p>Tovah Feldshuh</p>

<p>Won</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Director_of_a_Play" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Director of a Play">Outstanding Director</ref>

<p>Jerry Zaks</p>

<p>Won</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Costume_Design" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Costume Design">Outstanding Costume Design</ref>

<p>William Ivey Long</p>

<p>Won</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Lighting_Design" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Lighting Design">Outstanding Lighting Design</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Paul_Gallo" title="Paul Gallo">Paul Gallo</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Set_Design" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Set Design">Outstanding Set Design</ref>

<p>Tony Walton</p>

<p>Nominated</p>

<h3>Revival[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=10" title="Edit section: Revival">edit</ref>]</h3>


<p>Year</p>

<p>Award</p>

<p>Category</p>

<p>Nominee</p>

<p>Result</p>


<p>2010</p>

<ref target="/wiki/64th_Tony_Awards" title="64th Tony Awards">Tony Award</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Revival_of_a_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Revival of a Play">Best Revival</ref>

<p>Ken Ludwig</p>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Performance_by_a_Featured_Actress_in_a_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Performance by a Featured Actress in a Play">Best Featured Actress</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Jan_Maxwell" title="Jan Maxwell">Jan Maxwell</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Costume_Design_of_a_Play" title="Tony Award for Best Costume Design of a Play">Best Costume Design</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Martin_Pakledinaz" title="Martin Pakledinaz">Martin Pakledinaz</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<ref target="/wiki/Outer_Critics_Circle_Award" title="Outer Critics Circle Award">Outer Critics Circle Award</ref><ref target="#cite_note-10">[10]</ref>

<p>Outstanding Revival</p>

<p>n/a</p>

<p>Nominated</p>


<p>Outstanding Director</p>

<ref target="/wiki/Stanley_Tucci" title="Stanley Tucci">Stanley Tucci</ref>

<p>Nominated</p>


<p>Outstanding Featured Actress</p>

<p>Jan Maxwell</p>

<p>Nominated</p>


<p>Outstanding Costume Design</p>

<p>Martin Pakledinaz</p>

<p>Nominated</p>

<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=11" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>


<ref target="#cite_ref-1">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.kenludwig.com/faq/how_did_mr_ludwig_get_his_first_commercial_production.php" rel="nofollow">FAQ on Lend Me a Tenor</ref> at kenludwig.com, accessed May 20, 2009

<ref target="#cite_ref-2">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.thisistheatre.com/shows/gielgud123.html" rel="nofollow">Listing for West End</ref> thisistheatre.com, accessed May 20, 2009

<ref target="#cite_ref-3">^</ref> Ludwig, Ken. Lend me a tenor (1989), Samuel French, Inc, .mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:"\"""\"""'""'"}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}<ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-573-69121-5" title="Special:BookSources/0-573-69121-5">0-573-69121-5</ref>, p. 5

<ref target="#cite_ref-4">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.ibdb.com/production.php?id=4535" rel="nofollow">"'Lend Me a Tenor' Listing"</ref> Internet Broadway Database, accessed September 20, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-5">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.kenludwig.com/original_cast/lend_me_a_tenor_the_original_cast.php" rel="nofollow">Cast List</ref> kenludwig.com, accessed September 20, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-6">^</ref> Hetrick, Adam. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.playbill.com/news/article/138413-The-Show-Must-Go-On-Lend-Me-a-Tenor-with-LaPaglia-Shalhoub-and-Bartha-Opens-on-Broadway" rel="nofollow">"The Show Must Go On: Lend Me a Tenor, with LaPaglia, Shalhoub and Bartha, Opens on Broadway"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100407202928/http://www.playbill.com/news/article/138413-The-Show-Must-Go-On-Lend-Me-a-Tenor-with-LaPaglia-Shalhoub-and-Bartha-Opens-on-Broadway" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2010-04-07 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref>. Playbill.com, April 4, 2010

<ref target="#cite_ref-7">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.broadwayworld.com/article/Justin_Bartha_Confirmed_for_LEND_ME_A_TENOR_20100105" rel="nofollow">Justin Bartha Confirmed for Lend Me a Tenor</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-8">^</ref> <ref class="external autonumber" href="http://www.kenludwig.com/Press%20Release%20Announcing%20the%20Show%20-%20Nov.%202%2C%202006.pdf" rel="nofollow">[1]</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-9">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/11/01/nyregion/review-performances-of-comedy-of-tenors-and-bandstand.html?_r=0" rel="nofollow">Review: Performances of ‘Comedy of Tenors’ and ‘Bandstand’</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-10">^</ref> Gans, Andrew (May 17, 2010). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.playbill.com/article/memphis-la-cage-zeta-jones-finneran-and-more-are-outer-critics-circle-award-winners-com-168485" rel="nofollow">"Memphis, La Cage, Zeta-Jones, Finneran and More Are Outer Critics Circle Award Winners"</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/Playbill" title="Playbill">Playbill</ref>. Retrieved September 7, 2018.


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit&section=12" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.ibdb.com/broadway-show/5331" rel="nofollow">Lend Me a Tenor</ref> at the <ref target="/wiki/Internet_Broadway_Database" title="Internet Broadway Database">Internet Broadway Database</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://theater2.nytimes.com/mem/theater/treview.html?res=950DE4DC103EF930A35750C0A96F948260/" rel="nofollow">New York Times review</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100418061338/http://community.nytimes.com/rate-review/theater.nytimes.com/show/24602/Lend-Me-a-Tenor/overview" rel="nofollow">New York Times reader reviews</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.google.com/hostednews/ap/article/ALeqM5gRuqi4htnnCPD0wgmC3WFDiiuxOAD9ESHPUO0" rel="nofollow">Associated Press review</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.tenorthemusical.co.uk/" rel="nofollow">Lend Me a Tenor The Musical website</ref>




<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&oldid=919287345">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&oldid=919287345</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:1986_plays" title="Category:1986 plays">1986 plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_by_Ken_Ludwig" title="Category:Plays by Ken Ludwig">Plays by Ken Ludwig</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Broadway_plays" title="Category:Broadway plays">Broadway plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Music_of_Cleveland" title="Category:Music of Cleveland">Music of Cleveland</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:Webarchive_template_wayback_links" title="Category:Webarchive template wayback links">Webarchive template wayback links</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=Lend+Me+a+Tenor" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=Lend+Me+a+Tenor" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/Lend_Me_a_Tenor" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:Lend_Me_a_Tenor" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/Lend_Me_a_Tenor">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/Lend_Me_a_Tenor" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/Lend_Me_a_Tenor" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&oldid=919287345" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q16386653" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&id=919287345" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=Lend+Me+a+Tenor">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=Lend+Me+a+Tenor&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Otello_darf_nicht_platzen" hreflang="de" lang="de" title="Otello darf nicht platzen – German">Deutsch</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D0%9E%D0%B4%D0%BE%D0%BB%D0%B6%D0%B8%D1%82%D0%B5_%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%BE%D1%80%D0%B0!" hreflang="ru" lang="ru" title="Одолжите тенора! – Russian">Русский</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q16386653#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 2 October 2019, at 21:45 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Lend_Me_a_Tenor&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.208","walltime":"0.320","ppvisitednodes":{"value":851,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":9887,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":674,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":15,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":0,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":1,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":14008,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":1,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 278.169 1 -total"," 50.60% 140.746 1 Template:Reflist"," 24.78% 68.928 1 Template:ISBN"," 15.41% 42.855 1 Template:Cite_web"," 14.92% 41.501 1 Template:About"," 14.69% 40.863 1 Template:Catalog_lookup_link"," 14.17% 39.420 1 Template:Infobox_play"," 12.47% 34.678 1 Template:Infobox"," 9.50% 26.431 1 Template:IBDB_show"," 4.92% 13.672 1 Template:Error-small"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.057","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":2880217,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1226","timestamp":"20191002214546","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"Lend Me a Tenor","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Lend_Me_a_Tenor","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q16386653","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q16386653","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2007-01-20T18:59:58Z","dateModified":"2019-10-02T21:45:46Z","image":"https:\/\/upload.wikimedia.org\/wikipedia\/en\/e\/ed\/LendMeATenor.JPG","headline":"play written by Ken Ludwig"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":91,"wgHostname":"mw1258"});});</p>


