



<p>Two Trains Running - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"Two_Trains_Running","wgTitle":"Two Trains Running","wgCurRevisionId":914448492,"wgRevisionId":914448492,"wgArticleId":3117927,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["Webarchive template wayback links","Articles needing additional references from October 2008","All articles needing additional references","Articles with IBDb links","1990 plays","All-Black cast Broadway shows","Plays by August Wilson","Pittsburgh in fiction","Off-Broadway plays","Laurence Olivier Award-winning plays","West End plays","Civil rights movement in popular culture","The Pittsburgh Cycle","Plays set in the 1960s","Plays set in Pennsylvania"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],</p>
<p>"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"Two_Trains_Running","wgRelevantArticleId":3117927,"wgRequestId":"XZiatQpAIDEAAJ8OJPgAAACA","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q7859307",</p>
<p>"wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","jquery.makeCollapsible.styles":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","jquery.makeCollapsible","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert",</p>
<p>"ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head","mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>


























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>Two Trains Running</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<p>Two Trains Running<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Two_Trains_Running.jpg"></ref>Broadway production posterWritten by<ref target="/wiki/August_Wilson" title="August Wilson">August Wilson</ref>Date premiered1990Place premiered<ref target="/wiki/Yale_Repertory_Theatre" title="Yale Repertory Theatre">Yale Repertory Theatre</ref><ref target="/wiki/New_Haven,_Connecticut" title="New Haven, Connecticut">New Haven, Connecticut</ref>Original languageSpanishSeries<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/The_Pittsburgh_Cycle" title="The Pittsburgh Cycle">The Pittsburgh Cycle</ref>SubjectThe uncertain future promised by the Civil Rights Movement of the 1960sGenreDramaSettingthe Hill District of Pittsburgh, 1969</p>
<p>Two Trains Running is a play by American playwright <ref target="/wiki/August_Wilson" title="August Wilson">August Wilson</ref>, the sixth in his ten-part series The Pittsburgh Cycle. The play premiered on <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> in 1993 and was a finalist for the <ref target="/wiki/Pulitzer_Prize_for_Drama" title="Pulitzer Prize for Drama">Pulitzer Prize for Drama</ref>. </p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Productions">1 Productions</ref>
<ref target="#Plot_synopsis">2 Plot synopsis</ref>
<ref target="#Historical_context">3 Historical context</ref>

<ref target="#African-American_migration">3.1 African-American migration</ref>
<ref target="#The_Hill_District_in_the_1960s">3.2 The Hill District in the 1960s</ref>
<ref target="#Urban_unrest_and_the_Black_Power_movement">3.3 Urban unrest and the Black Power movement</ref>
<ref target="#Black_women_in_the_1960s">3.4 Black women in the 1960s</ref>


<ref target="#Awards_and_nominations">4 Awards and nominations</ref>
<ref target="#References">5 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">6 External links</ref>


<h2>Productions[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Productions">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Two Trains Running was first performed by the <ref target="/wiki/Yale_Repertory_Theatre" title="Yale Repertory Theatre">Yale Repertory Theatre</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/New_Haven,_Connecticut" title="New Haven, Connecticut">New Haven, Connecticut</ref> in March 1990.<ref target="#cite_note-1">[1]</ref></p>
<p>It was then performed at the Huntington Theatre (<ref target="/wiki/Boston" title="Boston">Boston</ref>, Massachusetts), the <ref target="/wiki/Seattle_Repertory_Theatre" title="Seattle Repertory Theatre">Seattle Repertory Theatre</ref> (Seattle, Washington), and the <ref target="/wiki/Old_Globe_Theatre" title="Old Globe Theatre">Old Globe Theatre</ref>, (<ref target="/wiki/San_Diego" title="San Diego">San Diego</ref>, California).<ref target="#cite_note-2">[2]</ref></p>
<p>The play premiered on Broadway at the <ref target="/wiki/Walter_Kerr_Theatre" title="Walter Kerr Theatre">Walter Kerr Theatre</ref> on April 13, 1992. The play closed on August 30, 1992 after 160 performances and 7 previews. Directed by <ref target="/wiki/Lloyd_Richards" title="Lloyd Richards">Lloyd Richards</ref>, the cast featured <ref target="/wiki/Roscoe_Lee_Browne" title="Roscoe Lee Browne">Roscoe Lee Browne</ref> as Holloway, <ref target="/wiki/Anthony_Chisholm_(actor)" title="Anthony Chisholm (actor)">Anthony Chisholm</ref> as Wolf, <ref target="/wiki/Laurence_Fishburne" title="Laurence Fishburne">Laurence Fishburne</ref> as Sterling, Leonard Parker as West and Cynthia Martells as Risa.<ref target="#cite_note-vault-3">[3]</ref></p>

<h2>Plot synopsis[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Plot synopsis">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Characters</p>
<p>Holloway</p>
<p>Wolf</p>
<p>Sterling</p>
<p>Risa</p>
<p>West</p>
<p>Hambone</p>
<p>Memphis</p>
<p>The play takes place in the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Hill_District" title="Hill District">Hill District</ref>, an <ref target="/wiki/African-American_neighborhood" title="African-American neighborhood">African-American neighborhood</ref> in <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Pittsburgh,_Pennsylvania" title="Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania">Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</ref>, in 1969. It explores the social and psychological manifestations of changing attitudes toward race from the perspective of urban blacks.</p>

<h2>Historical context[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Historical context">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Question_book-new.svg"></ref>This section does not <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Citing_sources" title="Wikipedia:Citing sources">cite</ref> any <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Verifiability" title="Wikipedia:Verifiability">sources</ref>. Please help <ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit">improve this section</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Help:Introduction_to_referencing_with_Wiki_Markup/1" title="Help:Introduction to referencing with Wiki Markup/1">adding citations to reliable sources</ref>. Unsourced material may be challenged and <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Verifiability#Burden_of_evidence" title="Wikipedia:Verifiability">removed</ref>. (October 2008) (<ref target="/wiki/Help:Maintenance_template_removal" title="Help:Maintenance template removal">Learn how and when to remove this template message</ref>)
<h3>African-American migration[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: African-American migration">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Further information: <ref target="/wiki/Great_Migration_(African_American)" title="Great Migration (African American)">Great Migration (African American)</ref></p>
<p>Seeking to escape from poverty, <ref target="/wiki/Racism" title="Racism">racism</ref>, and segregatory "<ref target="/wiki/Jim_Crow_laws" title="Jim Crow laws">Jim Crow</ref>" laws, many black Americans migrated to northern industrial cities during the early and mid-20th century. Most of these migrants had worked in agriculture in the former <ref target="/wiki/Confederate_States_of_America" title="Confederate States of America">Confederate</ref> slave states, and few were well acquainted with urban life. Broadly speaking, blacks who moved north could expect higher wages, better educational opportunities, and greater potential for social advancement than they had received in the South.</p>
<p>While racism in the North was arguably less violent and overt than in the South, it was nonetheless present. Though <ref target="/wiki/Lynching" title="Lynching">lynching</ref> was rarer and de jure segregation did not exist in the North, negative attitudes towards blacks prevailed among many white citizens. As industrial, <ref target="/wiki/Inner_city" title="Inner city">inner city</ref> neighborhoods became increasingly black, many whites left for the suburbs, taking their capital assets with them.</p>
<p>The result was the rapid emergence of overwhelmingly black neighborhoods, which, generally speaking, suffered tragically high poverty and crime rates. Yet these neighborhoods also simmered with hopes of economic, social, and political advancement. As such, they served as fertile soil for the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Civil_Rights_Movement" title="Civil Rights Movement">Civil Rights Movement</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Black_Power_movement" title="Black Power movement">Black Power movement</ref>. Two Trains Running is set in such a neighborhood.</p>

<h3>The Hill District in the 1960s[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: The Hill District in the 1960s">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The restaurant in the play is at 1621 Wylie Avenue, in Pittsburgh's Hill District. In the 1940s and 1950s, the Hill District was one of the most prosperous, culturally active black neighborhoods in the United States. In 1960s, however, the neighborhood had suffered a sharp economic decline.</p>
<ref target="#cite_note-study-4">[4]</ref>
<p>In the play, Memphis recounts how his restaurant, which now sees few patrons, used to be packed with customers. He discusses how many once-bustling small businesses have since closed down.</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Urban_Redevelopment_Authority_of_Pittsburgh" title="Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh">Pittsburgh's Urban Redevelopment Authority</ref> seized land in the area throughout the 1960s, as part of the movement known generally as <ref target="/wiki/Urban_renewal" title="Urban renewal">urban renewal</ref>. Countless buildings were destroyed to make way for the <ref target="/wiki/Civic_Arena_(Pittsburgh)" title="Civic Arena (Pittsburgh)">Civic Arena</ref> and various public housing projects.<ref target="#cite_note-study-4">[4]</ref> This effort displaced thousands of people, and is remembered as one of the most catastrophic urban development efforts in US history.
<p>In the play, Memphis's building is to be seized by the city (presumably by the URA), and he is nervous about the price he will receive for it. Speaking of the eminent domain clause in his deed, he says "They don't know I got a clause of my own... They can carry me out feet first... but my clause say... they got to meet my price!" Like Hambone's "He gonna give me my ham", this indignant insistence is not just material. It represents an unyielding demand for dignity and respect from those who have historically been denied it.</p>

<h3>Urban unrest and the Black Power movement[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: Urban unrest and the Black Power movement">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Throughout Act Two of the play, Sterling (a young man from the neighborhood recently released from the state penitentiary) eagerly awaits a rally, for which he tries to generate interest at the restaurant. Though he makes it clear that the rally involves racial justice, he does not specify its exact motivations or political aims. Memphis reacts with scorn when Sterling posts a flyer for the event, but he never makes it clear exactly why he is so uncomfortable with it.</p>
<p>To understand the significance of the rally, one must consider the history of riots in Pittsburgh in the late 1960s. After the assassination of <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Martin_Luther_King,_Jr." title="Martin Luther King, Jr.">Martin Luther King, Jr.</ref> on April 4, 1968, a wave of riots struck urban, black areas of the United States. Though not as devastating as the riots in Washington, D.C. and Chicago, the riots in Pittsburgh damaged black areas economically and escalated tensions with the city police.</p>
<p>Memphis's scorn also reflects a broader generational conflict on the topic of resistance that came to a head in the 1960s. Many older, southern-born blacks like Memphis had learned to survive by not stirring up trouble with the white establishment. Many in the younger generation, such as Sterling, viewed this attitude as implicit submission—a remnant of slave mentality worthy of contempt.</p>
<p>This shift in attitude is evident in the evolution of the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Civil_Rights_Movement" title="Civil Rights Movement">Civil Rights Movement</ref>. In 1960, the movement relied primarily on legal action and political lobbying by organizations such as the <ref target="/wiki/NAACP" title="NAACP">NAACP</ref>. Over the next few years, however, <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Nonviolent" title="Nonviolent">nonviolent</ref> mass action emerged as the primary tactic, manifesting in events such as the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/1963_March_on_Washington" title="1963 March on Washington">1963 March on Washington</ref>. By the late 1960s, however, many younger members of the movement, questioned the idea of nonviolence. For example, in 1966, <ref target="/wiki/Stokely_Carmichael" title="Stokely Carmichael">Stokely Carmichael</ref> became leader of the <ref target="/wiki/Student_Nonviolent_Coordinating_Committee" title="Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee">Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee</ref> (SNCC). Carmichael believed that true liberation for black people required direct seizure of power rather than appeal to white power structures. Pursuant to this belief, he dismissed all white members of SNCC. The organization effectively became part of the <ref target="/wiki/Black_Power" title="Black Power">Black Power</ref> movement, and over the next few years dissolved, as many of its leaders (including Carmichael) joined the more radical <ref target="/wiki/Black_Panther_Party" title="Black Panther Party">Black Panther Party</ref>.</p>

<h3>Black women in the 1960s[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: Black women in the 1960s">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Though she has relatively few lines, Risa is one of the most powerful characters in Two Trains Running. Despite his long struggles with oppression, Memphis seems to have little idea of his oppressive behavior toward Risa. He never thanks her or shows appreciation for her work, and he constantly meddles in her affairs as if she could not manage without him.</p>
<p>While Holloway is polite to Risa, he does nothing to defend her from Memphis' persistent criticism. For all he has to say on the topic of racial injustice, he seems oblivious or apathetic to the injustice that occurs right before his eyes at the restaurant.</p>
<p>When Sterling invites Risa to the rally, she shows surprisingly little interest. Though she does not say so explicitly, it appears she feels alienated from the Civil Rights and Black Power movements.</p>
<p>This interaction elegantly portrays the exclusion of women from the movement. As one author writes:</p>

<p>The movement, though ostensibly for the liberation of the black race, was in word and deed for the liberation of the black male. Race was extremely sexualized in the rhetoric of the movement. Freedom was equated with manhood and the freedom of blacks with the redemption of black masculinity.<ref target="#cite_note-5">[5]</ref> </p>
<h2>Awards and nominations[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=8" title="Edit section: Awards and nominations">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Awards</p>
<p>1991 American Theatre Critics Association New Play Award, for the best new play not yet produced in New York <ref target="#cite_note-6">[6]</ref></p>
<p>1992 Tony Award, Best Featured Actor in a Play (Fishburne)</p>
<p>1992 <ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award" title="Drama Desk Award">Drama Desk Award</ref> Outstanding Featured Actor in a Play (Fishburne)</p>
<p>2007 <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lucille_Lortel_Award" title="Lucille Lortel Award">Lucille Lortel Award</ref> for Outstanding Revival</p>
<p>Nominations</p>
<p>1992 Pulitzer Prize for Drama<ref target="#cite_note-7">[7]</ref></p>
<p>1992 Tony Award for Best Play <ref target="#cite_note-vault-3">[3]</ref></p>
<p>1992 Tony Award Best Featured Actor in a Play (Brown)</p>
<p>1992 Tony Award Best Featured Actress in a Play (Martells)</p>
<p>2007 Audelco Award for Dramatic Production of the Year</p>
<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=9" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>


<ref target="#cite_ref-1">^</ref> Rizzo, Frank. <ref class="external text" href="http://articles.courant.com/1992-04-13/features/0000203287_1_wilson-s-cycle-wilson-director-lloyd-richards-broadway-producer" rel="nofollow">"'Trains Likely To Be Rep's Last Ride To Broadway"</ref> Hartford Courant, April 13, 1992

<ref target="#cite_ref-2">^</ref> Churnin, Nancy. <ref class="external text" href="http://articles.latimes.com/1991-03-15/entertainment/ca-248_1_artistic-director&usg=AFQjCNE_iO71-3D4s9zLBn1OkJAtikVLTw" rel="nofollow">"A Director With a New Direction : Stage: Lloyd Richards, at the Old Globe for 'Two Trains,' will abandon some tasks to concentrate on what matters most to him: directing, teaching and searching out new talent."</ref> Los Angeles Times, March 15, 1991

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-vault_3-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-vault_3-1">b</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.playbill.com/production/two-trains-running-walter-kerr-theatre-vault-0000010053#" rel="nofollow">"'Two Trains Running" Broadway"</ref> </p>
<p>playbill.com, accessed April 12, 2016</p>

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-study_4-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-study_4-1">b</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://theoldglobe.org/_pdf/studyguides/two-trains-study-guide.pdf" rel="nofollow">"Study Guide, The Hill District, p. 4"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120823185541/http://theoldglobe.org/_pdf/studyguides/two-trains-study-guide.pdf" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2012-08-23 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref> theoldglobe.org, accessed April 12, 2016</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-5">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.mit.edu/activities/thistle/v9/9.01/6blackf.html" rel="nofollow">"Black Women in the Black Liberation Movement"</ref> But Some of Us Are Brave: A History of Black Feminism in the United States, mit.edu, accessed April 12, 2016

<ref target="#cite_ref-6">^</ref> <ref class="external autonumber" href="http://americantheatrecritics.org/steinberg-atca-award/" rel="nofollow">[1]</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-7">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.pulitzer.org/prize-winners-by-category/218" rel="nofollow">"Pulitzer Prize, Drama"</ref> pulitzer.org, accessed April 12, 2016


<p>Wilson, August (1992). <ref class="external text" href="https://archive.org/details/twotrainsrunning00wils" rel="nofollow">Two Trains Running</ref> (First ed.). New York: Plume. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-452-26929-6" title="Special:BookSources/0-452-26929-6">0-452-26929-6</ref>..mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:"\"""\"""'""'"}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}</p>
<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit&section=10" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.ibdb.com/broadway-production/4678" rel="nofollow">Two Trains Running</ref> at the <ref target="/wiki/Internet_Broadway_Database" title="Internet Broadway Database">Internet Broadway Database</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.lortel.org/Archives/Production/4416" rel="nofollow">Two Trains Running</ref> at the <ref target="/wiki/Lortel_Archives" title="Lortel Archives">Internet Off-Broadway Database</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Template:Pittsburgh_Cycle" title="Template:Pittsburgh Cycle">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:Pittsburgh_Cycle" title="Template talk:Pittsburgh Cycle">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:Pittsburgh_Cycle&action=edit">e</ref><ref target="/wiki/August_Wilson" title="August Wilson">August Wilson</ref>'s <ref target="/wiki/August_Wilson#The_Pittsburgh_Cycle" title="August Wilson">Pittsburgh Cycle</ref>Plays
<ref target="/wiki/Fences_(play)" title="Fences (play)">Fences</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Gem_of_the_Ocean" title="Gem of the Ocean">Gem of the Ocean</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Jitney_(play)" title="Jitney (play)">Jitney</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Joe_Turner%27s_Come_and_Gone" title="Joe Turner's Come and Gone">Joe Turner's Come and Gone</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/King_Hedley_II" title="King Hedley II">King Hedley II</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Ma_Rainey%27s_Black_Bottom" title="Ma Rainey's Black Bottom">Ma Rainey's Black Bottom</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Piano_Lesson" title="The Piano Lesson">The Piano Lesson</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Radio_Golf" title="Radio Golf">Radio Golf</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Seven_Guitars" title="Seven Guitars">Seven Guitars</ref>
<ref class="mw-selflink selflink">Two Trains Running</ref>
<p>Adaptations</p>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Piano_Lesson_(film)" title="The Piano Lesson (film)">The Piano Lesson</ref> (1995 film)
<ref target="/wiki/Fences_(film)" title="Fences (film)">Fences</ref> (2016 film)
<ref target="/wiki/Ma_Rainey%27s_Black_Bottom_(film)" title="Ma Rainey's Black Bottom (film)">Ma Rainey's Black Bottom</ref> (upcoming film)





<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&oldid=914448492">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&oldid=914448492</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:1990_plays" title="Category:1990 plays">1990 plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:All-Black_cast_Broadway_shows" title="Category:All-Black cast Broadway shows">All-Black cast Broadway shows</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_by_August_Wilson" title="Category:Plays by August Wilson">Plays by August Wilson</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Pittsburgh_in_fiction" title="Category:Pittsburgh in fiction">Pittsburgh in fiction</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Off-Broadway_plays" title="Category:Off-Broadway plays">Off-Broadway plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Laurence_Olivier_Award-winning_plays" title="Category:Laurence Olivier Award-winning plays">Laurence Olivier Award-winning plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:West_End_plays" title="Category:West End plays">West End plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Civil_rights_movement_in_popular_culture" title="Category:Civil rights movement in popular culture">Civil rights movement in popular culture</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:The_Pittsburgh_Cycle" title="Category:The Pittsburgh Cycle">The Pittsburgh Cycle</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_set_in_the_1960s" title="Category:Plays set in the 1960s">Plays set in the 1960s</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_set_in_Pennsylvania" title="Category:Plays set in Pennsylvania">Plays set in Pennsylvania</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:Webarchive_template_wayback_links" title="Category:Webarchive template wayback links">Webarchive template wayback links</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_needing_additional_references_from_October_2008" title="Category:Articles needing additional references from October 2008">Articles needing additional references from October 2008</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:All_articles_needing_additional_references" title="Category:All articles needing additional references">All articles needing additional references</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_IBDb_links" title="Category:Articles with IBDb links">Articles with IBDb links</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=Two+Trains+Running" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=Two+Trains+Running" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/Two_Trains_Running" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:Two_Trains_Running" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/Two_Trains_Running">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/Two_Trains_Running" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/Two_Trains_Running" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&oldid=914448492" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7859307" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=Two_Trains_Running&id=914448492" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=Two+Trains+Running">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=Two+Trains+Running&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>



<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7859307#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Add interlanguage links">Add links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 7 September 2019, at 14:47 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Two_Trains_Running&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.252","walltime":"0.376","ppvisitednodes":{"value":681,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":20482,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":463,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":9,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":1,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":0,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":5791,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":0,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 329.060 1 -total"," 28.49% 93.751 1 Template:Cite_book"," 20.77% 68.332 1 Template:Infobox_play"," 18.97% 62.427 1 Template:Infobox"," 15.40% 50.670 1 Template:Unreferenced_section"," 13.71% 45.107 1 Template:Unreferenced"," 12.44% 40.928 1 Template:Ambox"," 12.18% 40.063 1 Template:Details"," 11.01% 36.243 1 Template:Reflist"," 4.54% 14.939 1 Template:Webarchive"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.122","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":2709396,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1339","timestamp":"20190907144744","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"Two Trains Running","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Two_Trains_Running","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7859307","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7859307","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2005-11-09T16:33:21Z","dateModified":"2019-09-07T14:47:44Z","image":"https:\/\/upload.wikimedia.org\/wikipedia\/en\/b\/b3\/Two_Trains_Running.jpg","headline":"play written by August Wilson"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":119,"wgHostname":"mw1328"});});</p>


