



<p>Jake's Women - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"Jake's_Women","wgTitle":"Jake's Women","wgCurRevisionId":911902844,"wgRevisionId":911902844,"wgArticleId":1915743,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["Wikipedia articles with plot summary needing attention from August 2019","All Wikipedia articles with plot summary needing attention","Commons category link is on Wikidata","1996 films","Plays by Neil Simon","Plays set in New York City","1992 plays"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun",</p>
<p>"Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"Jake's_Women","wgRelevantArticleId":1915743,"wgRequestId":"XZo17QpAAD0AAGN-fisAAAAN","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q6124524","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":</p>
<p>"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","jquery.makeCollapsible.styles":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","jquery.makeCollapsible","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head","mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init",</p>
<p>"ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>

























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>Jake's Women</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<p>Jake's WomenWritten by<ref target="/wiki/Neil_Simon" title="Neil Simon">Neil Simon</ref>Characters</p>
<p>Jake</p>
<p>Maggie</p>
<p>Karen</p>
<p>Julie</p>
<p>Edith</p>
<p>Molly</p>
<p>Sheila</p>
<p>Date premieredMarch 24, 1992 (1992-03-24)Place premiered<ref target="/wiki/Old_Globe_Theatre" title="Old Globe Theatre">Old Globe Theatre</ref> (<ref target="/wiki/San_Diego" title="San Diego">San Diego</ref>, California)SettingNew York in the 1980s</p>
<p>Jake's Women is a 1992 play by <ref target="/wiki/Neil_Simon" title="Neil Simon">Neil Simon</ref>. The play centers on Jake, a writer with a struggling marriage. Jake talks to many of the women he knows, both in real life and in his imagination, as he works to save his marriage. Jake, suffering with psychosis and seeing representations of his daughter at age 12, his late wife Julie and recently divorced wife Maggie, is dealing with the inability to write productively and must resolve these issues before he does so.</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Productions">1 Productions</ref>

<ref target="#History">1.1 History</ref>


<ref target="#Plot">2 Plot</ref>
<ref target="#Film">3 Film</ref>
<ref target="#References">4 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">5 External links</ref>


<h2>Productions[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Productions">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Jake's Women opened on <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> at the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Neil_Simon_Theater" title="Neil Simon Theater">Neil Simon Theater</ref> on March 24, 1992 and closed on October 25, 1992 after 245 performances and 14 previews.<ref target="#cite_note-1">[1]</ref> Directed by <ref target="/wiki/Gene_Saks" title="Gene Saks">Gene Saks</ref>, the cast featured <ref target="/wiki/Alan_Alda" title="Alan Alda">Alan Alda</ref> (Jake), <ref target="/wiki/Helen_Shaver" title="Helen Shaver">Helen Shaver</ref> (Maggie), <ref target="/wiki/Brenda_Vaccaro" title="Brenda Vaccaro">Brenda Vaccaro</ref> (Karen), <ref target="/wiki/Kate_Burton_(actress)" title="Kate Burton (actress)">Kate Burton</ref> (Julie), <ref target="/wiki/Joyce_Van_Patten" title="Joyce Van Patten">Joyce Van Patten</ref> (Edith), <ref target="/wiki/Tracy_Pollan" title="Tracy Pollan">Tracy Pollan</ref> (Molly at 21), and <ref target="/wiki/Talia_Balsam" title="Talia Balsam">Talia Balsam</ref> (Sheila).<ref target="#cite_note-2">[2]</ref> The sets and costumes were by <ref target="/wiki/Santo_Loquasto" title="Santo Loquasto">Santo Loquasto</ref> and the lighting by <ref target="/wiki/Tharon_Musser" title="Tharon Musser">Tharon Musser</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-3">[3]</ref></p>
<p>Alan Alda was nominated for the <ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award" title="Tony Award">Tony Award</ref> for Best Actor in a Play.<ref target="#cite_note-4">[4]</ref></p>

<h3>History[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: History">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Jake's Women premiered at the <ref target="/wiki/Old_Globe_Theatre" title="Old Globe Theatre">Old Globe Theatre</ref> (<ref target="/wiki/San_Diego" title="San Diego">San Diego</ref>, California) in March 1990, running through April, starring <ref target="/wiki/Peter_Coyote" title="Peter Coyote">Peter Coyote</ref> with direction by <ref target="/wiki/Jack_O%27Brien_(director)" title="Jack O'Brien (director)">Jack O'Brien</ref>. According to Simon, after that production closed he re-wrote "70 percent", and the role of Jake was re-cast with Alan Alda with a new director, Gene Saks. The role of Jake was re-written, according to Simon: "Jake used to just react to the other people...now he's the centerpiece."<ref target="#cite_note-5">[5]</ref></p>
<p>Prior to its Broadway opening, Jake's Women was staged at the <ref target="/wiki/Stevens_Center" title="Stevens Center">Stevens Center</ref> in Winston-Salem as part of the <ref target="/wiki/University_of_North_Carolina_School_of_the_Arts" title="University of North Carolina School of the Arts">North Carolina School of the Arts</ref> Broadway Preview Series. The show, starring Alan Alda, had 19 sold-out performances.<ref target="#cite_note-6">[6]</ref></p>
<p>In 2016 Jake's Women was staged at Beit Zvi Theatre in Ramat Gan, Israel.<ref target="#cite_note-7">[7]</ref></p>

<h2>Plot[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Plot">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>This article's plot summary may be <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:How_to_write_a_plot_summary" title="Wikipedia:How to write a plot summary">too long or excessively detailed</ref>. Please <ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=edit">help improve it</ref> by removing unnecessary details and making it more concise. (August 2019) (<ref target="/wiki/Help:Maintenance_template_removal" title="Help:Maintenance template removal">Learn how and when to remove this template message</ref>)</p>
<p>Act One:</p>
<p>Jake is a successful writer living in New York in 1990. His marriage to wife Maggie is beginning to fall apart. We begin by seeing Jake on stage typing, then, interrupted by a phone call he gets into an argument with sister Karen about meeting up on Saturday night for dinner. After hanging up, an imaginary Maggie 'appears', stating he's always working and he's so busy she doesn't even know why he thought of her. Jake then persuades her to act out the scene in which they met eight years ago at a July fourth party. Maggie plays along for a bit before interrupting the fantasy, stating that the past is not helping them get through the future. Jake expresses his disappointment, and Maggie leaves.</p>
<p>Jake then confides in the audience in how his marriage is in trouble, before calling on his sister Karen to help him. Karen 'appears' and expresses her irritation at his calling her while she was watching The Godfather I, II and III. </p>
<p>Jake explains that he and Maggie are in trouble, and he believes that she has been having an affair with a new man in her office. Karen aggravates him into admitting he had an affair with an actress a year ago before explaining he loves Maggie more than ever and would do anything to keep her. Maggie then arrives home and has just started upstairs for a shower when Jake explains he wishes to speak to her before dinner. Maggie goes to the bathroom, and Karen warns him not to cause trouble for him. She then leaves.</p>
<p>Maggie enters and begins to fix herself a drink, and Jake explains that they are going to dinner with Karen on Saturday before Maggie interrupts, stating she has to go to Philadelphia on Saturday. This then leads to an argument between the two, leading Jake to ask, "Do you want out of this marriage?" Stunned, Maggie expresses her wish to stay with him before another argument ensues, with Maggie telling Jake he is controlling and spends more time on his work than with her. She then proposes that they separate for six months to give them some breathing space.</p>
<p>As Maggie begins to leave the room, Jake asks her if 'Michael Jaffe' has anything to do with the separation. He interrogates Maggie until she admits she has slept with Michael, but it wasn't an affair because "it stopped as soon as it started." Maggie then leaves the room.</p>
<p>As Jake is sitting there miserably, his daughter Molly, age twelve, "appears" and begins to talk to him. When asking him if he and Maggie are separating because they both had an affair, Jake violently expresses his reluctance to discuss such matters with a young girl, stating that if she were older, he would discuss it. Younger Molly then agrees, exits, and is replaced by Molly at age twenty one. Older Molly tells her father that the problems between him and Maggie are caused by Julie, Jake's late wife and Molly's mother. Molly then persuades Jake to talk to his psychiatrist in his mind, stating it'll give him complete control - his favourite thing in life. Jake agrees and Molly exits.</p>
<p>Edith, Jake's psychiatrist then enters, mocking Jake and his problems. She taunts him and gives seemingly useless advice, stating that he "likes to deprive himself." Eventually, she coerces him into saying what he wants the most, which he says is Julie.</p>
<p>Julie then appears, at age twenty one, doing a crossword puzzle and asking Jake for the answers. An ice cream truck is then heard and Julie exits.</p>
<p>Jake then continues to talk to Edith, getting angrier and angrier at her as she continuously taunts and mocks him. Maggie then enters and Jake fixes her a drink, Edith 'fades out' while telling Jake that he always has options and to listen to his wife. Jake and Maggie then launch into a discussion of how Maggie can't seem to stop "running." She explains that she needs time for herself, and after six months they will see if things are any better. Jake scornfully remarks that "you can't keep what you give up," and Maggie tells him that Jake never let Julie go, despite her death. We find out that Maggie has been pregnant several times, but evidently has had miscarriages. Maggie then exits.</p>
<p>Jake confides in the audience that he has tried to let Julie go, and she is always "bursting in on him." Julie, age twenty one then appears, yelling angrily and demanding to know where he has been. Jake is confused until Julie states that they have slept together the previous night. Jake explains to her that it wasn't a late night, and it was twenty-nine years ago. Julie begins to understand that time has passed before stating, "last night was wonderful." Jake then explains to her that they could never be together as they once were, and Julie, horrified, asks him if he is dead.</p>
<p>Jake calls on Karen to help him explain to Julie her death. Then Julie expresses her relief, telling Jake, "I hate it when somebody I love dies." Julie then expresses her irritation at the fact that Jake only calls her when he's in trouble. Edith appears and she and Karen help support Julie's argument. Julie asks Jake to make her thirty-six, but when he tells her he can't, she begins to fade out in annoyance. Jake finally tells her that she never was thirty-six, that she died in a car accident when she was thirty-five while taking Molly up to camp. Edith and Karen leave. At first, Julie is confused as to who Molly is but then realizes she has a daughter. After Jake shows her a photo Julie expresses her wish to see Molly, asking Jake to summon her up. Jake refuses, but eventually agrees to let Molly and Julie meet on Julie's "birthday." Molly calls and Jake speaks to her, with Julie exiting.</p>
<p>Jake hangs up and tells the audience how Molly is the only human he ever trusted. He then reminisces about the time when Molly and Maggie met eight years ago. A younger Maggie then enters expressing her apologies for being late. She and Jake then chat about going out to dinner before Maggie kisses him just as Molly enters. Molly and Maggie exchange greetings and Maggie hands her a present, which turns out to be an out of date World Atlas. Maggie, embarrassed, admits she grabbed it without looking. Molly then exits, to turn off her TV, and Maggie expresses her joy. She then leaves to the bathroom. Molly enters and tells Jake that he and Maggie should marry straight away. A phone is then heard and Molly leaves.</p>
<p>Present Maggie enters and states she is staying at the beach house. She then exits the apartment. Jake gloomily sits on the couch before both Mollys, age twelve and twenty one, appear and sit with him. They try to play a game but it ends up relating back to Maggie, so they simply sit.</p>
<p>Act Two:</p>
<p>Begins with Jake, once again, seated at his computer typing. Maggie enters seductively and expresses her wish to be with him again, before laughing in his face. It is realized that Maggie is only a hallucination and she leaves. Jake confides in the audience on how his imaginary women are appearing without his summons, before Karen enters, asking to speak with him.</p>
<p>Karen and Jake get into an argument over his relationships and it is found that he has had several relationships in the six months that Maggie has been gone. He is currently with a woman named Shelia. Edith arrives and together, she and Karen irritate him. Jake realizes they are "really there" and calls Edith in order to help get rid of the hallucinations. Karen and Edith then leave. Jake tells the audience he never called Edith—that it was a trick to get rid of Karen and Edith in his head.</p>
<p>The doorbell rings and Shelia enters. She and Jake have a strange conversation in which Jake's insanity starts to become clear. Maggie then appears and begins to mock Jake from behind Shelia's back. Jake grows angry with Maggie, frequently shouting at her, with Shelia (who cannot see Maggie) growing frightened. She eventually runs out of the house screaming.</p>
<p>After an Imaginary reunion between Julie and Molly, the real Maggie returns to talk with Jake. She informs him that she has dinner plans with someone and that she believes that person is going to propose, leading to an argument between Jake and Maggie, and eventually Maggie's departure.</p>
<p>Suddenly, Jake hears the voice of his late mother. She informs him of her forgiveness and love of him and then disappears. Then all of the other imaginary characters reappear and say goodbye to Jake. The real Maggie then enters and announces that she canceled the dinner date. She wants to work things out with Jake. Jake walks towards her and they reach out towards each other like <ref target="/wiki/The_Creation_of_Adam" title="The Creation of Adam">The Creation of Adam</ref> in the <ref target="/wiki/Sistine_Chapel" title="Sistine Chapel">Sistine Chapel</ref>. The lights fade to black.</p>

<h2>Film[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: Film">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>In <ref target="/wiki/1996_in_film" title="1996 in film">1996</ref>, the play was made into a TV movie starring <ref target="/wiki/Alan_Alda" title="Alan Alda">Alan Alda</ref> with direction by <ref target="/wiki/Glenn_Jordan" title="Glenn Jordan">Glenn Jordan</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-8">[8]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-9">[9]</ref> Both Alda and Van Patten were brought in from the original cast to reprise respectively the roles of Jake and Edith.</p>

<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>


<ref target="#cite_ref-1">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.playbillvault.com/Show/Detail/858/Jakes-Women" rel="nofollow">Jake's Women</ref> playbillvault.com, accessed April 13, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-2">^</ref> Rich, Frank. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.theater.nytimes.com/mem/theater/treview.html?res=9E0CEED91F3CF936A15750C0A964958260" rel="nofollow">"Review/Theater; 'Jake's Women,' a New Chapter in the Sex Wars"</ref> <ref target="/wiki/The_New_York_Times" title="The New York Times">The New York Times</ref>, March 25, 1992

<ref target="#cite_ref-3">^</ref> Simon, Neil. <ref class="external text" href="https://books.google.com/books?id=tJKheX7zGywC&pg=PA3#v=onepage" rel="nofollow">"Script"</ref> Jake's Women (1993), (books.google.com), Samuel French, Inc., ISBN unknown, pp.2-6

<ref target="#cite_ref-4">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.ibdb.com/production.php?id=4668" rel="nofollow">Jake's Women</ref> Internet Broadway Database, accessed April 14, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-5">^</ref> Churnin, Nancy. <ref class="external text" href="http://articles.latimes.com/1991-09-05/entertainment/ca-2392_1_jake-s-women" rel="nofollow">"Rewritten 'Jake's Women' Back on Broadway Track"</ref> Los Angeles Times, September 5, 1991

<ref target="#cite_ref-6">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.uncsa.edu/stevenscenter/" rel="nofollow">"History, Stevens Center"</ref> uncsa.edu, accessed April 13, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-7">^</ref> <ref class="external free" href="http://www.beit-zvi.com/?CategoryID=10&ArticleID=1089&SearchParam=%D7%94%D7%A0%D7%A9%D7%99%D7%9D+%D7%A9%D7%9C+%D7%92%27%D7%99%D7%99%D7%A7" rel="nofollow">http://www.beit-zvi.com/?CategoryID=10&ArticleID=1089&SearchParam=%D7%94%D7%A0%D7%A9%D7%99%D7%9D+%D7%A9%D7%9C+%D7%92%27%D7%99%D7%99%D7%A7</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-8">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116680/" rel="nofollow">Jake's Women</ref> Internet Movie Database, accessed April 13, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-9">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.tcm.com/tcmdb/title/473170/Neil-Simon-s-Jake-s-Women/" rel="nofollow">Jake's Women</ref> .tcm.com, accessed April 13, 2012


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>



<p>Wikimedia Commons has media related to <ref class="extiw" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Jake%27s_Women" title="commons:Category:Jake's Women">Jake's Women</ref>.</p>

<ref class="external text" href="https://www.ibdb.com/broadway-show/4837" rel="nofollow">Jake's Women</ref> at the <ref target="/wiki/Internet_Broadway_Database" title="Internet Broadway Database">Internet Broadway Database</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://thattheatresite.com/library/showpages/show_501.html" rel="nofollow">Jake's Woman at ThatTheatreSite</ref> Provides character descriptions, updated audition listings, and other useful show resources.
<ref target="/wiki/Template:Neil_Simon" title="Template:Neil Simon">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:Neil_Simon" title="Template talk:Neil Simon">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:Neil_Simon&action=edit">e</ref><ref target="/wiki/Neil_Simon" title="Neil Simon">Neil Simon</ref>Plays
<ref target="/wiki/Come_Blow_Your_Horn" title="Come Blow Your Horn">Come Blow Your Horn</ref> (1961)
<ref target="/wiki/Barefoot_in_the_Park" title="Barefoot in the Park">Barefoot in the Park</ref> (1963)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Odd_Couple_(play)" title="The Odd Couple (play)">The Odd Couple</ref> (1965)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Star-Spangled_Girl" title="The Star-Spangled Girl">The Star-Spangled Girl</ref> (1966)
<ref target="/wiki/Plaza_Suite" title="Plaza Suite">Plaza Suite</ref> (1968)
<ref target="/wiki/Last_of_the_Red_Hot_Lovers" title="Last of the Red Hot Lovers">Last of the Red Hot Lovers</ref> (1969)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Gingerbread_Lady" title="The Gingerbread Lady">The Gingerbread Lady</ref> (1970)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Prisoner_of_Second_Avenue" title="The Prisoner of Second Avenue">The Prisoner of Second Avenue</ref> (1971)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Sunshine_Boys" title="The Sunshine Boys">The Sunshine Boys</ref> (1972)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Good_Doctor_(play)" title="The Good Doctor (play)">The Good Doctor</ref> (1973)
<ref target="/wiki/God%27s_Favorite" title="God's Favorite">God's Favorite</ref> (1974)
<ref target="/wiki/California_Suite" title="California Suite">California Suite</ref> (1976)
<ref target="/wiki/Chapter_Two_(play)" title="Chapter Two (play)">Chapter Two</ref> (1977)
<ref target="/wiki/I_Ought_to_Be_in_Pictures" title="I Ought to Be in Pictures">I Ought to Be in Pictures</ref> (1980)
<ref target="/wiki/Fools_(play)" title="Fools (play)">Fools</ref> (1981)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Odd_Couple_(play)" title="The Odd Couple (play)">The Female Odd Couple</ref> (1981)
<ref target="/wiki/Brighton_Beach_Memoirs" title="Brighton Beach Memoirs">Brighton Beach Memoirs</ref> (1983)
<ref target="/wiki/Biloxi_Blues" title="Biloxi Blues">Biloxi Blues</ref> (1985)
<ref target="/wiki/Broadway_Bound" title="Broadway Bound">Broadway Bound</ref> (1986)
<ref target="/wiki/Rumors_(play)" title="Rumors (play)">Rumors</ref> (1988)
<ref target="/wiki/Lost_in_Yonkers" title="Lost in Yonkers">Lost in Yonkers</ref> (1991)
<ref class="mw-selflink selflink">Jake's Women</ref> (1992)
<ref target="/wiki/Laughter_on_the_23rd_Floor" title="Laughter on the 23rd Floor">Laughter on the 23rd Floor</ref> (1993)
<ref target="/wiki/London_Suite_(play)" title="London Suite (play)">London Suite</ref> (1995)
<ref target="/wiki/Proposals" title="Proposals">Proposals</ref> (1997)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Dinner_Party_(play)" title="The Dinner Party (play)">The Dinner Party</ref> (2000)
<ref target="/wiki/45_Seconds_from_Broadway" title="45 Seconds from Broadway">45 Seconds from Broadway</ref> (2001)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Odd_Couple_(play)" title="The Odd Couple (play)">Oscar and Felix: A New Look at the Odd Couple</ref> (2002)
<ref target="/wiki/Rose%27s_Dilemma" title="Rose's Dilemma">Rose's Dilemma</ref> (2003)
<p>Musicals</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Little_Me_(musical)" title="Little Me (musical)">Little Me</ref> (1962)
<ref target="/wiki/Sweet_Charity" title="Sweet Charity">Sweet Charity</ref> (1966)
<ref target="/wiki/Promises,_Promises_(musical)" title="Promises, Promises (musical)">Promises, Promises</ref> (1968)
<ref target="/wiki/They%27re_Playing_Our_Song" title="They're Playing Our Song">They're Playing Our Song</ref> (1979)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Goodbye_Girl_(musical)" title="The Goodbye Girl (musical)">The Goodbye Girl</ref> (1993)
<p>Films</p>
<ref target="/wiki/After_the_Fox" title="After the Fox">After the Fox</ref> (1966)
<ref target="/wiki/Barefoot_in_the_Park_(film)" title="Barefoot in the Park (film)">Barefoot in the Park</ref> (1967)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Odd_Couple_(film)" title="The Odd Couple (film)">The Odd Couple</ref> (1968)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Out-of-Towners_(1970_film)" title="The Out-of-Towners (1970 film)">The Out-of-Towners</ref> (1970)
<ref target="/wiki/Plaza_Suite_(film)" title="Plaza Suite (film)">Plaza Suite</ref> (1971)
<ref target="/wiki/Last_of_the_Red_Hot_Lovers_(film)" title="Last of the Red Hot Lovers (film)">Last of the Red Hot Lovers</ref> (1972)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Heartbreak_Kid_(1972_film)" title="The Heartbreak Kid (1972 film)">The Heartbreak Kid</ref> (1972)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Prisoner_of_Second_Avenue" title="The Prisoner of Second Avenue">The Prisoner of Second Avenue</ref> (1975)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Sunshine_Boys_(1975_film)" title="The Sunshine Boys (1975 film)">The Sunshine Boys</ref> (1975)
<ref target="/wiki/Murder_by_Death" title="Murder by Death">Murder by Death</ref> (1976)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Goodbye_Girl" title="The Goodbye Girl">The Goodbye Girl</ref> (1977)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Cheap_Detective" title="The Cheap Detective">The Cheap Detective</ref> (1978)
<ref target="/wiki/California_Suite_(film)" title="California Suite (film)">California Suite</ref> (1978)
<ref target="/wiki/Chapter_Two_(film)" title="Chapter Two (film)">Chapter Two</ref> (1979)
<ref target="/wiki/Seems_Like_Old_Times_(film)" title="Seems Like Old Times (film)">Seems Like Old Times</ref> (1980)
<ref target="/wiki/Only_When_I_Laugh_(film)" title="Only When I Laugh (film)">Only When I Laugh</ref> (1981)
<ref target="/wiki/Neil_Simon%27s_I_Ought_to_Be_in_Pictures" title="Neil Simon's I Ought to Be in Pictures">I Ought to Be in Pictures</ref> (1982)
<ref target="/wiki/Max_Dugan_Returns" title="Max Dugan Returns">Max Dugan Returns</ref> (1983)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Lonely_Guy" title="The Lonely Guy">The Lonely Guy</ref> (1984)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Slugger%27s_Wife" title="The Slugger's Wife">The Slugger's Wife</ref> (1985)
<ref target="/wiki/Brighton_Beach_Memoirs_(film)" title="Brighton Beach Memoirs (film)">Brighton Beach Memoirs</ref> (1986)
<ref target="/wiki/Biloxi_Blues_(film)" title="Biloxi Blues (film)">Biloxi Blues</ref> (1988)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Marrying_Man" title="The Marrying Man">The Marrying Man</ref> (1991)
<ref target="/wiki/Broadway_Bound_(film)" title="Broadway Bound (film)">Broadway Bound</ref> (1992)
<ref target="/wiki/Lost_in_Yonkers_(film)" title="Lost in Yonkers (film)">Lost in Yonkers</ref> (1993)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Sunshine_Boys_(1996_film)" title="The Sunshine Boys (1996 film)">The Sunshine Boys</ref> (1996)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Odd_Couple_II" title="The Odd Couple II">The Odd Couple II</ref> (1998)
<ref target="/wiki/Laughter_on_the_23rd_Floor_(film)" title="Laughter on the 23rd Floor (film)">Laughter on the 23rd Floor</ref> (2001)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Goodbye_Girl_(2004_film)" title="The Goodbye Girl (2004 film)">The Goodbye Girl</ref> (2004)





<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&oldid=911902844">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&oldid=911902844</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:1996_films" title="Category:1996 films">1996 films</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_by_Neil_Simon" title="Category:Plays by Neil Simon">Plays by Neil Simon</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_set_in_New_York_City" title="Category:Plays set in New York City">Plays set in New York City</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:1992_plays" title="Category:1992 plays">1992 plays</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:Wikipedia_articles_with_plot_summary_needing_attention_from_August_2019" title="Category:Wikipedia articles with plot summary needing attention from August 2019">Wikipedia articles with plot summary needing attention from August 2019</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:All_Wikipedia_articles_with_plot_summary_needing_attention" title="Category:All Wikipedia articles with plot summary needing attention">All Wikipedia articles with plot summary needing attention</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Commons_category_link_is_on_Wikidata" title="Category:Commons category link is on Wikidata">Commons category link is on Wikidata</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=Jake%27s+Women" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=Jake%27s+Women" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/Jake%27s_Women" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:Jake%27s_Women" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/Jake%27s_Women">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/Jake%27s_Women" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/Jake%27s_Women" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&oldid=911902844" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q6124524" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=Jake%27s_Women&id=911902844" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>In other projects</h3></p>


<ref target="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Jake%27s_Women" hreflang="en">Wikimedia Commons</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=Jake%27s+Women">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=Jake%27s+Women&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jake%27s_Women" hreflang="es" lang="es" title="Jake's Women – Spanish">Español</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://tr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Akl%C4%B1mdaki_Kad%C4%B1nlar" hreflang="tr" lang="tr" title="Aklımdaki Kadınlar – Turkish">Türkçe</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q6124524#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 21 August 2019, at 22:27 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Jake%27s_Women&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.164","walltime":"0.249","ppvisitednodes":{"value":791,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":24618,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":790,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":19,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":1,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":0,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":3929,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":1,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 204.791 1 -total"," 32.05% 65.644 1 Template:Infobox_play"," 29.74% 60.913 1 Template:Infobox"," 22.29% 45.655 1 Template:Commons_category"," 22.07% 45.204 1 Template:Long_plot"," 18.81% 38.516 1 Template:Ambox"," 8.38% 17.156 1 Template:IBDB_show"," 6.63% 13.568 1 Template:Reflist"," 6.44% 13.181 1 Template:Commons"," 5.34% 10.929 1 Template:Neil_Simon"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.049","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":2107178,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1329","timestamp":"20190925034834","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"Jake's Women","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Jake%27s_Women","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q6124524","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q6124524","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2005-05-20T16:52:08Z","dateModified":"2019-08-21T22:27:24Z","headline":"play by Neil Simon"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":88,"wgHostname":"mw1266"});});</p>


