



<p>Show Boat - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"Show_Boat","wgTitle":"Show Boat","wgCurRevisionId":916877743,"wgRevisionId":916877743,"wgArticleId":429885,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["Webarchive template wayback links","CS1 maint: archived copy as title","All articles with dead external links","Articles with dead external links from January 2011","Articles with dead external links from May 2018","Articles with permanently dead external links","Articles with short description","Good articles","Pages with timeline metadata","Articles needing additional references from June 2015","All articles needing additional references","Wikipedia articles with GND identifiers","Wikipedia articles with MusicBrainz release group identifiers","Wikipedia articles with MusicBrainz work identifiers","1927 musicals",</p>
<p>"Broadway musicals","Musicals by Jerome Kern","American musical films","Musicals based on novels","American films","Musicals by Oscar Hammerstein II","World's fairs in fiction"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"Show_Boat","wgRelevantArticleId":429885,"wgRequestId":"XYqObgpAADgAAJLcRjoAAABM","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":</p>
<p>"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q2166879","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","jquery.makeCollapsible.styles":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":</p>
<p>"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","jquery.makeCollapsible","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head","mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>


























<ref id="top"></ref>


<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Good_articles" title="This is a good article. Follow the link for more information."></ref>

<p>Show Boat</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<p>For other uses, see <ref class="mw-redirect mw-disambig" href="/wiki/Show_Boat_(disambiguation)" title="Show Boat (disambiguation)">Show Boat (disambiguation)</ref>.</p>
<p>1927 musical by Jerome Kern and Oscar Hammerstein II</p>


<p>Show Boat<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Show_Boat.jpg"></ref>Original 1927 sheet music for Ol' Man River, from Show BoatMusic<ref target="/wiki/Jerome_Kern" title="Jerome Kern">Jerome Kern</ref>Lyrics<ref target="/wiki/Oscar_Hammerstein_II" title="Oscar Hammerstein II">Oscar Hammerstein II</ref><ref target="/wiki/P._G._Wodehouse" title="P. G. Wodehouse">P. G. Wodehouse</ref>Book<ref target="/wiki/Oscar_Hammerstein_II" title="Oscar Hammerstein II">Oscar Hammerstein II</ref>Basis<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(novel)" title="Show Boat (novel)">Show Boat</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Edna_Ferber" title="Edna Ferber">Edna Ferber</ref>PremiereDecember 27, 1927: <ref target="/wiki/Ziegfeld_Theatre_(1927)" title="Ziegfeld Theatre (1927)">Ziegfeld Theatre</ref><ref target="/wiki/New_York_City" title="New York City">New York City</ref>Productions1927 <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> 1928 <ref target="/wiki/West_End_theatre" title="West End theatre">West End</ref> 1932 Broadway <ref target="/wiki/Revival_(theatre)" title="Revival (theatre)">revival</ref> 1946 Broadway revival1966 <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lincoln_Center" title="Lincoln Center">Lincoln Center</ref> revival1971 West End revival 1983 Broadway revival 1994 Broadway revival1998 West End revival 2016 West End revivalAwards<ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Revival_of_a_Musical" title="Tony Award for Best Revival of a Musical">Tony Award for Best Revival</ref><ref target="/wiki/Laurence_Olivier_Award_for_Best_Musical_Revival" title="Laurence Olivier Award for Best Musical Revival">Olivier Award for Best Revival</ref></p>
<p>Show Boat is a <ref target="/wiki/Musical_theatre" title="Musical theatre">musical</ref> in two acts, with music by <ref target="/wiki/Jerome_Kern" title="Jerome Kern">Jerome Kern</ref> and book and lyrics by <ref target="/wiki/Oscar_Hammerstein_II" title="Oscar Hammerstein II">Oscar Hammerstein II</ref>, based on <ref target="/wiki/Edna_Ferber" title="Edna Ferber">Edna Ferber</ref>'s best-selling <ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(novel)" title="Show Boat (novel)">novel of the same name</ref>. The musical follows the lives of the performers, stagehands and dock workers on the Cotton Blossom, a <ref target="/wiki/Mississippi_River" title="Mississippi River">Mississippi River</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Showboat" title="Showboat">show boat</ref>, over 40 years from 1887 to 1927. Its themes include racial prejudice and tragic, enduring love. The musical contributed such classic songs as "<ref target="/wiki/Ol%27_Man_River" title="Ol' Man River">Ol' Man River</ref>", "<ref target="/wiki/Make_Believe_(Jerome_Kern_song)" title="Make Believe (Jerome Kern song)">Make Believe</ref>", and "<ref target="/wiki/Can%27t_Help_Lovin%27_Dat_Man" title="Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man">Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man</ref>".</p>
<p>The musical was first produced in 1927 by <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Florenz_Ziegfeld" title="Florenz Ziegfeld">Florenz Ziegfeld</ref>. The premiere of Show Boat on <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> was an important event in the history of American musical theatre. It "was a radical departure in musical storytelling, marrying spectacle with seriousness", compared with the trivial and unrealistic <ref target="/wiki/Operetta" title="Operetta">operettas</ref>, light <ref target="/wiki/Edwardian_musical_comedy" title="Edwardian musical comedy">musical comedies</ref> and "Follies"-type musical <ref target="/wiki/Revue" title="Revue">revues</ref> that defined Broadway in the 1890s and early 20th century.<ref target="#cite_note-Lahr-1">[1]</ref> According to The Complete Book of Light Opera:</p>

<p>Here we come to a completely new genre – the musical play as distinguished from musical comedy. Now … the play was the thing, and everything else was subservient to that play. Now … came complete integration of song, humor and production numbers into a single and inextricable artistic entity.<ref target="#cite_note-history-2">[2]</ref></p>
<p>The quality of Show Boat was recognized immediately by critics, and it is frequently revived. Awards did not exist for Broadway shows in 1927, when the show premiered, or in 1932 when its first revival was staged. Late 20th-century revivals of Show Boat have won both the <ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Revival_of_a_Musical" title="Tony Award for Best Revival of a Musical">Tony Award for Best Revival of a Musical</ref> (1995) and the <ref target="/wiki/Laurence_Olivier_Award_for_Best_Musical_Revival" title="Laurence Olivier Award for Best Musical Revival">Laurence Olivier Award for Best Musical Revival</ref> (1991).<ref target="#cite_note-3">[3]</ref></p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Background">1 Background</ref>
<ref target="#Synopsis">2 Synopsis</ref>
<ref target="#Musical_numbers">3 Musical numbers</ref>

<ref target="#History_of_revisions">3.1 History of revisions</ref>


<ref target="#Principal_roles">4 Principal roles</ref>
<ref target="#Production_history">5 Production history</ref>

<ref target="#Original_1927_production">5.1 Original 1927 production</ref>
<ref target="#Paul_Robeson">5.2 Paul Robeson</ref>
<ref target="#American_revivals_and_1936_film">5.3 American revivals and 1936 film</ref>
<ref target="#London_productions">5.4 London productions</ref>


<ref target="#Adaptations">6 Adaptations</ref>

<ref target="#Film_and_television">6.1 Film and television</ref>
<ref target="#Radio">6.2 Radio</ref>
<ref target="#Concert_hall">6.3 Concert hall</ref>


<ref target="#Selected_recordings">7 Selected recordings</ref>
<ref target="#Racial_issues">8 Racial issues</ref>

<ref target="#Integration">8.1 Integration</ref>
<ref target="#Language_and_stereotypes">8.2 Language and stereotypes</ref>

<ref target='#The_word_"nigger"'>8.2.1 The word "nigger"</ref>
<ref target="#African-American_English">8.2.2 African-American English</ref>


<ref target="#Revisions_and_cancellations">8.3 Revisions and cancellations</ref>
<ref target="#1993_revival">8.4 1993 revival</ref>
<ref target="#Analysis">8.5 Analysis</ref>


<ref target="#Notes">9 Notes</ref>
<ref target="#References">10 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">11 External links</ref>


<h2>Background[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Background">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>In doing research for her proposed novel <ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(novel)" title="Show Boat (novel)">Show Boat</ref>, writer <ref target="/wiki/Edna_Ferber" title="Edna Ferber">Edna Ferber</ref> spent five days on the <ref target="/wiki/James_Adams_Floating_Theatre" title="James Adams Floating Theatre">James Adams Floating Palace Theatre</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/Bath,_North_Carolina" title="Bath, North Carolina">Bath, North Carolina</ref>, gathering material about a disappearing American entertainment venue, the river <ref target="/wiki/Showboat" title="Showboat">showboat</ref>. In a few weeks, she gained what she called a "treasure trove of show-boat material, human, touching, true". Ferber researched these American showboats for months prior to her stay on the Floating Palace Theatre. <ref target="/wiki/Jerome_Kern" title="Jerome Kern">Jerome Kern</ref> was impressed by the novel and, hoping to adapt it as a musical, asked the critic <ref target="/wiki/Alexander_Woollcott" title="Alexander Woollcott">Alexander Woollcott</ref> to introduce him to Ferber in October 1926. Woollcott introduced them that evening during the intermission of Kern's latest musical, <ref target="/wiki/Criss_Cross_(musical)" title="Criss Cross (musical)">Criss Cross</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-Block-4">[4]</ref></p>
<p>Ferber was at first shocked that anyone would want to adapt Show Boat as a musical. After being assured by Kern that he did not want to adapt it as the typical frivolous "girlie" show of the 1920s, she granted him and his collaborator <ref target="/wiki/Oscar_Hammerstein_II" title="Oscar Hammerstein II">Oscar Hammerstein II</ref> the rights to set her novel to music. After composing most of the first-act songs, Kern and Hammerstein auditioned their material for producer <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Florenz_Ziegfeld" title="Florenz Ziegfeld">Florenz Ziegfeld</ref>, thinking that he was the person to create the elaborate production they felt necessary for Ferber's sprawling work.<ref target="#cite_note-Kantor-5">[5]</ref> Ziegfeld was impressed with the show and agreed to produce it, writing the next day, "This is the best musical comedy I have ever been fortunate to get a hold of; I am thrilled to produce it, this show is the opportunity of my life..."<ref target="#cite_note-Kantor-5">[5]</ref>Show Boat, with its serious and dramatic nature, was considered an unusual choice for Ziegfeld, who was best known for <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Revues" title="Revues">revues</ref> such as the <ref target="/wiki/Ziegfeld_Follies" title="Ziegfeld Follies">Ziegfeld Follies</ref>.</p>
<p>Though Ziegfeld anticipated opening his <ref target="/wiki/Ziegfeld_Theatre_(1927)" title="Ziegfeld Theatre (1927)">new theatre</ref> on Sixth Avenue with Show Boat, the epic nature of the work required an unusually long gestation period and extensive changes during out-of-town tryouts. Impatient with Kern and Hammerstein and worried about the serious tone of the musical (he strongly disliked the songs Ol' Man River and Mis'ry's Comin' Around), Ziegfeld decided to open <ref target="/wiki/Ziegfeld_Theatre_(1927)" title="Ziegfeld Theatre (1927)">his theatre</ref> in February 1927 with <ref target="/wiki/Rio_Rita_(musical)" title="Rio Rita (musical)">Rio Rita</ref>, a musical by Kern's collaborator <ref target="/wiki/Guy_Bolton" title="Guy Bolton">Guy Bolton</ref>. When Rio Rita proved to be a success, Show Boat's <ref target="/wiki/Broadway_theatre" title="Broadway theatre">Broadway</ref> opening was delayed until Rita could be moved to another theatre.<ref target="#cite_note-Bloom-6">[6]</ref></p>

<h2>Synopsis[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Synopsis">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Note: Although the basic plot of Show Boat has always remained the same, over the years revisions and alterations were made by the creators, and over time by subsequent producers and directors. Some of these revisions were for length and some for convenience, as when a different actor played a certain role and was unable to perform a specialty piece written for the role's creator. Some have been made to reflect contemporary sensitivities toward race, gender and other social issues.</p>

<p>Act I</p>
<p>In 1887, the show boat Cotton Blossom arrives at the river dock in <ref target="/wiki/Natchez,_Mississippi" title="Natchez, Mississippi">Natchez, Mississippi</ref>. The <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Reconstruction_era_(United_States)" title="Reconstruction era (United States)">Reconstruction era</ref> had ended a decade earlier, and white-dominated Southern legislatures have imposed <ref target="/wiki/Racial_segregation" title="Racial segregation">racial segregation</ref> and <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Jim_Crow" title="Jim Crow">Jim Crow</ref> rules. The boat's owner, Cap'n Andy Hawks, introduces his actors to the crowd on the levee. A fistfight breaks out between Steve Baker, the leading man of the troupe, and Pete, a rough <ref target="/wiki/Engineer" title="Engineer">engineer</ref> who had been making passes at Steve's wife, the leading lady <ref target="/wiki/Julie_Dozier" title="Julie Dozier">Julie La Verne</ref>. Steve knocks Pete down, and Pete swears revenge, suggesting he knows a dark secret about Julie. Cap'n Andy pretends to the shocked crowd that the fight was a preview of one of the melodramas to be performed. The troupe exits with the showboat band, and the crowd follows.</p>
<p>A handsome riverboat gambler, <ref target="/wiki/Gaylord_Ravenal" title="Gaylord Ravenal">Gaylord Ravenal</ref>, appears on the levee and is taken with eighteen-year-old Magnolia ("Nolie") Hawks, an aspiring performer and the daughter of Cap'n Andy and his wife Parthenia Ann (Parthy). Magnolia is likewise smitten with Ravenal ("<ref target="/wiki/Make_Believe_(Jerome_Kern_song)" title="Make Believe (Jerome Kern song)">Make Believe</ref>"). She seeks advice from Joe, a black dock worker aboard the boat, who has returned from buying flour for his wife Queenie, the ship's cook. He replies that there are "lots like [Ravenal] on the river." As Magnolia goes inside the boat to tell her friend Julie about the handsome stranger, Joe mutters that she ought to ask the river for advice. He and the other dock workers reflect on the wisdom and indifference of "<ref target="/wiki/Ol%27_Man_River" title="Ol' Man River">Ol' Man River</ref>", who doesn't seem to care what the world's troubles are, but "jes' keeps rollin' along".</p>
<p>Magnolia finds Julie inside and announces that she's in love. Julie cautions her that this stranger could be just a "no-account river fellow". Magnolia says that if she found out he was "no-account", she'd stop loving him. Julie warns her that it's not that easy to stop loving someone, explaining that she'll always love Steve, singing a few lines of "<ref target="/wiki/Can%27t_Help_Lovin%27_Dat_Man" title="Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man">Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man</ref>". Queenie overhears – she is surprised that Julie knows that song as she has only heard "colored folks" sing it. Magnolia remarks that Julie sings it all the time, and when Queenie asks if she can sing the entire song, Julie obliges.</p>
<p>During the rehearsal for that evening, Julie and Steve learn that the town sheriff is coming to arrest them. Steve takes out a large pocket knife and makes a cut on the back of her hand, sucking the blood and swallowing it. Pete returns with the sheriff, who insists the show cannot proceed because Julie is a <ref target="/wiki/Mulatto" title="Mulatto">mulatto</ref> who has been <ref target="/wiki/Passing_(racial_identity)" title="Passing (racial identity)">passing</ref> as white and local law prohibits <ref target="/wiki/Miscegenation" title="Miscegenation">mixed marriages</ref>. Julie admits that her mother was black, but Steve tells the sheriff that he also has <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/One-drop_theory" title="One-drop theory">"black blood"</ref> in him, so their marriage is legal in Mississippi. The troupe backs him up, boosted by the ship's <ref target="/wiki/Maritime_pilot" title="Maritime pilot">pilot</ref> Windy McClain, a longtime friend of the sheriff. The couple have escaped the charge of miscegenation, but they still have to leave the show boat; identified as black, they can no longer perform for the segregated white audience. Cap'n Andy fires Pete, but in spite of his sympathy for Julie and Steve, he cannot violate the law for them.</p>
<p>Ravenal returns and asks for passage on the boat. Andy hires him as the new leading man and assigns his daughter Magnolia as the new leading lady, over her mother's objections. As Magnolia and Ravenal begin to rehearse their roles and in the process, kiss for the first time (infuriating Parthy), Joe reprises the last few lines of "Ol' Man River".</p>
<p>Weeks later, Magnolia and Ravenal have been a hit with the crowds and have fallen in love. As the levee workers hum "Ol' Man River" in the background, he proposes to Magnolia, and she accepts. The couple joyously sings "<ref target="/wiki/You_Are_Love" title="You Are Love">You Are Love</ref>". They make plans to marry the next day while Parthy, who disapproves, is out of town. Parthy has discovered that Ravenal once killed a man and arrives with the Sheriff to interrupt the wedding festivities. The group learns that Ravenal was acquitted of murder. Cap'n Andy calls Parthy "narrow-minded" and defends Ravenal by announcing that he also once killed a man. Parthy faints, but the ceremony proceeds.</p>

<p>Act II</p>
<p>Six years have passed, and it is 1893. Ravenal and Magnolia have moved to <ref target="/wiki/Chicago" title="Chicago">Chicago</ref>, where they make a precarious living from Ravenal's gambling. At first they are rich and enjoying the good life ("Why Do I Love You?") By 1903, they have a daughter, Kim, and after years of varying income, they are broke and rent a room in a boarding house. Depressed over his inability to support his family, Ravenal abandons Magnolia and Kim. Frank and Ellie, two former actors from the showboat, learn that Magnolia is living in the rooms they want to rent. The old friends seek a singing job for Magnolia at the Trocadero, the club where they are doing a New Year's show. Julie is working there. She has fallen into drinking after having been abandoned by Steve. At a rehearsal, she tries out the new song "<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Bill_(Show_Boat)" title="Bill (Show Boat)">Bill</ref>." She appears to be thinking of Steve and sings it with great emotion. From her dressing-room, she hears Magnolia singing "Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man" for her audition, the song which Julie taught her years ago. Julie secretly quits her job so that Magnolia can fill it, without learning of her sacrifice.</p>
<p>Ravenal visits his daughter Kim at the convent where she goes to school to say goodbye before leaving her forever ("Make Believe" (reprise)). On New Year's Eve, Andy and Parthy go to Chicago for a surprise visit to their daughter Magnolia. He goes to the Trocadero without his wife, and sees Magnolia overcome with emotion and nearly booed off stage. Andy rallies the crowd by starting a sing-along of the standard, "<ref target="/wiki/After_the_Ball_(song)" title="After the Ball (song)">After the Ball</ref>". Magnolia becomes a great musical star.</p>
<p>More than 20 years pass, and it is 1927. An aged Joe on the Cotton Blossom sings a reprise of "Ol' Man River". Cap'n Andy has a chance meeting with Ravenal and arranges his reunion with Magnolia. Andy knows that Magnolia is retiring and returning to the Cotton Blossom with Kim, who has become a Broadway star. Kim gives her admirers a taste of her performing abilities by singing an updated, <ref target="/wiki/Charleston_(dance)" title="Charleston (dance)">Charleston</ref> version of "Why Do I Love You?" Ravenal sings a reprise of "You Are Love" to the offstage Magnolia. Although he is uncertain about asking her to take him back, Magnolia, who has never stopped loving him, greets him warmly and does. As the happy couple walks up the boat's gangplank, Joe and the cast sing the last verse of "Ol' Man River".</p>

<p>Plot variants in 1951 film</p>
<p>The <ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1951_film)" title="Show Boat (1951 film)">1951 MGM film</ref> changed the final scenes of the story, as well as many small details. It reconciles Ravenal and Magnolia a few years after they separate, rather than 23. When Ravenal leaves Magnolia in Chicago, she is pregnant. By a chance meeting with Julie, Ravenal learns that Magnolia gave birth to his daughter. He returns to her and sees the child Kim playing. Magnolia sees them together and takes him back, and the family returns to the show boat. Joe and the chorus start singing "Ol' Man River" as the scenes unfold, then the paddlewheel starts turning in tempo with the music, as the ship heads down river. Julie is shown, viewing from a distance. She had watched the scene from the shadows.</p>

<h2>Musical numbers[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Musical numbers">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>The musical numbers in the original production were as follows:</p>




<p>Act 1</p>
<p>"Cotton Blossom" – Stevedores and Townspeople</p>
<p>"Where's the Mate for Me?" – Gaylord Ravenal</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Make_Believe_(Jerome_Kern_song)" title="Make Believe (Jerome Kern song)">Make Believe</ref>" – Gaylord and Magnolia</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Ol%27_Man_River" title="Ol' Man River">Ol' Man River</ref>" – Joe and Stevedores</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Can%27t_Help_Lovin%27_Dat_Man" title="Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man">Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man</ref>" – Julie, Queenie, Joe, Magnolia and Ensemble</p>
<p>"Life Upon the Wicked Stage" – Ellie and Townswomen</p>
<p>"Till Good Luck Comes My Way" – Gaylord, Pete, Frank, and Townsmen</p>
<p>"Ol' Man River" (reprise) – Joe</p>
<p>"I Might Fall Back on You" – Ellie, Frank and Girls</p>
<p>"C'mon Folks (Queenie's Ballyhoo)" – Queenie, Stevedores, and Gals</p>
<p>"Olio Dance" – (instrumental)</p>
<p>"You Are Love" – Gaylord and Magnolia</p>
<p>Act I "Finale (Wedding Scene)" – Magnolia, Ravenal, Cap'n Andy, and Chorus</p>




<p>Act 2</p>
<p>"At the Fair" – Sightseers, Barkers, and Dandies</p>
<p>"Dandies on Parade" – City Folk</p>
<p>"Why Do I Love You?" – Magnolia, Ravenal, Cap'n Andy, Parthy Ann Hawks, and Company</p>
<p>"In Dahomey" – <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Jubilee_Singers" title="Jubilee Singers">Jubilee Singers</ref> and Dahomey Dancers</p>
<p>"<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Bill_(Show_Boat)" title="Bill (Show Boat)">Bill</ref>" (lyrics by <ref target="/wiki/P._G._Wodehouse" title="P. G. Wodehouse">P. G. Wodehouse</ref> and revised by Hammerstein) – Julie</p>
<p>"Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man" (reprise) – Magnolia</p>
<p>"Nuns' Processional" – Nuns</p>
<p>"Make Believe" (reprise) – Ravenal</p>
<p>"Goodbye, My Lady Love" (music and lyrics by <ref target="/wiki/Joseph_E._Howard" title="Joseph E. Howard">Joseph E. Howard</ref>) – Frank and Ellie</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/After_the_Ball_(song)" title="After the Ball (song)">After the Ball</ref>" (from <ref target="/wiki/A_Trip_to_Chinatown" title="A Trip to Chinatown">A Trip to Chinatown</ref>; music and lyrics by <ref target="/wiki/Charles_K._Harris" title="Charles K. Harris">Charles K. Harris</ref>) – Magnolia and Ensemble</p>
<p>"Ol' Man River" (reprise) – Joe</p>
<p>"Hey, Feller" – Jubilee Singers and Queenie</p>
<p>"You Are Love" (reprise) – Gaylord</p>
<p>"Why Do I Love You?" (reprise) – Kim and Flappers</p>
<p>"Finale Ultimo (Ol' Man River)" – Joe and Chorus</p>



<h3>History of revisions[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: History of revisions">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The original production ran four-and-a-half hours during tryouts but was trimmed to just over three by the time it got to Broadway. During previews, two songs, "<ref target="/wiki/Mis%27ry%27s_Comin%27_Aroun" title="Mis'ry's Comin' Aroun">Mis'ry's Comin' Aroun</ref>" and "Let's Start the New Year", were cut from the show. "Mis'ry's Comin' Aroun" was published in the complete vocal score<ref target="#cite_note-Block2-7">[7]</ref> and fragments of it are also heard in the scoring, notably in the original 1927 overture and in the miscegenation scene. The song "Be Happy, Too" was also cut after the Washington, D.C., tryout<ref target="#cite_note-8">[8]</ref> The 1988 studio cast album reinstated the entire song, and it was also included in the 1994 <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Hal_Prince" title="Hal Prince">Hal Prince</ref> revival. "Let's Start the New Year" was performed in the 1989 <ref target="/wiki/Paper_Mill_Playhouse" title="Paper Mill Playhouse">Paper Mill Playhouse</ref> production.</p>
<p>Two songs, "Till Good Luck Comes My Way" (sung by Ravenal) and "Hey Feller!" (sung by Queenie), were written mainly to cover scenery changes. They were discarded beginning with the 1946 revival, although "Till Good Luck" was included in the 1993 <ref target="/wiki/Harold_Prince" title="Harold Prince">Harold Prince</ref> revival of the show. The comedy song, "I Might Fall Back On You," was also cut beginning in 1946. It was restored in the 1951 film version and several stage productions since the 1980s. On record, "Hey Feller!" appears only on the 1988 <ref target="/wiki/EMI" title="EMI">EMI</ref> album. Kern and Hammerstein wrote two new songs for revivals and three more for the 1936 film version.</p>
<p>The <ref target="/wiki/Harold_Fielding" title="Harold Fielding">Harold Fielding</ref> production in London in the early 1970s claimed to use the entire original score, but it omitted "Hey, Feller!" and "In Dahomey", among others. This cast album broke ground in being the first two-LP version of Show Boat ever released.</p>
<p>The score also includes four songs not originally written for Show Boat: "<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Bill_(Show_Boat)" title="Bill (Show Boat)">Bill</ref>" was originally written by Kern and <ref target="/wiki/P._G._Wodehouse" title="P. G. Wodehouse">P. G. Wodehouse</ref> in 1917 and was reworked by Hammerstein for Show Boat. Two other songs not by Kern and Hammerstein, "Goodbye, My Lady Love" by <ref target="/wiki/Joseph_E._Howard" title="Joseph E. Howard">Joseph E. Howard</ref> and "<ref target="/wiki/After_the_Ball_(song)" title="After the Ball (song)">After the Ball</ref>" by <ref target="/wiki/Charles_K._Harris" title="Charles K. Harris">Charles K. Harris</ref>, were included by the authors for historical atmosphere and are included in revivals.<ref target="#cite_note-9">[9]</ref> The New Year's Eve scene features an instrumental version of "<ref target="/wiki/There%27ll_Be_a_Hot_Time_in_the_Old_Town_Tonight" title="There'll Be a Hot Time in the Old Town Tonight">There'll Be a Hot Time in the Old Town Tonight</ref>".</p>
<p>Some of the following numbers have been cut or revised in subsequent productions, as noted below (the songs "Ol' Man River", "Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man", and "<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Bill_(Show_Boat)" title="Bill (Show Boat)">Bill</ref>" have been included in every stage and film production of Show Boat):</p>

<p>Overture – The original overture, used in all stage productions up to 1946 (and heard on the three-disc EMI/Angel CD for the first time in nearly 50 years), is based chiefly on the deleted song "<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Mis%27ry%27s_Comin%27_Round" title="Mis'ry's Comin' Round">Mis'ry's Comin' Round</ref>", as Kern wanted to save this song in some form. The song was restored in the Harold Prince 1994 revival of the show. The overture also contains fragments of "Ol' Man River", "Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man", and a faster arrangement of "Why Do I Love You?" The overtures for the 1946 revival and the 1966 Lincoln Center revival consist of medleys of songs from the show. All three overtures were arranged by the show's orchestrator, <ref target="/wiki/Robert_Russell_Bennett" title="Robert Russell Bennett">Robert Russell Bennett</ref>, who orchestrated most of Kern's later shows.</p>
<p>"Cotton Blossom" – This number is performed in all the stage productions, and shorter versions were used in the 1936 and 1951 film versions.<ref target="#cite_note-10">[10]</ref> It was not used in the 1929 film version.</p>
<p>"Where's the Mate for Me?" – Ravenal's first song; heard in all stage versions, partially sung in the 1936 film version, and sung complete in the 1951 film version. Not sung in the 1929 film version.</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Make_Believe_(Jerome_Kern_song)" title="Make Believe (Jerome Kern song)">Make Believe</ref>" – Performed in all stage versions, and in the 1936 and 1951 film versions, but not the 1929 film version.</p>
<p>"Life Upon the Wicked Stage" – This comic song is usually included in stage versions but is heard in the 1936 film only in the orchestral score. Not included in the 1929 film, it is sung and danced in the 1951 film version.</p>
<p>"Till Good Luck Comes My Way" – Kern and Hammerstein cut it from the 1946 revival, but it was reinstated in the 1971 London stage revival. It is performed instrumentally in the 1936 film and is omitted altogether in the 1929 and 1951 films.</p>
<p>"I Might Fall Back on You" – This was usually cut after 1946, but it has been reinstated in revivals beginning in 1966. It was absent from the 1929 and 1936 films but included in the 1951 film.</p>
<p>"C'mon Folks (Queenie's Ballyhoo)" – Always included in the show, it was sung in the prologue to the 1929 film version,<ref target="#cite_note-first_film-11">[11]</ref> It was omitted from the 1936 film and performed instrumentally in the 1951 film.</p>
<p>"Olio Dance" – This is rarely performed now, since it was composed simply to cover a change of scenery. It is an orchestral piece that partially uses the melody of "I Might Fall Back on You" and can be heard on the EMI 3-CD album (as "Villain Dance"). The 1936 film substituted the new Kern-Hammerstein number "Gallivantin' Around", performed as an <ref target="/wiki/Olio_(musical_number)" title="Olio (musical number)">olio</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Irene_Dunne" title="Irene Dunne">Irene Dunne</ref> (as Magnolia) in blackface. It was omitted from the 1989 PBS <ref target="/wiki/Paper_Mill_Playhouse" title="Paper Mill Playhouse">Paper Mill Playhouse</ref> production. Some modern productions move the song "I Might Fall Back on You" to this spot.</p>
<p>"You Are Love" – Kern considered this popular waltz to be the score's weakest song: he tried unsuccessfully to eliminate it from the 1936 film version. It has never been cut from any stage production. It was shortened, and the introductory section was omitted, in both the 1936 and the 1951 films. It was not performed in the 1929 film.</p>
<p>"Act I Finale" – This was shortened in the 1936 film and omitted from the 1929 and 1951 films. Its midsection, banjo-dominant, buck-and-wing dance theme became a repeating motif in the 1951 film, played onstage during the backstage miscegenation scene, and later as a soft-shoe dance for Cap'n Andy and granddaughter Kim.</p>
<p>"At the Chicago World's Fair" – Used in all stage productions except for the Harold Prince 1994 revival, it was omitted from all the film versions, but an instrumental version was performed in the 1936 film.</p>
<p>"Why Do I Love You?" – Used in all stage versions, this number was sung during the exit music to the 1929 film;<ref target="#cite_note-first_film-11">[11]</ref> it was performed only as background music for the 1936 film and was sung in the 1951 film version. In the 1994 Hal Prince revival, it was sung by Parthy.</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/In_Dahomey#Song_from_Show_Boat" title="In Dahomey">In Dahomey</ref>" – This was cut from the score after the 1946 Broadway production and has not been revived as it is viewed as racially offensive as well as unnecessary to the plot. It is sung at the <ref target="/wiki/World%27s_Columbian_Exposition" title="World's Columbian Exposition">Chicago World's Fair</ref> by a group of supposedly African natives. They chant in a supposed African language before breaking into modern English, singing about how glad they are to return to their apartments after the day's performance. It was not used in any film version of the show but was included in the complete 1988 EMI recording and in a 1993 studio recording on the Jay label of the 1946 score.</p>
<p>"Goodbye, My Lady Love" – This is used only in American productions. It is included in the 1936 film, but not in the 1929 or 1951 films.</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/After_the_Ball_(song)" title="After the Ball (song)">After the Ball</ref>" – Performed in all stage productions and in both the 1936 and 1951 films, but not the 1929 one.</p>
<p>"Hey, Feller" – Used in nearly all stage productions up until 1946, and sung in the prologue to the 1929 film.<ref target="#cite_note-first_film-11">[11]</ref> Not used in the 1936 film, but used as background score in the 1951 film during the opening post-credits scene as the show boat arrives.</p>
<p>Additional numbers have been included in films and revivals as follows:</p>

<p>"<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Mis%27ry%27s_Comin%27_Round" title="Mis'ry's Comin' Round">Mis'ry's Comin' Round</ref>" – Though this was cut from the original production, Kern ensured that it was published in the complete vocal score.<ref target="#cite_note-Block-4">[4]</ref> The 1988 album reinstated it, and it was also included in the 1994 Hal Prince revival.</p>
<p>"Let's Start the New Year" – Cut from the original production but performed in the 1989 Paper Mill Playhouse production.</p>
<p>"I Have The Room Above Her" is a romantic duet written by Kern and Hammerstein for Ravenal and Magnolia in the 1936 film. It was included in the 1994 Broadway revival.</p>
<p>"Gallivantin' Around" is a cakewalk-style number written by Kern and Hammerstein for Magnolia for the 1936 film.</p>
<p>"Ah Still Suits Me" is a comic duet written by Kern and Hammerstein for the 1936 film and sung by the characters Joe and Queenie (Paul Robeson and <ref target="/wiki/Hattie_McDaniel" title="Hattie McDaniel">Hattie McDaniel</ref>). The number was also included in the 1989 Paper Mill Playhouse production.<ref target="#cite_note-Klein-12">[12]</ref></p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Nobody_Else_But_Me" title="Nobody Else But Me">Nobody Else But Me</ref>" was written by Kern and Hammerstein for the 1946 Broadway revival, to be sung in the spot where Kim usually sings a reprise of "Why Do I Love You". This was the last song written by Kern; he died shortly before the 1946 production opened.<ref target="#cite_note-13">[13]</ref> In the 1971 London stage revival, the song was sung by Julie, in a new scene written especially for that production. It is not sung in any film version of the show but was frequently heard in stage revivals up until about the 1980s.</p>
<p>"Dandies on Parade" is a dance number arranged for the 1994 Broadway production by David Krane, largely from Kern's music.</p>
<h2>Principal roles[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: Principal roles">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Cap'n Andy Hawks, the owner and captain of the Cotton Blossom show boat. He is the husband of Parthy Ann, and the father of Magnolia.</p>
<p>Magnolia Hawks, the daughter of Parthy and Cap'n Andy. She marries Gaylord Ravenal and becomes the mother of Kim.</p>
<p>Gaylord Ravenal, a handsome river boat gambler. Later, the husband of Magnolia and father of Kim.</p>
<p>Julie La Verne, the leading lady of the troupe and the wife of Steve.</p>
<p>Steve Baker, the leading man of the Cotton Blossom and protective husband of Julie.</p>
<p>Parthy Ann Hawks, the stern wife of Cap'n Andy.</p>
<p>Pete, the tough engineer of the Cotton Blossom who tries to flirt with Julie.</p>
<p>Joe, a dock worker on the boat, and the husband of Queenie.</p>
<p>Queenie, the ship's cook and the wife of Joe.</p>
<p>Frank Schultz, a performer on the boat who often plays the villain characters. He is married to Ellie.</p>
<p>Ellie, a singer and dancer in an act with her husband Frank.</p>
<p>Kim, the daughter of Magnolia and Gaylord.</p>
<p>Windy McClain, the pilot of the Cotton Blossom.</p>
<h2>Production history[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: Production history">edit</ref>]</h2>
<h3>Original 1927 production[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: Original 1927 production">edit</ref>]</h3>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Show-Boat-1928.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:Show-Boat-1928.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref>Scene from the original Broadway production
<p>Ziegfeld <ref target="/wiki/Preview_(theatre)" title="Preview (theatre)">previewed</ref> the show in a pre-Broadway tour from November 15 to December 19, 1927. The locations included the <ref target="/wiki/National_Theatre_(Washington,_D.C.)" title="National Theatre (Washington, D.C.)">National Theatre</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/Washington,_D.C." title="Washington, D.C.">Washington, D.C.</ref>, the <ref target="/wiki/Regional_Enterprise_Tower#Nixon_Theater" title="Regional Enterprise Tower">Nixon Theatre</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/Pittsburgh" title="Pittsburgh">Pittsburgh</ref>, the <ref target="/wiki/Ohio_Theatre_(Cleveland,_Ohio)" title="Ohio Theatre (Cleveland, Ohio)">Ohio Theatre</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/Cleveland" title="Cleveland">Cleveland</ref>, and the <ref target="/wiki/Erlanger_Theatre" title="Erlanger Theatre">Erlanger Theatre</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/Philadelphia" title="Philadelphia">Philadelphia</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-Vancheri-14">[14]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-Kreuger-15">[15]</ref> The show opened on Broadway at the <ref target="/wiki/Ziegfeld_Theatre_(1927)" title="Ziegfeld Theatre (1927)">Ziegfeld Theatre</ref> on December 27, 1927. The critics were immediately enthusiastic, and the show was a great popular success, running a year and a half, for a total of 572 performances.</p>
<p>The production was staged by Oscar Hammerstein II.<ref target="#cite_note-16">[16]</ref> Choreography for the show was by Sammy Lee. The original cast included <ref target="/wiki/Norma_Terris" title="Norma Terris">Norma Terris</ref> as Magnolia Hawks and her daughter Kim (as an adult), <ref target="/wiki/Howard_Marsh" title="Howard Marsh">Howard Marsh</ref> as Gaylord Ravenal, <ref target="/wiki/Helen_Morgan" title="Helen Morgan">Helen Morgan</ref> as Julie LaVerne, <ref target="/wiki/Jules_Bledsoe" title="Jules Bledsoe">Jules Bledsoe</ref> as Joe, <ref target="/wiki/Charles_Winninger" title="Charles Winninger">Charles Winninger</ref> as Cap'n Andy Hawks, <ref target="/wiki/Edna_May_Oliver" title="Edna May Oliver">Edna May Oliver</ref> as Parthy Ann Hawks, <ref target="/wiki/Sammy_White_(actor)" title="Sammy White (actor)">Sammy White</ref> as Frank Schultz, <ref target="/wiki/Eva_Puck" title="Eva Puck">Eva Puck</ref> as Ellie May Chipley, and <ref target="/wiki/Tess_Gardella" title="Tess Gardella">Tess Gardella</ref> as Queenie. The orchestrator was <ref target="/wiki/Robert_Russell_Bennett" title="Robert Russell Bennett">Robert Russell Bennett</ref>, and the conductor was <ref target="/wiki/Victor_Baravalle" title="Victor Baravalle">Victor Baravalle</ref>. The <ref target="/wiki/Scenic_design" title="Scenic design">scenic design</ref> for the original production was by <ref target="/wiki/Joseph_Urban" title="Joseph Urban">Joseph Urban</ref>, who had worked with Ziegfeld for many years in his <ref target="/wiki/Ziegfeld_Follies" title="Ziegfeld Follies">Follies</ref> and had designed the elaborate new Ziegfeld Theatre itself. Costumes were designed by John Harkrider.<ref target="#cite_note-17">[17]</ref></p>
<p>In his opening night review for the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/New_York_Times" title="New York Times">New York Times</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Brooks_Atkinson" title="Brooks Atkinson">Brooks Atkinson</ref> called the book's adaptation "intelligently made", and the production one of "unimpeachable skill and taste". He termed Terris "a revelation"; Winninger "extraordinarily persuasive and convincing"; and Bledsoe's singing "remarkably effective".<ref target="#cite_note-18">[18]</ref></p>

<h3>Paul Robeson[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=8" title="Edit section: Paul Robeson">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The character Joe, the <ref target="/wiki/Stevedore" title="Stevedore">stevedore</ref> who sings "Ol' Man River", was expanded from the novel and written specifically by Kern and Hammerstein for <ref target="/wiki/Paul_Robeson" title="Paul Robeson">Paul Robeson</ref>, already a noted actor and singer. Although he is the actor most identified with the role and the song, he was unavailable for the original production due to its opening delay. Jules Bledsoe premiered the part. Robeson played Joe in four notable productions of Show Boat: the 1928 London premier production, the 1932 Broadway revival, the 1936 film version and a 1940 stage revival in <ref target="/wiki/Los_Angeles" title="Los Angeles">Los Angeles</ref>.</p>
<p>Reviewing the 1932 Broadway revival, the critic <ref target="/wiki/Brooks_Atkinson" title="Brooks Atkinson">Brooks Atkinson</ref> described Robeson's performance: "Mr. Robeson has a touch of genius. It is not merely his voice, which is one of the richest organs on the stage. It is his understanding that gives 'Old Man River' an epic lift. When he sings...you realize that Jerome Kern's spiritual has reached its final expression."<ref target="#cite_note-19">[19]</ref></p>

<h3>American revivals and 1936 film[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=9" title="Edit section: American revivals and 1936 film">edit</ref>]</h3>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Show_Boat_(1936_Film)_Opening_Title.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:Show_Boat_(1936_Film)_Opening_Title.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref>Opening title from the 1936 film version. After closing at the Ziegfeld Theatre in 1929, the original production toured extensively. The national company is notable for including <ref target="/wiki/Irene_Dunne" title="Irene Dunne">Irene Dunne</ref> as Magnolia. <ref target="/wiki/Hattie_McDaniel" title="Hattie McDaniel">Hattie McDaniel</ref> played Queenie in a 1933 West Coast production, joined by tenor <ref target="/wiki/Allan_Jones_(actor)" title="Allan Jones (actor)">Allan Jones</ref> as Ravenal.<ref target="#cite_note-20">[20]</ref>
<p>Dunne was soon offered a contract by <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/RKO_Studios" title="RKO Studios">RKO Studios</ref> and appeared in the 1936 <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Universal_Studios" title="Universal Studios">Universal Studios</ref> film adaptation of Show Boat, as did Jones as Ravenal, McDaniel as Queenie and Robeson as Joe. The film also featured Winninger (Cap'n Andy), Morgan (Julie), White (Frank), and Francis X. Mahoney (Rubberface) recreating their original Broadway stage roles.<ref target="#cite_note-21">[21]</ref></p>
<p>Show Boat was <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Revival_(play)" title="Revival (play)">revived</ref> by Ziegfeld on Broadway in 1932 at the <ref target="/wiki/Earl_Carroll_Theatre" title="Earl Carroll Theatre">Casino Theatre</ref> with most of the original cast, but with Paul Robeson as Joe<ref target="#cite_note-22">[22]</ref> and <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Dennis_King_(actor)" title="Dennis King (actor)">Dennis King</ref> as Ravenal.</p>
<p>In 1946, a major new Broadway revival was produced by Jerome Kern and Oscar Hammerstein II at the show's original home, the Ziegfeld Theatre. The 1946 revival featured a revised score and new song by Kern and Hammerstein, and a new overture and orchestrations by Robert Russell Bennett. The show was directed by Hammerstein and <ref target="/wiki/Hassard_Short" title="Hassard Short">Hassard Short</ref> and featured <ref target="/wiki/Jan_Clayton" title="Jan Clayton">Jan Clayton</ref> (Magnolia), Charles Fredricks (Ravenal), <ref target="/wiki/Carol_Bruce" title="Carol Bruce">Carol Bruce</ref> (Julie), <ref target="/wiki/Kenneth_Lee_Spencer" title="Kenneth Lee Spencer">Kenneth Spencer</ref> (Joe), <ref target="/wiki/Helen_Dowdy" title="Helen Dowdy">Helen Dowdy</ref> (Queenie), and <ref target="/wiki/Buddy_Ebsen" title="Buddy Ebsen">Buddy Ebsen</ref> (Frank). The successful production ran for 418 performances and then toured extensively. Kern, however, died just weeks before the January 5, 1946 opening, making it the last show he worked on.</p>
<p>Additional New York revivals were produced in 1948 and 1954 at the <ref target="/wiki/New_York_City_Center" title="New York City Center">New York City Center</ref>. The <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Music_Theater_of_Lincoln_Center&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Music Theater of Lincoln Center (page does not exist)">Music Theater of Lincoln Center</ref> company produced Show Boat in 1966 at the <ref target="/wiki/David_H._Koch_Theater" title="David H. Koch Theater">New York State Theater</ref> in a new production. It starred <ref target="/wiki/Barbara_Cook" title="Barbara Cook">Barbara Cook</ref> (Magnolia), <ref target="/wiki/Constance_Towers" title="Constance Towers">Constance Towers</ref> (Julie), <ref target="/wiki/Stephen_Douglass" title="Stephen Douglass">Stephen Douglass</ref> (Ravenal), <ref target="/wiki/David_Wayne" title="David Wayne">David Wayne</ref> (Cap'n Andy), <ref target="/wiki/Margaret_Hamilton_(actress)" title="Margaret Hamilton (actress)">Margaret Hamilton</ref> (Parthy) and <ref target="/wiki/William_Warfield" title="William Warfield">William Warfield</ref> (Joe). It was produced by <ref target="/wiki/Richard_Rodgers" title="Richard Rodgers">Richard Rodgers</ref>, and Robert Russell Bennett once again provided a new overture and revised orchestrations.</p>
<p>1983 brought a production at the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Kennedy_Center" title="Kennedy Center">Kennedy Center</ref>, Washington, D.C., that starred <ref target="/wiki/Mickey_Rooney" title="Mickey Rooney">Mickey Rooney</ref> as Cap'n Andy, and another at the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/George_Gershwin_Theatre" title="George Gershwin Theatre">Uris Theatre</ref> in New York. The latter revival was presented by <ref target="/wiki/Douglas_Urbanski" title="Douglas Urbanski">Douglas Urbanski</ref> and starred <ref target="/wiki/Donald_O%27Connor" title="Donald O'Connor">Donald O'Connor</ref> as Cap'n Andy.<ref target="#cite_note-23">[23]</ref></p>
<p>In 1989 the <ref target="/wiki/Paper_Mill_Playhouse" title="Paper Mill Playhouse">Paper Mill Playhouse</ref> of <ref target="/wiki/Millburn,_New_Jersey" title="Millburn, New Jersey">Millburn, New Jersey</ref>, mounted a production which was noted for its intention to restore the show in accordance with the creators' original intentions. The production restored part of the original 1927 overture and one number discarded from the show after the Broadway opening, as well as the song Ah Still Suits Me, written by Kern and Hammerstein for the 1936 film version. It was directed by Robert Johanson and starred <ref target="/wiki/Eddie_Bracken" title="Eddie Bracken">Eddie Bracken</ref> as Cap'n Andy. The Paper Mill production was preserved on videotape and broadcast on <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Public_Broadcasting_Service" title="Public Broadcasting Service">PBS</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-Klein-12">[12]</ref></p>
<p>Livent Inc. presented the most recent major production of Show Boat on Broadway in 1994. Produced and directed by <ref target="/wiki/Harold_Prince" title="Harold Prince">Harold Prince</ref>, it premiered in <ref target="/wiki/Toronto" title="Toronto">Toronto</ref>, Ontario, in 1993 prior to opening in New York on October 2, 1994, at the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/George_Gershwin_Theatre" title="George Gershwin Theatre">George Gershwin Theatre</ref>. It ran for 947 performances, Broadway's longest-running Show Boat to date.<ref target="#cite_note-24">[24]</ref> This production went on tour, playing at the Kennedy Center; and it was also staged in London and Melbourne, Australia. Prince's production revived interest in the show by tightening the book, dropping and adding songs cut in various productions, and highlighting its racial elements. Perhaps the most notable change in the score was Prince's transforming "Why Do I Love You?" from a duet between Magnolia and Ravenal to a lullaby sung by Parthy Ann to Magnolia's baby girl. The change was partly to accommodate the song's being performed by stage actress <ref target="/wiki/Elaine_Stritch" title="Elaine Stritch">Elaine Stritch</ref>. The love duet for Magnolia and Ravenal, "I Have the Room Above Her", originally written by Kern and Hammerstein for the 1936 film, was added to the production. Two new mime and dance "Montages" in Act 2 depicted the passage of time through changing styles of dance and music.<ref target="#cite_note-25">[25]</ref></p>

<h3>London productions[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=10" title="Edit section: London productions">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The original London <ref target="/wiki/West_End_theatre" title="West End theatre">West End</ref> production of Show Boat opened May 3, 1928, at the <ref target="/wiki/Theatre_Royal,_Drury_Lane" title="Theatre Royal, Drury Lane">Theatre Royal, Drury Lane</ref> and featured among the cast, <ref target="/wiki/Cedric_Hardwicke" title="Cedric Hardwicke">Cedric Hardwicke</ref> as Capt. Andy, <ref target="/wiki/Edith_Day" title="Edith Day">Edith Day</ref> as Magnolia, Paul Robeson as Joe, and <ref target="/wiki/Alberta_Hunter" title="Alberta Hunter">Alberta Hunter</ref> as Queenie.<ref target="#cite_note-26">[26]</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Mabel_Mercer" title="Mabel Mercer">Mabel Mercer</ref>, later famed as a cabaret singer, was in the chorus. Other West End presentations include a 1971 production at the <ref target="/wiki/Adelphi_Theatre" title="Adelphi Theatre">Adelphi Theatre</ref>, which ran for 909 performances.<ref target="#cite_note-Kreuger-15">[15]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-27">[27]</ref></p>
<p>The Hal Prince production ran at the <ref target="/wiki/Prince_Edward_Theatre" title="Prince Edward Theatre">Prince Edward Theatre</ref> in 1998,<ref target="#cite_note-28">[28]</ref> and was nominated for the Olivier Award, Outstanding Musical Production (1999).<ref target="#cite_note-29">[29]</ref> Other notable revivals in England have included the joint <ref target="/wiki/Opera_North" title="Opera North">Opera North</ref>/<ref target="/wiki/Royal_Shakespeare_Company" title="Royal Shakespeare Company">Royal Shakespeare Company</ref> production of 1989,<ref target="#cite_note-Vancheri-14">[14]</ref> which ran at the <ref target="/wiki/London_Palladium" title="London Palladium">London Palladium</ref> in 1990, and the 2006 production directed by <ref target="/wiki/Francesca_Zambello" title="Francesca Zambello">Francesca Zambello</ref>, presented by <ref target="/wiki/Raymond_Gubbay" title="Raymond Gubbay">Raymond Gubbay</ref> at London's <ref target="/wiki/Royal_Albert_Hall" title="Royal Albert Hall">Royal Albert Hall</ref>. It was the first fully staged musical production in the history of that venue.<ref target="#cite_note-30">[30]</ref></p>
<p>A production was transferred from <ref target="/wiki/Sheffield" title="Sheffield">Sheffield</ref>'s <ref target="/wiki/Crucible_Theatre" title="Crucible Theatre">Crucible Theatre</ref> to London's <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/New_London_Theatre" title="New London Theatre">New London Theatre</ref> with previews beginning on April 9, 2016, and an official opening on April 25, 2016. It was directed by <ref target="/wiki/Daniel_Evans_(actor)" title="Daniel Evans (actor)">Daniel Evans</ref> using the <ref target="/wiki/Goodspeed_Musicals" title="Goodspeed Musicals">Goodspeed Musicals</ref> version of the show. The cast included <ref target="/wiki/Gina_Beck" title="Gina Beck">Gina Beck</ref> as Magnolia, <ref target="/wiki/Lucy_Briers" title="Lucy Briers">Lucy Briers</ref> as Parthy Ann and <ref target="/wiki/Malcolm_Sinclair_(actor)" title="Malcolm Sinclair (actor)">Malcolm Sinclair</ref> as Cap'n Andy.<ref target="#cite_note-31">[31]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-32">[32]</ref> Despite very favorable reviews, the show closed at the end of August 2016.<ref target="#cite_note-33">[33]</ref></p>

<h2>Adaptations[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=11" title="Edit section: Adaptations">edit</ref>]</h2>
<h3>Film and television[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=12" title="Edit section: Film and television">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Show Boat has been adapted for film three times, and for television once.</p>

<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Show_boat.jpeg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:Show_boat.jpeg" title="Enlarge"></ref>French poster from the 1951 MGM film version of "Show Boat"
<p>1929 <ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1929_film)" title="Show Boat (1929 film)">Show Boat</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/Universal_Pictures" title="Universal Pictures">Universal</ref>. Released in silent and partial sound versions. Not a film version of the musical; its plot is based on the original Edna Ferber novel. Immediately after the silent film was completed, a prologue with some music from the show was filmed and added to a part-talkie version of the same film, which was released with two sound sequences.</p>
<p>1936 <ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1936_film)" title="Show Boat (1936 film)">Show Boat</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/Universal_Pictures" title="Universal Pictures">Universal</ref>. Directed by <ref target="/wiki/James_Whale" title="James Whale">James Whale</ref>. A mostly faithful film version of the show, featuring four members of the original Broadway cast. Screenplay by Oscar Hammerstein II; music arrangements by Robert Russell Bennett; music direction and conducting by Victor Baraville.</p>
<p>1946 <ref target="/wiki/Till_the_Clouds_Roll_By" title="Till the Clouds Roll By">Till the Clouds Roll By</ref>. <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/MGM" title="MGM">MGM</ref>. In this fictionalized film biography of composer Jerome Kern (played by <ref target="/wiki/Robert_Walker_(actor,_born_1918)" title="Robert Walker (actor, born 1918)">Robert Walker</ref>), Show Boat's 1927 opening night on Broadway is depicted in a lavishly staged fifteen-minute medley of six of the show's songs. The number features <ref target="/wiki/Kathryn_Grayson" title="Kathryn Grayson">Kathryn Grayson</ref>, <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Tony_Martin_(entertainer)" title="Tony Martin (entertainer)">Tony Martin</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Lena_Horne" title="Lena Horne">Lena Horne</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Virginia_O%27Brien" title="Virginia O'Brien">Virginia O'Brien</ref>, Caleb Peterson, and William Halligan as, respectively, Magnolia, Ravenal, Julie, Ellie, Joe, and Cap'n Andy.</p>
<p>1951 <ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1951_film)" title="Show Boat (1951 film)">Show Boat</ref>. <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/MGM" title="MGM">MGM</ref>. Somewhat revised Technicolor film version. Follows the basic storyline and contains many songs from the show but makes many changes in the details of plot and character. The most financially successful and frequently revived of the three film versions.</p>
<p>1989 A live performance by the <ref target="/wiki/Paper_Mill_Playhouse" title="Paper Mill Playhouse">Paper Mill Playhouse</ref> was videotaped for television and shown on <ref target="/wiki/Great_Performances" title="Great Performances">Great Performances</ref> on <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Public_Broadcasting_Service" title="Public Broadcasting Service">PBS</ref>. It contains more of the songs (and fewer cuts) than any of the film versions. It includes the choral number "Let's Start the New Year", which was dropped from the show before its Broadway opening, and "Ah Still Suits Me", a song written by Kern and Hammerstein for the 1936 film version of the show.<ref target="#cite_note-Klein-12">[12]</ref></p>
<h3>Radio[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=13" title="Edit section: Radio">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Show Boat was adapted for <ref target="/wiki/Live_radio" title="Live radio">live radio</ref> at least seven times. Due to network censorship rules, many of the radio productions eliminated the miscegenation aspect of the plot. Notable exceptions were the 1940 Cavalcade of America broadcast<ref target="#cite_note-34">[34]</ref> and the 1952 <ref target="/wiki/Lux_Radio_Theatre" title="Lux Radio Theatre">Lux Radio Theatre</ref> broadcast.</p>

<ref target="/wiki/The_Campbell_Playhouse_(radio_series)" title="The Campbell Playhouse (radio series)">The Campbell Playhouse</ref> (<ref target="/wiki/CBS_Radio" title="CBS Radio">CBS Radio</ref>, March 31, 1939). Directed and introduced by <ref target="/wiki/Orson_Welles" title="Orson Welles">Orson Welles</ref>. This was a non-musical version of the story that was based more closely on Edna Ferber's novel than on the musical. From the original stage cast <ref target="/wiki/Helen_Morgan" title="Helen Morgan">Helen Morgan</ref> repeated her portrayal of Julie, here singing one song not from the musical. Welles portrayed Cap'n Andy, <ref target="/wiki/Margaret_Sullavan" title="Margaret Sullavan">Margaret Sullavan</ref> was Magnolia, and author Edna Ferber made her acting debut as Parthy. This version made Julie into an illegal alien who must be deported.
<ref target="/wiki/Cavalcade_of_America" title="Cavalcade of America">Cavalcade of America</ref> (<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/NBC_Radio" title="NBC Radio">NBC Radio</ref>, May 28, 1940). A half-hour dramatization with Jeanette Nolan, John McIntire, <ref target="/wiki/Agnes_Moorehead" title="Agnes Moorehead">Agnes Moorehead</ref> and the Ken Christy Chorus. Although brief, it was remarkably faithful to the original show.
<ref target="/wiki/Lux_Radio_Theatre" title="Lux Radio Theatre">Lux Radio Theatre</ref> (CBS, June 1940). Introduced and produced by <ref target="/wiki/Cecil_B._DeMille" title="Cecil B. DeMille">Cecil B. DeMille</ref>, it featured <ref target="/wiki/Irene_Dunne" title="Irene Dunne">Irene Dunne</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Allan_Jones_(actor)" title="Allan Jones (actor)">Allan Jones</ref>, and <ref target="/wiki/Charles_Winninger" title="Charles Winninger">Charles Winninger</ref>, all of whom were in the 1936 film version. In this condensed version some songs from the show were sung, but Julie was played by a non-singing Gloria Holden. This version made the biracial Julie a single woman. Only a few lines of Ol' Man River were heard, sung by a chorus. While supposedly based on the 1936 film, this production used the ending of the original show, which the film did not use.
<ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Radio_Hall_of_Fame_(radio_program)&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Radio Hall of Fame (radio program) (page does not exist)">Radio Hall of Fame</ref> (1944). This production featured Kathryn Grayson, playing Magnolia for the first time.<ref target="#cite_note-Kreuger-15">[15]</ref> Also in the cast were Allan Jones as Ravenal, <ref target="/wiki/Helen_Forrest" title="Helen Forrest">Helen Forrest</ref> as Julie, Charles Winninger as Cap'n Andy, Ernest Whitman as Joe, and <ref target="/wiki/Elvia_Allman" title="Elvia Allman">Elvia Allman</ref> as Parthy.
<ref target="/wiki/The_Railroad_Hour" title="The Railroad Hour">The Railroad Hour</ref> (<ref target="/wiki/ABC_News_Radio" title="ABC News Radio">ABC Radio</ref>, 1950). Condensed to a half-hour, this version featured singers <ref target="/wiki/Dorothy_Kirsten" title="Dorothy Kirsten">Dorothy Kirsten</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Gordon_MacRae" title="Gordon MacRae">Gordon MacRae</ref>, and Lucille Norman. "Ol' Man River" was sung by MacRae instead of by an African-American singer. Explanation of Julie and Steve's departure went completely unmentioned in this version.
<ref target="/wiki/Lux_Radio_Theatre" title="Lux Radio Theatre">Lux Radio Theatre</ref> (CBS, February 1952). A radio version of the 1951 <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/MGM" title="MGM">MGM</ref> film featuring <ref target="/wiki/Kathryn_Grayson" title="Kathryn Grayson">Kathryn Grayson</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Ava_Gardner" title="Ava Gardner">Ava Gardner</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Howard_Keel" title="Howard Keel">Howard Keel</ref>, and <ref target="/wiki/William_Warfield" title="William Warfield">William Warfield</ref> from the film's cast. <ref target="/wiki/Jay_C._Flippen" title="Jay C. Flippen">Jay C. Flippen</ref> portrayed Cap'n Andy. This version was extremely faithful to the 1951 film adaptation.<ref target="#cite_note-35">[35]</ref>
<p>In 2011, a two-part version was broadcast on <ref target="/wiki/BBC_Radio_4" title="BBC Radio 4">BBC Radio 4</ref> in the Classic Serial spot. Solely based on the novel by <ref target="/wiki/Edna_Ferber" title="Edna Ferber">Edna Ferber</ref>, it was dramatized by Moya O'Shea, and was produced and directed by Tracey Neale. It starred <ref target="/wiki/Samantha_Spiro" title="Samantha Spiro">Samantha Spiro</ref> as Magnolia, Ryan McCluskey as Ravenal, <ref target="/wiki/Nonso_Anozie" title="Nonso Anozie">Nonso Anozie</ref> as Joe, <ref target="/wiki/Tracy_Ifeachor" title="Tracy Ifeachor">Tracy Ifeachor</ref> as Queenie, Laurel Lefkow as Parthy, Morgan Deare as Cap'n Andy and <ref target="/wiki/Lysette_Anthony" title="Lysette Anthony">Lysette Anthony</ref> as Kim. Original music was by <ref target="/wiki/Neil_Brand" title="Neil Brand">Neil Brand</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-36">[36]</ref></p>
<p>On June 16, 2012, a revival of the musical by <ref target="/wiki/Lyric_Opera_of_Chicago" title="Lyric Opera of Chicago">Lyric Opera of Chicago</ref> was broadcast by <ref target="/wiki/WFMT" title="WFMT">WFMT</ref>-Radio of Chicago.<ref target="#cite_note-37">[37]</ref> This production of Show Boat reinstated the songs Mis'ry's Comin' Round, Till Good Luck Comes My Way and Hey, Feller!. It marked the first time a virtually complete version of Show Boat had ever been broadcast on radio.</p>
<h3>Concert hall[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=14" title="Edit section: Concert hall">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>In 1941, the <ref target="/wiki/Cleveland_Orchestra" title="Cleveland Orchestra">Cleveland Orchestra</ref>, under the direction of <ref target="/wiki/Artur_Rodzi%C5%84ski" title="Artur Rodziński">Artur Rodziński</ref>, premiered the orchestral work Show Boat: A Scenario for Orchestra , a 22-minute orchestral work weaving together many themes from the show. Rodziński and the orchestra recorded it that same year<ref target="#cite_note-38">[38]</ref> and there have been several modern recordings of the work since, notably one by <ref target="/wiki/John_Mauceri" title="John Mauceri">John Mauceri</ref> and the <ref target="/wiki/Hollywood_Bowl_Orchestra" title="Hollywood Bowl Orchestra">Hollywood Bowl Orchestra</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-39">[39]</ref></p>
<h2>Selected recordings[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=15" title="Edit section: Selected recordings">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Question_book-new.svg"></ref>This section needs additional citations for <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Verifiability" title="Wikipedia:Verifiability">verification</ref>. Please help <ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit">improve this article</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Help:Introduction_to_referencing_with_Wiki_Markup/1" title="Help:Introduction to referencing with Wiki Markup/1">adding citations to reliable sources</ref>. Unsourced material may be challenged and removed.Find sources: <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?as_eq=wikipedia&q=%22Show+Boat%22" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat"</ref> – <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?tbm=nws&q=%22Show+Boat%22+-wikipedia" rel="nofollow">news</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?&q=%22Show+Boat%22+site:news.google.com/newspapers&source=newspapers" rel="nofollow">newspapers</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?tbs=bks:1&q=%22Show+Boat%22+-wikipedia" rel="nofollow">books</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="//scholar.google.com/scholar?q=%22Show+Boat%22" rel="nofollow">scholar</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="https://www.jstor.org/action/doBasicSearch?Query=%22Show+Boat%22&acc=on&wc=on" rel="nofollow">JSTOR</ref> (June 2015) (<ref target="/wiki/Help:Maintenance_template_removal" title="Help:Maintenance template removal">Learn how and when to remove this template message</ref>)
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:TillCloudsRollBy01.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:TillCloudsRollBy01.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref><ref target="/wiki/Lena_Horne" title="Lena Horne">Lena Horne</ref> as Julie LaVerne in a scene from Show Boat in <ref target="/wiki/Till_the_Clouds_Roll_By" title="Till the Clouds Roll By">Till the Clouds Roll By</ref> (1946)
<p>1928 – original <ref target="/wiki/London" title="London">London</ref> cast album, with the show's original orchestrations. This was released in England on 78 rpm records years before being sold in the United States. Because the U.S. had not yet begun making <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Original_cast_album" title="Original cast album">original cast albums</ref> of Broadway shows, the 1927 Broadway cast as a whole was never recorded performing the songs, although Jules Bledsoe, Helen Morgan, and Tess Gardella did record individual numbers from it. The cast on the 1928 London album included <ref target="/wiki/Edith_Day" title="Edith Day">Edith Day</ref>, Howett Worster, Marie Burke and <ref target="/wiki/Alberta_Hunter" title="Alberta Hunter">Alberta Hunter</ref>. Due to contractual restrictions, cast member <ref target="/wiki/Paul_Robeson" title="Paul Robeson">Paul Robeson</ref> was replaced on the album as Joe by his understudy, baritone Norris Smith. But that same year, Robeson, with the same chorus that accompanied him in the show, did record "Ol' Man River" in its original orchestration. That recording was later released separately. His rendition appears on the <ref target="/wiki/EMI" title="EMI">EMI</ref> <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/CD" title="CD">CD</ref> "Paul Robeson Sings 'Ol' Man River' and Other Favorites".</p>
<p>1932 – <ref target="/wiki/Studio_recording" title="Studio recording">studio cast recording</ref> on 78rpm by <ref target="/wiki/Brunswick_Records" title="Brunswick Records">Brunswick Records</ref>. Later re-released by <ref target="/wiki/Columbia_Records" title="Columbia Records">Columbia Records</ref> on 78rpm, 33-1/3rpm and briefly on CD. This recording featured Helen Morgan, Paul Robeson, <ref target="/wiki/James_Melton" title="James Melton">James Melton</ref>, Frank Munn, and Countess Olga Albani, and was issued in conjunction with the 1932 revival of the show, although it was not strictly an "original cast" album of that revival. The orchestra was conducted by <ref target="/wiki/Victor_Young" title="Victor Young">Victor Young</ref>, and the original orchestrations and vocal arrangements were not used.</p>
<p>1946 – Broadway revival cast recording. Issued on 78rpm, LP and CD. The 78-RPM and LP versions were issued by Columbia, the CD by <ref target="/wiki/Sony" title="Sony">Sony</ref>. This was the first American recording of Show Boat which used the cast, conductor, and orchestrations of a major Broadway revival of the show. (Robert Russell Bennett's orchestrations for this revival thoroughly modified his original 1927 orchestrations.) <ref target="/wiki/Jan_Clayton" title="Jan Clayton">Jan Clayton</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Carol_Bruce" title="Carol Bruce">Carol Bruce</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Charles_Fredericks" title="Charles Fredericks">Charles Fredericks</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Kenneth_Lee_Spencer" title="Kenneth Lee Spencer">Kenneth Spencer</ref>, and Colette Lyons were featured. <ref target="/wiki/Buddy_Ebsen" title="Buddy Ebsen">Buddy Ebsen</ref> also appeared in the revival, but not on the album. Includes the new song "Nobody Else But Me".</p>
<p>1951 – <ref target="/wiki/MGM_Records" title="MGM Records">MGM Records</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Soundtrack_album" title="Soundtrack album">soundtrack album</ref>, with cast members of the <ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1951_film)" title="Show Boat (1951 film)">1951 film version</ref>. The first film soundtrack of Show Boat to be issued on records. Appeared both on 45rpm and 33-1/3rpm, later on CD in a much expanded edition. Actress <ref target="/wiki/Ava_Gardner" title="Ava Gardner">Ava Gardner</ref>, whose singing voice was replaced by Annette Warren's in the film, is heard singing on this album. The expanded version on CD contains both Warren's and Gardner's vocal tracks. This marked the recording debut of William Warfield, who played Joe and sang "Ol' Man River" in the film. Orchestrations were by <ref target="/wiki/Conrad_Salinger" title="Conrad Salinger">Conrad Salinger</ref>, <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Robert_Franklyn&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Robert Franklyn (page does not exist)">Robert Franklyn</ref>, and <ref target="/wiki/Alexander_Courage" title="Alexander Courage">Alexander Courage</ref>.</p>
<p>1956 – <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/RCA_Victor" title="RCA Victor">RCA Victor</ref> studio cast album conducted by <ref target="/wiki/Lehman_Engel" title="Lehman Engel">Lehman Engel</ref>. This album featured more of the score on one LP than had been previously recorded. It featured a white singer, famed American <ref target="/wiki/Baritone" title="Baritone">baritone</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Robert_Merrill" title="Robert Merrill">Robert Merrill</ref>, as both Joe and Gaylord Ravenal. Other singers included <ref target="/wiki/Patrice_Munsel" title="Patrice Munsel">Patrice Munsel</ref> as Magnolia and <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Rise_Stevens" title="Rise Stevens">Rise Stevens</ref> as Julie. Issued on CD in 2009, but omitting Frank and Ellie's numbers, which had been sung on the LP version by <ref target="/wiki/Janet_Pavek" title="Janet Pavek">Janet Pavek</ref> and <ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Kevin_Scott_(singer-actor)&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Kevin Scott (singer-actor) (page does not exist)">Kevin Scott</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-40">[40]</ref> The original orchestrations were not used.</p>
<p>1958 – RCA Victor studio cast album. The first Show Boat in stereo, this recording starred Howard Keel (singing "Ol' Man River" as well as Gaylord Ravenal's songs), <ref target="/wiki/Anne_Jeffreys" title="Anne Jeffreys">Anne Jeffreys</ref>, and <ref target="/wiki/Gogi_Grant" title="Gogi Grant">Gogi Grant</ref>, and did not use the original orchestrations. It was issued on CD in 2010.<ref target="#cite_note-41">[41]</ref></p>
<p>1959 – EMI British <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1959_Studio_cast_album)" title="Show Boat (1959 Studio cast album)">studio cast album</ref>. It featured Marlys Walters as Magnolia, Don McKay as Ravenal, <ref target="/wiki/Shirley_Bassey" title="Shirley Bassey">Shirley Bassey</ref> as Julie, <ref target="/wiki/Dora_Bryan" title="Dora Bryan">Dora Bryan</ref> as Ellie, and <ref target="/wiki/Inia_Te_Wiata" title="Inia Te Wiata">Inia Te Wiata</ref> singing "Ol' Man River".</p>
<p>1962 – Columbia studio cast album. Starring <ref target="/wiki/Barbara_Cook" title="Barbara Cook">Barbara Cook</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/John_Raitt" title="John Raitt">John Raitt</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Anita_Darian" title="Anita Darian">Anita Darian</ref>, and William Warfield, this was the first "Show Boat" recording issued on CD. Although Robert Russell Bennett was uncredited, this used several of his orchestrations for the 1946 revival of the show, together with some modifications.</p>
<p>1966 – Lincoln Center cast album. Issued by RCA Victor, it featured Cook, <ref target="/wiki/Constance_Towers" title="Constance Towers">Constance Towers</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Stephen_Douglass" title="Stephen Douglass">Stephen Douglass</ref>, and William Warfield. Robert Russell Bennett's orchestrations were modified even further. Also available on CD.</p>
<p>1971 – London revival cast album. Jazz singer <ref target="/wiki/Cleo_Laine" title="Cleo Laine">Cleo Laine</ref>, soprano Lorna Dallas, tenor Andre Jobin, and bass-baritone <ref target="/wiki/Thomas_Carey_(baritone)" title="Thomas Carey (baritone)">Thomas Carey</ref> were the leads. It used completely new orchestrations bearing almost no resemblance to Robert Russell Bennett's. This was the first 2-LP album of Show Boat. It included more of the score than had been previously put on records. Issued later on CD.</p>
<p>1988 – EMI studio cast album. This is a three-CD set which, for the first time, contained the entire score of the show, with the authentic 1927 orchestrations, uncensored lyrics, and vocal arrangements. The cast includes <ref target="/wiki/Frederica_von_Stade" title="Frederica von Stade">Frederica von Stade</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Jerry_Hadley" title="Jerry Hadley">Jerry Hadley</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Teresa_Stratas" title="Teresa Stratas">Teresa Stratas</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Karla_Burns" title="Karla Burns">Karla Burns</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Bruce_Hubbard" title="Bruce Hubbard">Bruce Hubbard</ref>, and <ref target="/wiki/Paige_O%27Hara" title="Paige O'Hara">Paige O'Hara</ref>. The album is conducted by <ref target="/wiki/John_McGlinn" title="John McGlinn">John McGlinn</ref>.</p>
<p>1993 – Toronto revival cast recording, starring <ref target="/wiki/Rebecca_Luker" title="Rebecca Luker">Rebecca Luker</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Mark_Jacoby" title="Mark Jacoby">Mark Jacoby</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Lonette_McKee" title="Lonette McKee">Lonette McKee</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Robert_Morse" title="Robert Morse">Robert Morse</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Elaine_Stritch" title="Elaine Stritch">Elaine Stritch</ref> and Michel Bell (as Joe).</p>
<p>There have been many other studio cast recordings of Show Boat in addition to those mentioned above. The soundtrack of the 1936 film version has appeared on a so-called "bootleg" CD label called Xeno.<ref target="#cite_note-42">[42]</ref></p>

<h2>Racial issues[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=16" title="Edit section: Racial issues">edit</ref>]</h2>
<h3>Integration[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=17" title="Edit section: Integration">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Show Boat boldly portrayed racial issues and was the first <ref target="/wiki/Racial_integration" title="Racial integration">racially integrated</ref> musical, in that both black and white performers appeared and sang on stage together.<ref target="#cite_note-Disclaimer-43">[43]</ref> <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Florenz_Ziegfeld" title="Florenz Ziegfeld">Ziegfeld's</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Ziegfeld_Follies" title="Ziegfeld Follies">Follies</ref> featured solo <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/African_American" title="African American">African American</ref> performers such as <ref target="/wiki/Bert_Williams" title="Bert Williams">Bert Williams</ref>, but would not have included a black woman in the chorus. Show Boat was structured with two choruses – a black chorus and a white chorus. One commentator noted that "Hammerstein uses the African-American chorus as essentially a <ref target="/wiki/Greek_chorus" title="Greek chorus">Greek chorus</ref>, providing clear commentary on the proceedings, whereas the white choruses sing of the not-quite-real."<ref target="#cite_note-Blogger-44">[44]</ref> In Show Boat Jerome Kern used the <ref target="/wiki/Thirty-two-bar_form" title="Thirty-two-bar form">AABA-chorus form</ref> exclusively in songs sung by African American characters (Ole Man River, Can't Help Lovin' dat Man), a form that later would be regarded as typical of 'white' popular music.<ref target="#cite_note-45">[45]</ref></p>
<p>Show Boat was the first Broadway musical to seriously depict an <ref target="/wiki/Interracial_marriage" title="Interracial marriage">interracial marriage</ref>, as in Ferber's original novel, and to feature a character of <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Mixed_race" title="Mixed race">mixed race</ref> who was "<ref target="/wiki/Passing_(racial_identity)" title="Passing (racial identity)">passing</ref>" for white. (Although the musical comedy <ref target="/wiki/Whoopee!" title="Whoopee!">Whoopee!</ref> (1930), starring <ref target="/wiki/Eddie_Cantor" title="Eddie Cantor">Eddie Cantor</ref>, supposedly depicted a romance between a mixed-blood <ref target="/wiki/Native_Americans_in_the_United_States" title="Native Americans in the United States">Native American</ref> man and a white woman, the man turns out to be white.<ref target="#cite_note-46">[46]</ref>)</p>

<h3>Language and stereotypes[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=18" title="Edit section: Language and stereotypes">edit</ref>]</h3>
<h4>The word "nigger"[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=19" title='Edit section: The word "nigger"'>edit</ref>]</h4>
<p>The show has generated controversy for the subject matter of interracial marriage, the historical portrayal of blacks working as laborers and servants in the 19th-century South, and the use of the word <ref target="/wiki/Nigger" title="Nigger">niggers</ref> in the lyrics (this is the first word in the opening chorus of the show). Originally the show opened with the black chorus onstage singing:</p>

<p>Niggers all work on the Mississippi,</p>
<p>Niggers all work while the white folks play.</p>
<p>Loadin' up boats wid de bales of cotton,</p>
<p>Gittin' no rest till de Judgement Day.<ref target="#cite_note-47">[47]</ref></p>
<p>In subsequent productions, "niggers" has been changed to "colored folk", to "darkies", and in one choice, "Here we all", as in "Here we all work on the Mississippi. Here we all work while the white folks play." In the 1966 <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lincoln_Center" title="Lincoln Center">Lincoln Center</ref> production of the show, produced two years after the <ref target="/wiki/Civil_Rights_Act_of_1964" title="Civil Rights Act of 1964">Civil Rights Act of 1964</ref> was passed, this section of the opening chorus was omitted rather than having words changed. The 1971 London revival used "Here we all work on the Mississippi". The 1988 CD for EMI restored the original 1927 lyric, while the <ref target="/wiki/Harold_Prince" title="Harold Prince">Harold Prince</ref> revival chose "colored folk".<ref target="#cite_note-48">[48]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-49">[49]</ref><ref target="#cite_note-50">[50]</ref></p>
<p>The Paper Mill Playhouse production, videotaped and telecast by PBS in 1989, used the word "nigger" when said by an unsympathetic character, but otherwise used the word "Negro".</p>
<p>Many critics believe that Kern and Hammerstein wrote the opening chorus to give a sympathetic voice to an oppressed people, and that they intended its use in an ironic way, as it had so often been used in a derogatory way. They wanted to alert the audience to the realities of <ref target="/wiki/Racism" title="Racism">racism</ref>:</p>

<p>'Show Boat begins with the singing of that most reprehensible word – nigger – yet this is no <ref target="/wiki/Coon_song" title="Coon song">coon song</ref>... [it] immediately establishes race as one of the central themes of the play. This is a <ref target="/wiki/Protest_song" title="Protest song">protest song</ref>, more ironic than angry perhaps, but a protest nonetheless. In the singers' hands, the word nigger has a sardonic tone... in the very opening, Hammerstein has established the gulf between the races, the privilege accorded the white folks and denied the black, and a flavor of the contempt built into the very language that whites used about African Americans. This is a very effective scene.... These are not <ref target="/wiki/Caricature" title="Caricature">caricature</ref> roles; they are wise, if uneducated, people capable of seeing and feeling more than some of the white folk around them.<ref target="#cite_note-Blogger-44">[44]</ref></p>
<p>The racial situations in the play provoke thoughts of how hard it must have been to be black in the South. In the dialogue, some of the blacks are called "niggers" by the white characters in the story. (Contrary to what is sometimes thought, black <ref target="/wiki/Slavery" title="Slavery">slavery</ref> is not depicted in the play; U.S. slavery was abolished by 1865, and the story runs from the 1880s to the late 1920s.) At first, it is shocking to believe they are allowed to use a word that negative at all in a play... But in the context in which it is used, it is appropriate due to the impact it makes. It reinforces how much of a derogatory term "nigger" was then and still is today.<ref target="#cite_note-Rosetta-51">[51]</ref></p>
<p>The word has not been used in any of the film versions of the musical. In the show, the Sheriff refers to Steve and Julie as having "nigger blood." In the 1936 and 1951 film versions, this was changed to "Negro blood". Likewise, the unsympathetic Pete calls Queenie a "nigger" in the stage version but refers to her as "colored" in the 1936 film, and does not use either word in the 1951 film.</p>

<h4>African-American English[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=20" title="Edit section: African-American English">edit</ref>]</h4>
<p>Those who consider Show Boat racially insensitive often note that the dialogue and lyrics of the black characters (especially the <ref target="/wiki/Stevedore" title="Stevedore">stevedore</ref> Joe and his wife Queenie) and choruses use various forms of <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/African_American_Vernacular_English" title="African American Vernacular English">African American Vernacular English</ref>. An example of this is shown in the following text:</p>

<p>Hey!</p>
<p>Where yo' think you're goin'?</p>
<p>Don't yo' know dis show is startin' soon?</p>
<p>Hey!</p>
<p>Jes' a few seats left yere!</p>
<p>It's light inside an' outside dere's no moon</p>
<p>What fo' you gals dressed up dicty?</p>
<p>Where's yo' all gwine?</p>
<p>Tell dose stingy men o' yourn</p>
<p>To step up here in line!<ref target="#cite_note-52">[52]</ref></p>
<p>Whether or not such language is an accurate reflection of the vernacular of blacks in Mississippi at the time, the effect of its usage has offended some critics, who see it as perpetuating racial stereotypes.<ref target="#cite_note-Showing_Grit-53">[53]</ref> The character Queenie (who sings the above verses) in the original production was played not by an African American but by the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Italian-American" title="Italian-American">Italian-American</ref> actress <ref target="/wiki/Tess_Gardella" title="Tess Gardella">Tess Gardella</ref> in <ref target="/wiki/Blackface" title="Blackface">blackface</ref> (Gardella was perhaps best known for portraying <ref target="/wiki/Aunt_Jemima" title="Aunt Jemima">Aunt Jemima</ref> in blackface).<ref target="#cite_note-AION-54">[54]</ref> Attempts by non-black writers to imitate black language stereotypically in songs like "<ref target="/wiki/Ol%27_Man_River" title="Ol' Man River">Ol' Man River</ref>" was alleged to be offensive, a claim that was repeated eight years later by critics of <ref target="/wiki/Porgy_and_Bess" title="Porgy and Bess">Porgy and Bess</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-55">[55]</ref> But such critics sometimes acknowledged that Hammerstein's intentions were noble, since "'Ol' Man River' was the song in which he first found his lyrical voice, compressing the suffering, resignation, and anger of an entire race into 24 taut lines and doing it so naturally that it's no wonder folks assume the song's a Negro spiritual."<ref target="#cite_note-Show_Boat_to_Sondheim-56">[56]</ref></p>
<p>The theatre critics and veterans <ref target="/wiki/Richard_Eyre" title="Richard Eyre">Richard Eyre</ref> and Nicholas Wright believe that Show Boat was revolutionary, not only because it was a radical departure from the previous style of plotless <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Revues" title="Revues">revues</ref>, but because it was a show written by non-blacks that portrayed blacks sympathetically rather than condescendingly:</p>

<p>Instead of a line of chorus girls showing their legs in the opening number singing that they were happy, happy, happy, the curtain rose on black dock-hands lifting bales of cotton and singing about the hardness of their lives. Here was a musical that showed poverty, suffering, bitterness, racial prejudice, a sexual relationship between black and white, a love story which ended unhappily – and of course show business. In "Ol' Man River" the black race was given an <ref target="/wiki/Anthem" title="Anthem">anthem</ref> to honor its misery that had the authority of an authentic spiritual.<ref target="#cite_note-Changing_Stages-57">[57]</ref></p>
<h3>Revisions and cancellations[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=21" title="Edit section: Revisions and cancellations">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Since the musical's 1927 premiere, Show Boat has both been condemned as a prejudiced show based on racial caricatures and championed as a breakthrough work that opened the door for public discourse in the arts about racism in America. Some productions (including one planned for June 2002 in <ref target="/wiki/Connecticut" title="Connecticut">Connecticut</ref>) have been cancelled because of objections.<ref target="#cite_note-FOX-58">[58]</ref></p>
<p>Such cancellations have been criticized by supporters of <ref target="/wiki/Performing_arts" title="Performing arts">the arts</ref>. After planned performances by an amateur <ref target="/wiki/Opera" title="Opera">opera</ref> company in <ref target="/wiki/Middlesbrough" title="Middlesbrough">Middlesbrough</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/England" title="England">England</ref> were "stopped because [they] would be 'distasteful' to ethnic minorities", a local newspaper declared that the actions were "surely taking political correctness too far".<ref target="#cite_note-Lathan-59">[59]</ref> A British theatre writer was concerned that "the kind of censorship we've been talking about – for censorship it is – actually militates against a truly integrated society, for it emphasizes differences. It puts a wall around groups within society, dividing people by creating metaphorical ghettos, and prevents mutual understanding".<ref target="#cite_note-Lathan-59">[59]</ref> Specifically, the cancellation was based on protests of plans to have all the black roles to be played in this production by white actors in blackface, as the company had no black members.<ref target="#cite_note-60">[60]</ref></p>
<p>As attitudes toward race relations have changed, producers and directors have altered some content to make the musical more <ref target="/wiki/Political_correctness" title="Political correctness">"politically correct"</ref>: "Show Boat, more than many musicals, was subject to cuts and revisions within a handful of years after its first performance, all of which altered the dramatic balance of the play."<ref target="#cite_note-Blogger-44">[44]</ref></p>

<h3>1993 revival[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=22" title="Edit section: 1993 revival">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The 1993 Hal Prince revival, originating in Toronto, was deliberately staged to cast attention on racial disparities; throughout the production, African-American actors constantly cleaned up messes, appeared to move the sets (even when <ref target="/wiki/Hydraulics" title="Hydraulics">hydraulics</ref> actually moved them), and performed other menial tasks.<ref target="#cite_note-Princereview-61">[61]</ref> After a New Year's Eve ball, all the streamers fell on the floor and African Americans immediately began sweeping them away. A montage in the second act showed time passing using the revolving door of the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Palmer_House" title="Palmer House">Palmer House</ref> in Chicago, with newspaper headlines being shown in quick succession, and snippets of slow motion to highlight a specific moment, accompanied by brief snippets of Ol' Man River. African-American dancers were seen performing a specific dance, and this would change to a scene showing white dancers performing the same dance. This was meant to illustrate how white performers "appropriated" the music and dancing styles of African Americans. Earlier productions of Show Boat, even the 1927 stage original and the 1936 film version, did not go this far in social commentary.<ref target="#cite_note-62">[62]</ref></p>
<p>During the production in Toronto, many black community leaders and their supporters expressed opposition to the show, protesting in front of the theatre, "shouting insults and waving placards reading SHOW BOAT SPREADS LIES AND HATE and SHOW BOAT = CULTURAL GENOCIDE".<ref target="#cite_note-Time-63">[63]</ref> Various theatre critics in New York, however, commented that Prince highlighted racial inequality in his production as to show its injustice, as well as to show the historical suffering of blacks. A critic noted that he included "an absolutely beautiful piece of music cut from the original production and from the movie ["Mis'ry's Comin' Round"] ... a haunting gospel melody sung by the black chorus. The addition of this number is so successful because it salutes the dignity and the pure talent of the black workers and allows them to shine for a brief moment on the center stage of the showboat".<ref target="#cite_note-Princereview-61">[61]</ref></p>

<h3>Analysis[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=23" title="Edit section: Analysis">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>Many commentators, both black and non-black, view the show as an outdated and stereotypical commentary on race relations that portrays blacks in a negative or inferior position. Douglass K. Daniel of <ref target="/wiki/Kansas_State_University" title="Kansas State University">Kansas State University</ref> has commented that it is a "racially flawed story",<ref target="#cite_note-AEJMC-64">[64]</ref> and the <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/African-Canadian" title="African-Canadian">African-Canadian</ref> writer <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/M._Nourbese_Philip" title="M. Nourbese Philip">M. Nourbese Philip</ref> claims:</p>

<p>The affront at the heart of Show Boat is still very alive today. It begins with the book and its negative and one-dimensional images of Black people and continues on through the colossal and deliberate omission of the Black experience, including the pain of a people traumatized by four centuries of attempted genocide and exploitation. Not to mention the appropriation of Black music for the profit of the very people who oppressed Blacks and Africans. All this continues to offend deeply. The ol' man river of racism continues to run through the history of these productions and is very much part of this (Toronto) production. It is part of the overwhelming need of white Americans and white Canadians to convince themselves of our inferiority – that our demands don't represent a challenge to them, their privilege and their superiority.<ref target="#cite_note-Showing_Grit-53">[53]</ref></p>
<p>Supporters of the musical believe that the depictions of racism should be regarded not as stereotyping blacks but rather <ref target="/wiki/Satire" title="Satire">satirizing</ref> the common national attitudes that both held those stereotypes and reinforced them through discrimination. In the words of <ref target="/wiki/The_New_Yorker" title="The New Yorker">The New Yorker</ref> theatre critic <ref target="/wiki/John_Lahr" title="John Lahr">John Lahr</ref>:</p>

<p>Describing racism doesn't make Show Boat racist. The production is meticulous in honoring the influence of black culture not just in the making of the nation's wealth but, through music, in the making of its modern spirit."<ref target="#cite_note-Lahr-1">[1]</ref></p>
<p>As described by <ref target="/wiki/Joe_Bob_Briggs" title="Joe Bob Briggs">Joe Bob Briggs</ref>:</p>

<p>Those who attempt to understand works like Show Boat and <ref target="/wiki/Porgy_and_Bess#Racial_controversy" title="Porgy and Bess">Porgy and Bess</ref> through the eyes of their creators usually consider that the show "was a statement AGAINST racism. That was the point of Edna Ferber's novel. That was the point of the show. That's how Oscar wrote it...I think this is about as far from racism as you can get."<ref target="#cite_note-DriveIn-65">[65]</ref></p>
<p>According to Rabbi Alan Berg, Kern and Hammerstein's score to Show Boat is "a tremendous expression of the ethics of tolerance and compassion".<ref target="#cite_note-Berg-66">[66]</ref> As Harold Prince (not Kern, to whom the quote has been mistakenly attributed) states in the production notes to his 1993 production of the show:</p>

<p>Throughout pre-production and rehearsal, I was committed to eliminate any inadvertent stereotype in the original material, dialogue which may seem "Uncle Tom" today... However, I was determined not to rewrite history. The fact that during the 45-year period depicted in our musical there were <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lynchings" title="Lynchings">lynchings</ref>, imprisonment, and forced labor of the blacks in the United States is irrefutable. Indeed, the United States still cannot hold its head high with regard to racism.</p>
<p>Oscar Hammerstein's commitment to idealizing and encouraging tolerance theatrically started with his libretto to Show Boat. It can be seen in his later works, many of which were set to music by <ref target="/wiki/Richard_Rodgers" title="Richard Rodgers">Richard Rodgers</ref>.<ref target="#cite_note-Gomberg-67">[67]</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Carmen_Jones" title="Carmen Jones">Carmen Jones</ref> is an attempt to present a modern version of the classic <ref target="/wiki/Carmen" title="Carmen">French opera</ref> through the experiences of African Americans during <ref target="/wiki/African-American_history#Two_World_Wars" title="African-American history">wartime</ref>, and <ref target="/wiki/South_Pacific_(musical)" title="South Pacific (musical)">South Pacific</ref> explores <ref target="/wiki/Interracial_marriage" title="Interracial marriage">interracial marriage</ref> and prejudice. Finally, <ref target="/wiki/The_King_and_I" title="The King and I">The King and I</ref> deals with different cultures' preconceived notions regarding each other and the possibility for cultural inclusiveness in societies.</p>
<p>Regarding the original author of Show Boat, Ann Shapiro states that</p>

<p>Edna Ferber was taunted for being <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Jewish" title="Jewish">Jewish</ref>; as a young woman eager to launch her career as a journalist, she was told that the <ref target="/wiki/Chicago_Tribune" title="Chicago Tribune">Chicago Tribune</ref> did not hire women reporters. Despite her experience of antisemitism and sexism, she idealized America, creating in her novels an American myth where strong women and downtrodden men of any race prevail... [Show Boat] create[s] visions of racial harmony... in a fictional world that purported to be America but was more illusion than reality. Characters in Ferber's novels achieve <ref target="/wiki/Cultural_assimilation" title="Cultural assimilation">assimilation</ref> and acceptance that was periodically denied Ferber herself throughout her life.<ref target="#cite_note-Shapiro-68">[68]</ref></p>
<p>Whether or not the show is racist, many contend that productions of it should continue as it serves as a history lesson of American race relations. According to African-American opera singer <ref target="/wiki/Phillip_Boykin" title="Phillip Boykin">Phillip Boykin</ref>, who played the role of Joe in a 2000 tour,</p>

<p>.mw-parser-output .templatequote{overflow:hidden;margin:1em 0;padding:0 40px}.mw-parser-output .templatequote .templatequotecite{line-height:1.5em;text-align:left;padding-left:1.6em;margin-top:0}Whenever a show deals with race issues, it gives the audience sweaty palms. I agree with putting it on the stage and making the audience think about it. We see where we came from so we don't repeat it, though we still have a long way to go. A lot of history would disappear if the show was put away forever. An artist must be true to an era. I'm happy with it.<ref target="#cite_note-Tucson-69">[69]</ref></p>

<h2>Notes[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=24" title="Edit section: Notes">edit</ref>]</h2>


<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Lahr_1-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Lahr_1-1">b</ref> Lahr, John (October 27, 1993). "Mississippi Mud". The New Yorker: 123–126..mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:"\"""\"""'""'"}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png")no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-history_2-0">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.theatrehistory.com/american/musical030.html" rel="nofollow">"American Musical Theatre: An Introduction"</ref>, theatrehistory.com, republished from The Complete Book of Light Opera. Mark Lubbock. New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1962, pp. 753–56, accessed December 3, 2008

<ref target="#cite_ref-3">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.olivierawards.com/about/previous-winners/view/item98525/olivier-winners-1991/" rel="nofollow">"Olivier Winners, 1991"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130602021406/http://www.olivierawards.com/about/previous-winners/view/item98525/olivier-winners-1991/" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2013-06-02 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref> olivierawards.com, accessed August 10, 2012

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Block_4-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Block_4-1">b</ref> Block, pp. 22–23</p>

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Kantor_5-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Kantor_5-1">b</ref> Kantor and Maslon, pp. 112–19</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-Bloom_6-0">^</ref> Bloom and Vlastnik, pp. 290–93

<ref target="#cite_ref-Block2_7-0">^</ref> Block, p. 24.

<ref target="#cite_ref-8">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.ovrtur.com/song/100013326" rel="nofollow">"Be Happy, Too"</ref>, Ovrtur.com, accessed January 16, 2016

<ref target="#cite_ref-9">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://tinpanalleyproject.com/index.php?option=com_content&task=view&id=25" rel="nofollow">"After the Ball"</ref>. Tin Pan Alley Project. Retrieved May 28, 2010.

<ref target="#cite_ref-10">^</ref> Raymond Knapp. The American Musical, 2005: Princeton University Press.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-first_film_11-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-first_film_11-1">b</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-first_film_11-2">c</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0020402/soundtrack" rel="nofollow">"Soundtracks for Show Boat (1929)"</ref>. Internet Movie Database. Retrieved June 12, 2010.</p>

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Klein_12-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Klein_12-1">b</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Klein_12-2">c</ref> Klein, Alvin (June 11, 1989). <ref class="external text" href="https://www.nytimes.com/1989/06/11/nyregion/theater-a-show-boat-as-it-s-meant-to-be.html" rel="nofollow">"Theater; A 'Show Boat' as It's Meant to Be"</ref>. New York Times.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-13">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.answers.com/topic/show-boat-1946-broadway-revival-cast" rel="nofollow">"Album Review:Show Boat 1946 Broadway Revival Cast"</ref>. Answers.com. Retrieved May 15, 2010.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Vancheri_14-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Vancheri_14-1">b</ref> Vancheri, Barbara. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.post-gazette.com/magazine/19980823show3.asp" rel="nofollow">"'Show Boat' continues successful voyage"</ref>. Post-Gazette, August 23, 1998. Retrieved January 6, 2006.</p>

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Kreuger_15-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Kreuger_15-1">b</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Kreuger_15-2">c</ref> Kreuger, Miles (1977). Show Boat: The Story of a Classic American Musical. New York: Oxford University Press. pp. 226–27.</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-16">^</ref> Zeke Colvan was officially credited as director of the production, but in his 1977 book Show Boat: The History of a Classic American Musical, musical historian <ref target="/wiki/Miles_Kreuger" title="Miles Kreuger">Miles Kreuger</ref> says that when he interviewed Oscar Hammerstein II months before the latter's death, the always modest Hammerstein admitted that now that Colvan was dead, he could finally state that it was he (Hammerstein) who had directed the original production of the show, and that Colvan had actually served as stage manager.

<ref target="#cite_ref-17">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.answers.com/topic/john-harkrider" rel="nofollow">"John Harkrider"</ref>. Answers.com. Retrieved May 24, 2010.

<ref target="#cite_ref-18">^</ref> Atkinson, J. Brooks (December 28, 1927). <ref class="external text" href="http://theater2.nytimes.com/mem/theater/treview.html?_r=1&html_title=&tols_title=SHOW%20BOAT%20(PLAY)&pdate=19271228&byline=By%20J.%20BROOKS%20ATKINSON&id=1077011431418&oref=slogin" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat"</ref>. New York Times.

<ref target="#cite_ref-19">^</ref> Atkinson, J. Brooks (May 20, 1932). <ref class="external text" href="https://www.nytimes.com/1932/05/20/archives/the-play-show-boat-as-good-as-new.html?sq=Show%2520Boat%2520%2520revival&scp=9&st=cse" rel="nofollow">"THE PLAY; Show Boat" as Good as New"</ref>. New York Times.

<ref target="#cite_ref-20">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.criterion.com/current/posts/928-show-boat" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat"</ref>, Criterion Collection, Accessed November 27, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-21">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0028249/" rel="nofollow">Show Boat</ref>, IMDB.com, Accessed November 27, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-22">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.glopad.org/pi/en/image/1003422" rel="nofollow">Advertisement for Show Boat</ref> 1932, Global Performing Arts Database, accessed April 29, 2010

<ref target="#cite_ref-23">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.ibdb.com/broadway-production/show-boat-4269" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat – Broadway Musical – 1994 Revival - IBDB"</ref>. www.ibdb.com.

<ref target="#cite_ref-24">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.ibdb.com/production.php?id=4269" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat"</ref>. Internet Broadway Database. Retrieved May 28, 2010.

<ref target="#cite_ref-25">^</ref> Barbara Isenberg (October 9, 1994). <ref class="external text" href="http://articles.latimes.com/1994-10-09/entertainment/ca-48293_1_show-boat" rel="nofollow">"Prince at the Helm"</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/Los_Angeles_Times" title="Los Angeles Times">Los Angeles Times</ref>.

<ref target="#cite_ref-26">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.ovrtur.com/production/2882553" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat, London Production, 1928"</ref>. ovrtur.com. Retrieved June 12, 2010.

<ref target="#cite_ref-27">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.guidetomusicaltheatre.com/london_shows_chronology/1971.htm" rel="nofollow">"Chronology of London Shows - The Guide to Musical Theatre"</ref>. www.guidetomusicaltheatre.com.

<ref target="#cite_ref-28">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.albemarle-london.com/Archive/ArchiveShow.php?Show_Name=Show%20Boat" rel="nofollow">"'Show Boat', Prince Edward Theatre, 1998"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101213085918/http://albemarle-london.com/Archive/ArchiveShow.php?Show_Name=Show%20Boat" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2010-12-13 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref> albemarle-london.com, accessed August 10, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-29">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.olivierawards.com/about/previous-winners/view/item98534/olivier-winners-1999/" rel="nofollow">"Olivier Winners 1999"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120117002400/http://www.olivierawards.com/about/previous-winners/view/item98534/olivier-winners-1999/" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> January 17, 2012, at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref> olivierawards.com, accessed August 10, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-30">^</ref> Dowden, Neil (June 6, 2006). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.musicomh.com/theatre/show-boat_0606.htm" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat at Royal Albert Hall"</ref>. OMH. Retrieved November 27, 2012.

<ref target="#cite_ref-31">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.bestoftheatre.co.uk/blog/post/show-boat-london" rel="nofollow">"West End transfer for critically acclaimed Show Boat"</ref>, Best of Theatre, February 11, 2016

<ref target="#cite_ref-32">^</ref> Billington, Michael. <ref class="external text" href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/theatreblog/2016/apr/26/show-boat-musical-daniel-evans-new-london-theatre" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat: the classic musical still shipshape after all these years"</ref>, The Guardian, April 26, 2016

<ref target="#cite_ref-33">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.stagefaves.com/blog/show-boat-closes-five-months-early-on-27-aug" rel="nofollow">"Despite five-star reviews, Show Boat closes five months early on 27 Aug"</ref>, StageFaves.com, May 10, 2016

<ref target="#cite_ref-34">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110726152905/http://oldtimeradio-in-tx.homedns.org/otr/cavalcade%20of%20america4/" rel="nofollow">"Archived copy"</ref>. Archived from <ref class="external text" href="http://oldtimeradio-in-tx.homedns.org/otr/cavalcade%20of%20america4/" rel="nofollow">the original</ref> on 2011-07-26. Retrieved 2011-02-03.CS1 maint: archived copy as title (<ref target="/wiki/Category:CS1_maint:_archived_copy_as_title" title="Category:CS1 maint: archived copy as title">link</ref>)

<ref target="#cite_ref-35">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://archive.org/details/Lux17" rel="nofollow">"Lux Radio Theater 1952"</ref> – via Internet Archive.

<ref target="#cite_ref-36">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b00yn83n" rel="nofollow">"'Show Boat', Episode 1 of 2, 20 Feb 2011 and 26 Feb 2011"</ref> bbc.co.uk, accessed Febriaru 21, 2011

<ref target="#cite_ref-37">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120603011156/http://www.lyricopera.org/watchandlisten/broadcasts.aspx" rel="nofollow">"Archived copy"</ref>. Archived from <ref class="external text" href="http://www.lyricopera.org/watchandlisten/broadcasts.aspx" rel="nofollow">the original</ref> on 2012-06-03. Retrieved 2012-06-16.CS1 maint: archived copy as title (<ref target="/wiki/Category:CS1_maint:_archived_copy_as_title" title="Category:CS1 maint: archived copy as title">link</ref>)

<ref target="#cite_ref-38">^</ref> <ref class="external free" href="https://archive.org/details/KernShowBoat-AScenarioForOrchestra" rel="nofollow">https://archive.org/details/KernShowBoat-AScenarioForOrchestra</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-39">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.cduniverse.com/search/xx/music/pid/1453173/a/hollywood+bowl+on+broadway.htm&frm=www.cduniverse.com" rel="nofollow">"John Mauceri - Hollywood Bowl On Broadway"</ref>. www.cduniverse.com.

<ref target="#cite_ref-40">^</ref> <ref class="external free" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B002QEXN0M" rel="nofollow">https://www.amazon.com/dp/B002QEXN0M</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-41">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B003PIUC9I?qi" rel="nofollow">"Howard Keel, Gogi Grant, Anne Jeffreys - Selections From Show Boat & Kiss Me Kate - Amazon.com Music"</ref>. www.amazon.com.

<ref target="#cite_ref-42">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.allmusic.com/album/release/show-boat-1936-soundtrack-mr0002001179" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat (1936 Soundtrack)"</ref>. Retrieved November 28, 2012.

<ref target="#cite_ref-Disclaimer_43-0">^</ref> Despite its technical correctness, that Show Boat deserves this title has been disputed by some. See note No. 5 and corresponding text

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Blogger_44-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Blogger_44-1">b</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Blogger_44-2">c</ref> Keeling, Richard (a.k.a. musickna) (December 8, 2005). <ref class="external text" href="http://heronwatermusic.blogspot.com/2005/12/show-boat.html" rel="nofollow">Music – "Show Boat"</ref>. <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Blogger.com" title="Blogger.com">Blogger.com</ref>. Retrieved January 2, 2006</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-45">^</ref> Appen, Ralf von / Frei-Hauenschild, Markus <ref class="external text" href="http://www.gfpm-samples.de/Samples13/appenfrei.pdf" rel="nofollow">"AABA, Refrain, Chorus, Bridge, Prechorus — Song Forms and their Historical Development"</ref>. In: Samples. Online Publikationen der Gesellschaft für Popularmusikforschung/German Society for Popular Music Studies e.V. Ed. by Ralf von Appen, André Doehring and Thomas Phleps. Vol. 13 (2015), p. 14-15.

<ref target="#cite_ref-46">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://ibdb.com/production.php?id=10796" rel="nofollow">Whoopee!</ref>, ibdb.com, Accessed November 27, 2012

<ref target="#cite_ref-47">^</ref> Hammerstein, Oscar II (1927). <ref class="external autonumber" href="http://www.allmusicals.com/lyrics/showboat/cottonblossom.htm" rel="nofollow">[1]</ref> Cotton Blossom Lyrics from Show Boat

<ref target="#cite_ref-48">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://newcitystage.com/2012/02/15/life-upon-the-wicked-stage-director-francesca-zambello-on-why-show-boat-remains-relevant/" rel="nofollow">"Life Upon the Wicked Stage: Director Francesca Zambello on why "Show Boat" remains relevant"</ref>. February 15, 2012. Retrieved November 28, 2012.

<ref target="#cite_ref-49">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0044030/faq" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat (1951) – FAQ"</ref>. Retrieved November 28, 2012.

<ref target="#cite_ref-50">^</ref> Thomas, Bob (August 20, 1991). <ref class="external text" href="https://news.google.com/newspapers?nid=1842&dat=19910820&id=TFAeAAAAIBAJ&sjid=ZccEAAAAIBAJ&pg=5247,2875548" rel="nofollow">"'Show Boat' Just Keeps Rolling Along"</ref>. The Times Daily.

<ref target="#cite_ref-Rosetta_51-0">^</ref> Cronin, Patricia (June 1997). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.mijohn.com/hsjc/rosetta/showb.htm" rel="nofollow">"Timeless 'Show Boat' Just Keeps on Rolling Along"</ref>. Retrieved January 5, 2006.

<ref target="#cite_ref-52">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.allmusicals.com/lyrics/showboat/queeniesballyhoo.htm" rel="nofollow">"Queenie's Ballyhoo Lyrics from Show Boat"</ref>. Retrieved November 28, 2012.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Showing_Grit_53-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Showing_Grit_53-1">b</ref> Philip, M. Nourbese (1993). <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20021203040229/http://www.nourbese.com/Essays-Showing%20Grit.htm" rel="nofollow">Showing Grit: Showboating North of the 44th Parallel</ref> (2nd ed.). Out of print. p. 59. Retrieved December 13, 2005</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-AION_54-0">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://theaion.6te.net/tessgardella/tessgardella.html" rel="nofollow">Tess Gardella</ref>. The Actresses of Italian Origin Notebook. Retrieved January 14, 2006

<ref target="#cite_ref-55">^</ref> Ellison, Cori. "Porgy and the Racial Politics of Music", New York Times, December 13, 1998.

<ref target="#cite_ref-Show_Boat_to_Sondheim_56-0">^</ref> Steyn, Mark (December 5, 1997). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.slate.com/id/2896/" rel="nofollow">"Where Have You Gone, Oscar Hammerstein?"</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/Slate_(magazine)" title="Slate (magazine)">Slate</ref>. Retrieved January 5, 2006.

<ref target="#cite_ref-Changing_Stages_57-0">^</ref> Eyre, Richard; & Wright, Nicholas. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.randomhouse.com/knopf/authors/eyre/excerpt.html" rel="nofollow">Changing Stages: A View of British and American Theatre in the Twentieth Century</ref>. Random House. Retrieved December 31, 2005

<ref target="#cite_ref-FOX_58-0">^</ref> Norvell, Scott; & S., Jon (March 18, 2002). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.foxnews.com/story/0,2933,48114,00.html" rel="nofollow">"The Show Can't Go On"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130526214256/http://www.foxnews.com/story/0,2933,48114,00.html" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2013-05-26 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref>. <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Fox_News_Channel" title="Fox News Channel">Fox News</ref>. Retrieved January 2, 2006

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Lathan_59-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Lathan_59-1">b</ref> Lathan, Peter (October 24, 1999). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.britishtheatreguide.info/articles/241099.htm" rel="nofollow">"A More Subtle Form of Censorship"</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20160303191558/http://www.britishtheatreguide.info/articles/241099.htm" rel="nofollow">Archived</ref> 2016-03-03 at the <ref target="/wiki/Wayback_Machine" title="Wayback Machine">Wayback Machine</ref>. The British Theatre Guide. Retrieved January 14, 2006</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-60">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-489325/Production-Show-Boat-sunk-race-row-blacked-actors.html" rel="nofollow">"Production of Show Boat is sunk after race row over 'blacked-up' actors"</ref>. Daily Mail. London. October 23, 2007.

<p>^ <ref target="#cite_ref-Princereview_61-0">a</ref> <ref target="#cite_ref-Princereview_61-1">b</ref> Saviola, Gerard C. <ref class="external text" href="http://xroads.virginia.edu/~UG97/showboat/sbreview.html" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat – Review of 1994 production"</ref>, <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/American_Studies" title="American Studies">American Studies</ref> at <ref target="/wiki/University_of_Virginia" title="University of Virginia">University of Virginia</ref>, April 1, 1997, accessed January 5, 2006</p>

<ref target="#cite_ref-62">^</ref> Richards, David (October 3, 1994). <ref class="external text" href="https://www.nytimes.com/1994/10/03/theater/theater-review-show-boat-classic-musical-with-a-change-in-focus.html?pagewanted=all&src=pm" rel="nofollow">"Show Boat; Classic Musical With a Change in Focus"</ref>. The New York Times. Retrieved November 27, 2012.

<ref target="#cite_ref-Time_63-0">^</ref> Henry, William A. III (November 1, 1993)

<ref target="#cite_ref-AEJMC_64-0">^</ref> Daniel, Douglass K. <ref class="external text" href="http://list.msu.edu/cgi-bin/wa?A3=ind9710a&L=AEJMC&E=7BIT&P=532016&B=--&T=TEXT%2FPLAIN;%20charset=US-ASCII" rel="nofollow">"They Just Keep Rolling Along: Images of Blacks in Film Versions of Show Boat"</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/Association_for_Education_in_Journalism_and_Mass_Communication" title="Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication">Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication</ref>, Minorities and Communication Division. Retrieved December 31, 2005[<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Link_rot" title="Wikipedia:Link rot">dead link</ref>]

<ref target="#cite_ref-DriveIn_65-0">^</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Joe_Bob_Briggs" title="Joe Bob Briggs">Briggs, Joe Bob</ref> (May 7, 1993). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.joebobbriggs.com/index.php?/body-of-influence-1993.html" rel="nofollow">Joe Bob Goes to the Drive In</ref>. <ref target="/wiki/Joe_Bob_Goes_to_the_Drive_In" title="Joe Bob Goes to the Drive In">The Joe Bob Report</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-Berg_66-0">^</ref> Laporte, Elaine. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.jewishsf.com/content/2-0-/module/displaystory/story_id/2914/edition_id/51/format/html/displaystory.html" rel="nofollow">Why do Jews sing the blues?</ref>. The Jewish News Weekly of Northern California, February 9, 1996

<ref target="#cite_ref-Gomberg_67-0">^</ref> Gomberg, Alan (February 16, 2004). <ref class="external text" href="http://www.talkinbroadway.com/rialto/past/2004/02_16_04.html" rel="nofollow">Making Americans: Jews and the Broadway Musical – Book Review</ref>. What's New on the Rialto?. Retrieved January 6, 2006

<ref target="#cite_ref-Shapiro_68-0">^</ref> Shapiro, Ann R. (2001). <ref class="external text" href="http://muse.jhu.edu/cgi-bin/access.cgi?uri=/journals/shofar/v020/20.2shapiro.html" rel="nofollow">"Edna Ferber, Jewish American Feminist"</ref>[<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Link_rot" title="Wikipedia:Link rot">permanent dead link</ref>], <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Shofar:_An_Interdisciplinary_Journal_of_Jewish_Studies" title="Shofar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Jewish Studies">Shofar: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Jewish Studies</ref>, vol. 20, #2, pp. 52–60

<ref target="#cite_ref-Tucson_69-0">^</ref> Regan, Margaret. <ref class="external text" href="http://www.tucsonweekly.com/gbase/arts/Content?oid=oid:42383" rel="nofollow">"Facing the Music – A Revival of Show Boat Confronts the Production's Historical Racism"</ref>, <ref target="/wiki/Tucson_Weekly" title="Tucson Weekly">Tucson Weekly</ref>, April 13, 2000, accessed July 2, 2016


<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=25" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Block, Geoffrey. Enchanted Evenings: The Broadway Musical from Show Boat to Sondheim, New York: Oxford University Press, Inc., 1997. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-19-510791-8" title="Special:BookSources/0-19-510791-8">0-19-510791-8</ref></p>
<p>Bloom, Ken and Vlastnik, Frank. Broadway Musicals: The 101 Greatest Shows of all Time, New York: Black Dog & Leventhal Publishers, 2004. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/1-57912-390-2" title="Special:BookSources/1-57912-390-2">1-57912-390-2</ref></p>
<p>Ferber, Edna. "A Peculiar Treasure", New York: Garden City Publishing Company, 1940.</p>
<p>Grams, Martin. The History of the Cavalcade of America: Sponsored by DuPont. (Morris Publishing, 1999). <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-7392-0138-7" title="Special:BookSources/0-7392-0138-7">0-7392-0138-7</ref></p>
<p>Jones, John Bush. Our Musicals, Ourselves: A Social History of American Musical Theatre, Hanover: Brandeis University Press, 2003. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/1-58465-311-6" title="Special:BookSources/1-58465-311-6">1-58465-311-6</ref></p>
<p>Kantor, Michael and Maslon, Laurence. Broadway: The American Musical, New York:Bullfinch Press, 2004. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-8212-2905-2" title="Special:BookSources/0-8212-2905-2">0-8212-2905-2</ref></p>
<p>Kislan, Richard. The Musical: A Look at the American Musical Theater, Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1980. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-13-608547-4" title="Special:BookSources/0-13-608547-4">0-13-608547-4</ref></p>
<p>Knapp, Raymond. The American Musical and the Formation of National Identity, Princeton: Princeton University Press, 2005. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-691-11864-7" title="Special:BookSources/0-691-11864-7">0-691-11864-7</ref></p>
<p>Kreuger, Miles. Showboat: The Story of a Classic American Musical, New York: Oxford University Press, 1977. <ref target="/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number" title="International Standard Book Number">ISBN</ref> <ref target="/wiki/Special:BookSources/0-19-502275-0" title="Special:BookSources/0-19-502275-0">0-19-502275-0</ref></p>
<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit&section=26" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.ibdb.com/broadway-show/7970" rel="nofollow">Show Boat</ref> at the <ref target="/wiki/Internet_Broadway_Database" title="Internet Broadway Database">Internet Broadway Database</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.imagi-nation.com/moonstruck/albm32.html" rel="nofollow">Information about the musical</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.pbs.org/wnet/broadway/shows/show-boat/" rel="nofollow">PBS.org info about Show Boat</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.scena.org/columns/lebrecht/060531-NL-show.html" rel="nofollow">Scena.org analysis of the show</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://xroads.virginia.edu/~ug97/showboat/sbintro.html" rel="nofollow">History of the show</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.glopad.org/pi/en/record/piece/1000520" rel="nofollow">Show Boat images</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.post-gazette.com/magazine/19980823show3.asp" rel="nofollow">Post-Gazette information and timeline for Show Boat</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.ovrtur.com/show/120925" rel="nofollow">Information at Ovrtur.com</ref>
<p>Streaming audio</p>

<ref class="external text" href="https://archive.org/download/otr_campbellplayhouse/CampbellPlayhouse39-03-31Showboat.mp3" rel="nofollow">Show Boat</ref> on <ref target="/wiki/The_Campbell_Playhouse_(radio_series)" title="The Campbell Playhouse (radio series)">Campbell Playhouse</ref>: March 31, 1939
<ref class="external text" href="https://archive.org/download/Lux05/Lux_40-06-24_Showboat.mp3" rel="nofollow">Show Boat</ref> on <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lux_Radio_Theater" title="Lux Radio Theater">Lux Radio Theater</ref>: June 24, 1940
<ref class="external text" href="https://archive.org/download/Radio.Hall.Of.Fame/RHOF_44-12-31_057_Showboat.mp3" rel="nofollow">Show Boat</ref> on Radio Hall of Fame: December 31, 1944
<ref class="external text" href="https://archive.org/download/TheRailroadHour/RH_50-10-30_ep109-Showboat.mp3" rel="nofollow">Show Boat</ref> on <ref target="/wiki/The_Railroad_Hour" title="The Railroad Hour">The Railroad Hour</ref>: October 30, 1950
<ref class="external text" href="https://archive.org/download/Lux17/Lux_52-02-11_Show_Boat.mp3" rel="nofollow">Show Boat</ref> on <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Lux_Radio_Theater" title="Lux Radio Theater">Lux Radio Theater</ref>: February 11, 1952
<ref target="/wiki/Template:Edna_Ferber" title="Template:Edna Ferber">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:Edna_Ferber" title="Template talk:Edna Ferber">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:Edna_Ferber&action=edit">e</ref><ref target="/wiki/Edna_Ferber" title="Edna Ferber">Edna Ferber</ref>Plays
<p>Our Mrs. McChesney (1915)</p>
<p>$1200 a Year: A Comedy in Three Acts (1920)</p>
<p>Minick: A Play (1924)</p>
<p>Stage Door (1926)</p>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Royal_Family_(play)" title="The Royal Family (play)">The Royal Family</ref> (1927)
<ref target="/wiki/Dinner_at_Eight_(play)" title="Dinner at Eight (play)">Dinner at Eight</ref> (1932)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Land_Is_Bright" title="The Land Is Bright">The Land Is Bright</ref> (1941)
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Edna-Ferber-1928.jpg"></ref>Novels
<p>Dawn O'Hara, The Girl Who Laughed (1911)</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Personality_Plus_(novel)" title="Personality Plus (novel)">Personality Plus</ref> (1914)
<p>Fanny Herself (1917)</p>
<p>The Girls (1921)</p>
<p>Gigolo (1922)</p>
<ref target="/wiki/So_Big_(novel)" title="So Big (novel)">So Big</ref> (1924)
<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(novel)" title="Show Boat (novel)">Show Boat</ref> (1926)
<ref target="/wiki/Cimarron_(novel)" title="Cimarron (novel)">Cimarron</ref> (1929)
<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/American_Beauty_(Edna_Ferber_novel)" title="American Beauty (Edna Ferber novel)">American Beauty</ref> (1931)
<ref target="/wiki/Come_and_Get_It_(novel)" title="Come and Get It (novel)">Come and Get It</ref> (1935)
<ref target="/wiki/Saratoga_Trunk_(novel)" title="Saratoga Trunk (novel)">Saratoga Trunk</ref> (1941)
<p>Great Son (1945)</p>
<ref class="new" href="/w/index.php?title=Giant_(novel)&action=edit&redlink=1" title="Giant (novel) (page does not exist)">Giant</ref> (1952)
<p>Ice Palace (1958)</p>
<p>Other works</p>
<ref target="/wiki/A_Peculiar_Treasure" title="A Peculiar Treasure">A Peculiar Treasure</ref> (1939 autobiography)
<p>AdaptationsSo Big</p>
<ref target="/wiki/So_Big_(1924_film)" title="So Big (1924 film)">So Big</ref> (1924 film)
<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/So_Big!_(1932_film)" title="So Big! (1932 film)">So Big</ref> (1932 film)
<ref target="/wiki/So_Big_(1953_film)" title="So Big (1953 film)">So Big</ref> (1953 film)
<p>Cimarron</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Cimarron_(1931_film)" title="Cimarron (1931 film)">Cimarron</ref> (1931 film)
<ref target="/wiki/Cimarron_(1960_film)" title="Cimarron (1960 film)">Cimarron</ref> (1960 film)
<p>Saratoga Trunk</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Saratoga_Trunk" title="Saratoga Trunk">Saratoga Trunk</ref> (1945 film)
<ref target="/wiki/Saratoga_(musical)" title="Saratoga (musical)">Saratoga</ref> (1959 musical)
<p>Show Boat</p>
<ref class="mw-selflink selflink">Show Boat</ref> (1927 musical)
<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1929_film)" title="Show Boat (1929 film)">Show Boat</ref> (1929 film)
<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1936_film)" title="Show Boat (1936 film)">Show Boat</ref> (1936 film)
<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1951_film)" title="Show Boat (1951 film)">Show Boat</ref> (1951 film)
<p>The Royal Family</p>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Royal_Family_of_Broadway" title="The Royal Family of Broadway">The Royal Family of Broadway</ref> (1930 musical)
<p>Giant</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Giant_(1956_film)" title="Giant (1956 film)">Giant</ref> (1956 film)
<ref target="/wiki/Giant_(musical)" title="Giant (musical)">Giant</ref> (2009 musical)
<p>Gigolo<ref target="/wiki/Gigolo_(film)" title="Gigolo (film)">Gigolo</ref> (1926 film)Family</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Janet_Fox" title="Janet Fox">Janet Fox</ref>

<ref target="/wiki/Template:Show_Boat" title="Template:Show Boat">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:Show_Boat" title="Template talk:Show Boat">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:Show_Boat&action=edit">e</ref><ref target="/wiki/Edna_Ferber" title="Edna Ferber">Edna Ferber</ref>'s <ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(novel)" title="Show Boat (novel)">Show Boat</ref> (1926)Characters
<ref target="/wiki/Julie_Dozier" title="Julie Dozier">Julie Dozier</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Gaylord_Ravenal" title="Gaylord Ravenal">Gaylord Ravenal</ref>
<p>Film</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1929_film)" title="Show Boat (1929 film)">Show Boat</ref> (1929)
<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1936_film)" title="Show Boat (1936 film)">Show Boat</ref> (1936)
<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1951_film)" title="Show Boat (1951 film)">Show Boat</ref> (1951)
<p>Music</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Make_Believe_(Jerome_Kern_song)" title="Make Believe (Jerome Kern song)">Make Believe</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Ol%27_Man_River" title="Ol' Man River">Ol' Man River</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Can%27t_Help_Lovin%27_Dat_Man" title="Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man">Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/Bill_(song)" title="Bill (song)">Bill</ref>"</p>
<p>"<ref target="/wiki/After_the_Ball_(song)" title="After the Ball (song)">After the Ball</ref>"</p>
<p>Other</p>
<ref class="mw-selflink selflink">Show Boat</ref> (1927, musical)
<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat_(1959_cast_album)" title="Show Boat (1959 cast album)">Show Boat</ref> (1959 cast album)
<ref target="/wiki/Andr%C3%A9_Previn_and_Friends_Play_Show_Boat" title="André Previn and Friends Play Show Boat">André Previn and Friends Play Show Boat</ref> (1995 instrumental jazz album)

<p>Awards for Show Boat</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Template:DramaDesk_Musical" title="Template:DramaDesk Musical">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:DramaDesk_Musical" title="Template talk:DramaDesk Musical">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:DramaDesk_Musical&action=edit">e</ref><ref target="/wiki/Drama_Desk_Award_for_Outstanding_Musical" title="Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Musical">Drama Desk Award for Outstanding Musical</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/The_Wiz" title="The Wiz">The Wiz</ref> (1975)
<ref target="/wiki/A_Chorus_Line" title="A Chorus Line">A Chorus Line</ref> (1976)
<ref target="/wiki/Annie_(musical)" title="Annie (musical)">Annie</ref> (1977)
<ref target="/wiki/Ain%27t_Misbehavin%27_(musical)" title="Ain't Misbehavin' (musical)">Ain't Misbehavin'</ref> (1978)
<ref target="/wiki/Sweeney_Todd:_The_Demon_Barber_of_Fleet_Street" title="Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street">Sweeney Todd</ref> (1979)
<ref target="/wiki/Evita_(musical)" title="Evita (musical)">Evita</ref> (1980)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Pirates_of_Penzance" title="The Pirates of Penzance">The Pirates of Penzance</ref> (1981)
<ref target="/wiki/Nine_(musical)" title="Nine (musical)">Nine</ref> (1982)
<ref target="/wiki/Little_Shop_of_Horrors_(musical)" title="Little Shop of Horrors (musical)">Little Shop of Horrors</ref> (1983)
<ref target="/wiki/Sunday_in_the_Park_with_George" title="Sunday in the Park with George">Sunday in the Park with George</ref> (1984)
<ref target="/wiki/Drood" title="Drood">The Mystery of Edwin Drood</ref> (1986)
<ref target="/wiki/Les_Mis%C3%A9rables_(musical)" title="Les Misérables (musical)">Les Miserables</ref> (1987)
<ref target="/wiki/Into_the_Woods" title="Into the Woods">Into the Woods</ref> (1988)
<ref target="/wiki/Jerome_Robbins%27_Broadway" title="Jerome Robbins' Broadway">Jerome Robbins' Broadway</ref> (1989)
<ref target="/wiki/City_of_Angels_(musical)" title="City of Angels (musical)">City of Angels</ref> (1990)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Secret_Garden_(musical)" title="The Secret Garden (musical)"> The Secret Garden</ref> (1991)
<ref target="/wiki/Crazy_for_You_(musical)" title="Crazy for You (musical)">Crazy for You</ref> (1992)
<ref target="/wiki/Kiss_of_the_Spider_Woman_(musical)" title="Kiss of the Spider Woman (musical)">Kiss of the Spider Woman</ref> (1993)
<ref target="/wiki/Passion_(musical)" title="Passion (musical)"> Passion </ref> (1994)
<ref class="mw-selflink selflink">Show Boat</ref> (1995)
<ref target="/wiki/Rent_(musical)" title="Rent (musical)">Rent</ref> (1996)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Life_(musical)" title="The Life (musical)">The Life</ref> (1997)
<ref target="/wiki/Ragtime_(musical)" title="Ragtime (musical)">Ragtime</ref> (1998)
<ref target="/wiki/Parade_(musical)" title="Parade (musical)">Parade</ref> (1999)
<ref target="/wiki/Contact_(musical)" title="Contact (musical)">Contact</ref> (2000)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Producers_(musical)" title="The Producers (musical)">The Producers</ref> (2001)
<ref target="/wiki/Thoroughly_Modern_Millie_(musical)" title="Thoroughly Modern Millie (musical)">Thoroughly Modern Millie</ref> (2002)
<ref target="/wiki/Hairspray_(musical)" title="Hairspray (musical)">Hairspray</ref> (2003)
<ref target="/wiki/Wicked_(musical)" title="Wicked (musical)">Wicked</ref> (2004)
<ref target="/wiki/Spamalot" title="Spamalot">Spamalot</ref> (2005)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Drowsy_Chaperone" title="The Drowsy Chaperone">The Drowsy Chaperone</ref> (2006)
<ref target="/wiki/Spring_Awakening_(musical)" title="Spring Awakening (musical)">Spring Awakening</ref> (2007)
<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Passing_Strange_(musical)" title="Passing Strange (musical)">Passing Strange</ref> (2008)
<ref target="/wiki/Billy_Elliot_the_Musical" title="Billy Elliot the Musical">Billy Elliot the Musical</ref> (2009)
<ref target="/wiki/Memphis_(musical)" title="Memphis (musical)">Memphis</ref> (2010)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Book_of_Mormon_(musical)" title="The Book of Mormon (musical)">The Book of Mormon</ref> (2011)
<ref target="/wiki/Once_(musical)" title="Once (musical)">Once</ref> (2012)
<ref target="/wiki/Matilda_the_Musical" title="Matilda the Musical">Matilda the Musical</ref> (2013)
<ref target="/wiki/A_Gentleman%27s_Guide_to_Love_and_Murder" title="A Gentleman's Guide to Love and Murder">A Gentleman's Guide to Love and Murder</ref> (2014)
<ref target="/wiki/Hamilton_(musical)" title="Hamilton (musical)">Hamilton</ref> (2015)
<ref target="/wiki/Shuffle_Along,_or,_the_Making_of_the_Musical_Sensation_of_1921_and_All_That_Followed" title="Shuffle Along, or, the Making of the Musical Sensation of 1921 and All That Followed">Shuffle Along</ref> (2016)
<ref target="/wiki/Come_from_Away" title="Come from Away">Come from Away</ref> (2017)
<ref target="/wiki/SpongeBob_SquarePants_(musical)" title="SpongeBob SquarePants (musical)">SpongeBob SquarePants</ref> (2018)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Prom_(musical)" title="The Prom (musical)">The Prom</ref> (2019)

<ref target="/wiki/Template:OlivierAward_MusicalRevival" title="Template:OlivierAward MusicalRevival">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:OlivierAward_MusicalRevival" title="Template talk:OlivierAward MusicalRevival">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:OlivierAward_MusicalRevival&action=edit">e</ref><ref target="/wiki/Laurence_Olivier_Award_for_Best_Musical_Revival" title="Laurence Olivier Award for Best Musical Revival">Laurence Olivier Award for Best Musical Revival</ref>
<ref class="mw-selflink selflink">Show Boat</ref> (1991)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Boys_from_Syracuse" title="The Boys from Syracuse">The Boys from Syracuse</ref> (1992)
<ref target="/wiki/Carousel_(musical)" title="Carousel (musical)">Carousel</ref> (1993)
<ref target="/wiki/Sweeney_Todd:_The_Demon_Barber_of_Fleet_Street" title="Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street">Sweeney Todd</ref> (1994)
<ref target="/wiki/She_Loves_Me" title="She Loves Me">She Loves Me</ref> (1995)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Who%27s_Tommy" title="The Who's Tommy">The Who's Tommy</ref> (1997)
<ref target="/wiki/Chicago_(musical)" title="Chicago (musical)">Chicago</ref> (1998)
<ref target="/wiki/Oklahoma!" title="Oklahoma!">Oklahoma!</ref> (1999)
<ref target="/wiki/Candide_(operetta)" title="Candide (operetta)">Candide</ref> (2000)
<ref target="/wiki/Singin%27_in_the_Rain_(musical)" title="Singin' in the Rain (musical)">Singin' in the Rain</ref> (2001)
<ref target="/wiki/My_Fair_Lady" title="My Fair Lady">My Fair Lady</ref> (2002)
<ref target="/wiki/Anything_Goes" title="Anything Goes">Anything Goes</ref> (2003)
<ref target="/wiki/Pacific_Overtures" title="Pacific Overtures">Pacific Overtures</ref> (2004)
<ref target="/wiki/Grand_Hotel_(musical)" title="Grand Hotel (musical)">Grand Hotel</ref> (2005)
<ref target="/wiki/Guys_and_Dolls" title="Guys and Dolls">Guys and Dolls</ref> (2006)
<ref target="/wiki/Sunday_in_the_Park_with_George" title="Sunday in the Park with George">Sunday in the Park with George</ref> (2007)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Magic_Flute_(musical)" title="The Magic Flute (musical)">The Magic Flute</ref> (2008)
<ref target="/wiki/La_Cage_aux_Folles_(musical)" title="La Cage aux Folles (musical)">La Cage aux Folles</ref> (2009)
<ref target="/wiki/Hello,_Dolly!_(musical)" title="Hello, Dolly! (musical)">Hello, Dolly!</ref> (2010)
<ref target="/wiki/Into_the_Woods" title="Into the Woods">Into the Woods</ref> (2011)
<ref target="/wiki/Crazy_for_You_(musical)" title="Crazy for You (musical)">Crazy for You</ref> (2012)
<ref target="/wiki/Sweeney_Todd:_The_Demon_Barber_of_Fleet_Street" title="Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street">Sweeney Todd</ref> (2013)
<ref target="/wiki/Merrily_We_Roll_Along_(musical)" title="Merrily We Roll Along (musical)">Merrily We Roll Along</ref> (2014)
<ref target="/wiki/City_of_Angels_(musical)" title="City of Angels (musical)">City of Angels</ref> (2015)
<ref target="/wiki/Gypsy_(musical)" title="Gypsy (musical)">Gypsy</ref> (2016)
<ref target="/wiki/Jesus_Christ_Superstar" title="Jesus Christ Superstar">Jesus Christ Superstar</ref> (2017)
<ref target="/wiki/Follies" title="Follies">Follies</ref> (2018)
<ref target="/wiki/Company_(musical)" title="Company (musical)">Company</ref> (2019)

<ref target="/wiki/Template:TonyAward_MusicalRevival" title="Template:TonyAward MusicalRevival">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:TonyAward_MusicalRevival" title="Template talk:TonyAward MusicalRevival">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:TonyAward_MusicalRevival&action=edit">e</ref><ref target="/wiki/Tony_Award_for_Best_Revival_of_a_Musical" title="Tony Award for Best Revival of a Musical">Tony Award for Best Revival of a Musical</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Carousel_(musical)" title="Carousel (musical)">Carousel</ref> (1994)
<ref class="mw-selflink selflink">Show Boat</ref> (1995)
<ref target="/wiki/The_King_and_I" title="The King and I">The King and I</ref> (1996)
<ref target="/wiki/Chicago_(musical)" title="Chicago (musical)">Chicago</ref> (1997)
<ref target="/wiki/Cabaret_(musical)" title="Cabaret (musical)">Cabaret</ref> (1998)
<ref target="/wiki/Annie_Get_Your_Gun_(musical)" title="Annie Get Your Gun (musical)">Annie Get Your Gun</ref> (1999)
<ref target="/wiki/Kiss_Me,_Kate" title="Kiss Me, Kate">Kiss Me, Kate</ref> (2000)
<ref target="/wiki/42nd_Street_(musical)" title="42nd Street (musical)">42nd Street</ref> (2001)
<ref target="/wiki/Into_the_Woods" title="Into the Woods">Into the Woods</ref> (2002)
<ref target="/wiki/Nine_(musical)" title="Nine (musical)">Nine</ref> (2003)
<ref target="/wiki/Assassins_(musical)" title="Assassins (musical)">Assassins</ref> (2004)
<ref target="/wiki/La_Cage_aux_Folles_(musical)" title="La Cage aux Folles (musical)">La Cage aux Folles</ref> (2005)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Pajama_Game" title="The Pajama Game">The Pajama Game</ref> (2006)
<ref target="/wiki/Company_(musical)" title="Company (musical)">Company</ref> (2007)
<ref target="/wiki/South_Pacific_(musical)" title="South Pacific (musical)">South Pacific</ref> (2008)
<ref target="/wiki/Hair_(musical)" title="Hair (musical)">Hair</ref> (2009)
<ref target="/wiki/La_Cage_aux_Folles_(musical)" title="La Cage aux Folles (musical)">La Cage aux Folles</ref> (2010)
<ref target="/wiki/Anything_Goes" title="Anything Goes">Anything Goes</ref> (2011)
<ref target="/wiki/Porgy_and_Bess" title="Porgy and Bess">Porgy and Bess</ref> (2012)
<ref target="/wiki/Pippin_(musical)" title="Pippin (musical)">Pippin</ref> (2013)
<ref target="/wiki/Hedwig_and_the_Angry_Inch_(musical)" title="Hedwig and the Angry Inch (musical)">Hedwig and the Angry Inch</ref> (2014)
<ref target="/wiki/The_King_and_I" title="The King and I">The King and I</ref> (2015)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Color_Purple_(musical)" title="The Color Purple (musical)">The Color Purple</ref> (2016)
<ref target="/wiki/Hello,_Dolly!_(musical)" title="Hello, Dolly! (musical)">Hello, Dolly!</ref> (2017)
<ref target="/wiki/Once_on_This_Island" title="Once on This Island">Once on This Island</ref> (2018)
<ref target="/wiki/Oklahoma!" title="Oklahoma!">Oklahoma!</ref> (2019)

<ref target="/wiki/Help:Authority_control" title="Help:Authority control">Authority control</ref> <ref target="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q2166879" title="Edit this at Wikidata"></ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Integrated_Authority_File" title="Integrated Authority File">GND</ref>: <ref class="external text" href="https://d-nb.info/gnd/30021605X" rel="nofollow">30021605X</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/MusicBrainz" title="MusicBrainz">MusicBrainz</ref> release group: <ref class="external text" href="https://musicbrainz.org/release-group/f88e2878-ebb8-3f3e-ac18-72cacabac7fb" rel="nofollow">f88e2878-ebb8-3f3e-ac18-72cacabac7fb</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/MusicBrainz" title="MusicBrainz">MusicBrainz</ref> work: <ref class="external text" href="https://musicbrainz.org/work/84dc2e3b-be75-4443-a9db-2cfcfe8c9d5a" rel="nofollow">84dc2e3b-be75-4443-a9db-2cfcfe8c9d5a</ref>





<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&oldid=916877743">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&oldid=916877743</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:1927_musicals" title="Category:1927 musicals">1927 musicals</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Broadway_musicals" title="Category:Broadway musicals">Broadway musicals</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Musicals_by_Jerome_Kern" title="Category:Musicals by Jerome Kern">Musicals by Jerome Kern</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:American_musical_films" title="Category:American musical films">American musical films</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Musicals_based_on_novels" title="Category:Musicals based on novels">Musicals based on novels</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:American_films" title="Category:American films">American films</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Musicals_by_Oscar_Hammerstein_II" title="Category:Musicals by Oscar Hammerstein II">Musicals by Oscar Hammerstein II</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:World%27s_fairs_in_fiction" title="Category:World's fairs in fiction">World's fairs in fiction</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:Webarchive_template_wayback_links" title="Category:Webarchive template wayback links">Webarchive template wayback links</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:CS1_maint:_archived_copy_as_title" title="Category:CS1 maint: archived copy as title">CS1 maint: archived copy as title</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:All_articles_with_dead_external_links" title="Category:All articles with dead external links">All articles with dead external links</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_dead_external_links_from_January_2011" title="Category:Articles with dead external links from January 2011">Articles with dead external links from January 2011</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_dead_external_links_from_May_2018" title="Category:Articles with dead external links from May 2018">Articles with dead external links from May 2018</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_permanently_dead_external_links" title="Category:Articles with permanently dead external links">Articles with permanently dead external links</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_short_description" title="Category:Articles with short description">Articles with short description</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Good_articles" title="Category:Good articles">Good articles</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Pages_with_timeline_metadata" title="Category:Pages with timeline metadata">Pages with timeline metadata</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_needing_additional_references_from_June_2015" title="Category:Articles needing additional references from June 2015">Articles needing additional references from June 2015</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:All_articles_needing_additional_references" title="Category:All articles needing additional references">All articles needing additional references</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Wikipedia_articles_with_GND_identifiers" title="Category:Wikipedia articles with GND identifiers">Wikipedia articles with GND identifiers</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Wikipedia_articles_with_MusicBrainz_release_group_identifiers" title="Category:Wikipedia articles with MusicBrainz release group identifiers">Wikipedia articles with MusicBrainz release group identifiers</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Wikipedia_articles_with_MusicBrainz_work_identifiers" title="Category:Wikipedia articles with MusicBrainz work identifiers">Wikipedia articles with MusicBrainz work identifiers</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=Show+Boat" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=Show+Boat" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/Show_Boat" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:Show_Boat" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/Show_Boat">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/Show_Boat" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/Show_Boat" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&oldid=916877743" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q2166879" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=Show_Boat&id=916877743" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>In other projects</h3></p>


<ref target="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Show_Boat_(musical)" hreflang="en">Wikimedia Commons</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=Show+Boat">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=Show+Boat&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Show_Boat" hreflang="de" lang="de" title="Show Boat – German">Deutsch</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Show_Boat" hreflang="es" lang="es" title="Show Boat – Spanish">Español</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Show_Boat_(com%C3%A9die_musicale)" hreflang="fr" lang="fr" title="Show Boat (comédie musicale) – French">Français</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://hr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Show_Boat" hreflang="hr" lang="hr" title="Show Boat – Croatian">Hrvatski</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://id.wikipedia.org/wiki/Show_Boat" hreflang="id" lang="id" title="Show Boat – Indonesian">Bahasa Indonesia</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/Show_Boat_(musical)" hreflang="it" lang="it" title="Show Boat (musical) – Italian">Italiano</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://he.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D7%A1%D7%A4%D7%99%D7%A0%D7%AA_%D7%94%D7%A9%D7%A2%D7%A9%D7%95%D7%A2%D7%99%D7%9D" hreflang="he" lang="he" title="ספינת השעשועים – Hebrew">עברית</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E3%82%B7%E3%83%A7%E3%82%A6%E3%83%9C%E3%83%BC%E3%83%88_(%E3%83%9F%E3%83%A5%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B8%E3%82%AB%E3%83%AB)" hreflang="ja" lang="ja" title="ショウボート (ミュージカル) – Japanese">日本語</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://no.wikipedia.org/wiki/Show_Boat" hreflang="no" lang="no" title="Show Boat – Norwegian">Norsk</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://nn.wikipedia.org/wiki/Show_Boat" hreflang="nn" lang="nn" title="Show Boat – Norwegian Nynorsk">Norsk nynorsk</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://sh.wikipedia.org/wiki/Show_Boat" hreflang="sh" lang="sh" title="Show Boat – Serbo-Croatian">Srpskohrvatski / српскохрватски</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://fi.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teatterilaiva_(musikaali)" hreflang="fi" lang="fi" title="Teatterilaiva (musikaali) – Finnish">Suomi</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://sv.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teaterb%C3%A5ten" hreflang="sv" lang="sv" title="Teaterbåten – Swedish">Svenska</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q2166879#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 21 September 2019, at 03:34 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Show_Boat&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"1.284","walltime":"2.417","ppvisitednodes":{"value":4527,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":142328,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":25820,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":17,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":6,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":1,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":112266,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":1,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 2169.864 1 -total"," 25.08% 544.177 1 Template:Reflist"," 13.61% 295.259 8 Template:ISBN"," 12.29% 266.663 1 Template:More_citations_needed_section"," 11.21% 243.294 1 Template:More_citations_needed"," 11.06% 239.984 1 Template:Authority_control"," 10.88% 235.993 1 Template:Ambox"," 10.67% 231.551 1 Template:Infobox_musical"," 9.58% 207.880 1 Template:Infobox"," 6.88% 149.372 1 Template:Cite_journal"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.479","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":7744648,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1348","timestamp":"20190923223402","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"Show Boat","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Show_Boat","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q2166879","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q2166879","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2004-01-13T22:03:54Z","dateModified":"2019-09-21T03:34:49Z","image":"https:\/\/upload.wikimedia.org\/wikipedia\/en\/f\/fb\/Show_Boat.jpg","headline":"1927 musical play by Jerome Kern and Oscar Hammerstein II"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":117,"wgHostname":"mw1261"});});</p>


