



<p>The Rivals - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"The_Rivals","wgTitle":"The Rivals","wgCurRevisionId":912007683,"wgRevisionId":912007683,"wgArticleId":741230,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["EngvarB from September 2013","Use dmy dates from September 2013","Articles needing additional references from July 2007","All articles needing additional references","Commons category link is on Wikidata","Articles with LibriVox links","Plays by Richard Brinsley Sheridan","1775 plays","Plays set in the 18th century"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November",</p>
<p>"December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"The_Rivals","wgRelevantArticleId":741230,"wgRequestId":"XY1R9gpAAEYAADr@wGkAAABE","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q7760957","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":</p>
<p>"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","ext.cite.styles":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","jquery.makeCollapsible.styles":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["ext.cite.ux-enhancements","site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","jquery.makeCollapsible","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head","mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups",</p>
<p>"ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>

























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>The Rivals</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>


<p>For other uses, see <ref class="mw-redirect mw-disambig" href="/wiki/The_Rivals_(disambiguation)" title="The Rivals (disambiguation)">The Rivals (disambiguation)</ref>.</p>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Question_book-new.svg"></ref>This article needs additional citations for <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Verifiability" title="Wikipedia:Verifiability">verification</ref>. Please help <ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit">improve this article</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Help:Introduction_to_referencing_with_Wiki_Markup/1" title="Help:Introduction to referencing with Wiki Markup/1">adding citations to reliable sources</ref>. Unsourced material may be challenged and removed.Find sources: <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?as_eq=wikipedia&q=%22The+Rivals%22" rel="nofollow">"The Rivals"</ref> – <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?tbm=nws&q=%22The+Rivals%22+-wikipedia" rel="nofollow">news</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?&q=%22The+Rivals%22+site:news.google.com/newspapers&source=newspapers" rel="nofollow">newspapers</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="//www.google.com/search?tbs=bks:1&q=%22The+Rivals%22+-wikipedia" rel="nofollow">books</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="//scholar.google.com/scholar?q=%22The+Rivals%22" rel="nofollow">scholar</ref> · <ref class="external text" href="https://www.jstor.org/action/doBasicSearch?Query=%22The+Rivals%22&acc=on&wc=on" rel="nofollow">JSTOR</ref> (July 2007) (<ref target="/wiki/Help:Maintenance_template_removal" title="Help:Maintenance template removal">Learn how and when to remove this template message</ref>)
<p>The RivalsWritten by<ref target="/wiki/Richard_Brinsley_Sheridan" title="Richard Brinsley Sheridan">Richard Brinsley Sheridan</ref>CharactersMrs Malaprop Miss Lydia languish Faulkland Acres Sir Lucius O'Trigger Fag David Coachman Errand boy servants Sir Anthony Absolute Captain Jack Absolute Julia Lucy MaidDate premiered17 January 1775Place premiered<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Covent_Garden_Theatre" title="Covent Garden Theatre">Covent Garden Theatre</ref>Original languageEnglishGenre<ref target="/wiki/Comedy_of_manners" title="Comedy of manners">Comedy of manners</ref>Setting<ref target="/wiki/Bath,_Somerset" title="Bath, Somerset">Bath</ref>, 'within one day'<ref target="#cite_note-1">[1]</ref></p>
<p>The Rivals is a <ref target="/wiki/Comedy_of_manners" title="Comedy of manners">comedy of manners</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Richard_Brinsley_Sheridan" title="Richard Brinsley Sheridan">Richard Brinsley Sheridan</ref> in five acts which was first performed at <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Covent_Garden_Theatre" title="Covent Garden Theatre">Covent Garden Theatre</ref> on 17 January 1775.<ref target="#cite_note-2">[2]</ref> The story has been updated in numerous adaptions, including a 1935 musical in <ref target="/wiki/London" title="London">London</ref> and a 1958 episode of the television series <ref target="/wiki/Maverick_(TV_series)" title="Maverick (TV series)">Maverick</ref>, with attribution.</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#History">1 History</ref>

<ref target="#Production">1.1 Production</ref>
<ref target="#Reception">1.2 Reception</ref>


<ref target="#Characters">2 Characters</ref>
<ref target="#Plot">3 Plot</ref>
<ref target="#Adaptations">4 Adaptations</ref>

<ref target="#Musical_(1935)">4.1 Musical (1935)</ref>
<ref target='#"Maverick"_adaptation_(1958)'>4.2 "Maverick" adaptation (1958)</ref>
<ref target="#Television_productions">4.3 Television productions</ref>
<ref target="#Jack_Absolute_Novels_(2003–2006)">4.4 Jack Absolute Novels (2003–2006)</ref>


<ref target="#Biographical_sources">5 Biographical sources</ref>
<ref target="#References">6 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">7 External links</ref>


<h2>History[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: History">edit</ref>]</h2>
<h3>Production[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Production">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The Rivals was Sheridan's first play. At the time, he was a young newlywed living in <ref target="/wiki/Bath,_Somerset" title="Bath, Somerset">Bath</ref>. At Sheridan's insistence, upon marriage his wife Eliza (born <ref target="/wiki/Elizabeth_Ann_Linley" title="Elizabeth Ann Linley">Elizabeth Linley</ref>) had given up her career as a singer. This was proper for the wife of a "gentleman", but it was difficult because Eliza would have earned a substantial income as a performer. Instead, the Sheridans lived beyond their means as they entertained the gentry and nobility with Eliza's singing (in private parties) and Richard's wit. Finally, in need of funds, Richard turned to the only craft that could gain him the remuneration he desired in a short time: he began writing a play. He had over the years written and published essays and poems, and among his papers were numerous unfinished plays, essays and political tracts, but never had he undertaken such an ambitious project as this. In a short time, however, he completed The Rivals.</p>

<h3>Reception[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Reception">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The Rivals was first performed at <ref target="/wiki/Covent_Garden" title="Covent Garden">Covent Garden</ref>, London, on 17 January 1775, with comedian <ref target="/wiki/Mary_Bulkley" title="Mary Bulkley">Mary Bulkley</ref> as Julia Melville.<ref target="#cite_note-Oxford_DNB-3">[3]</ref> It was roundly vilified by both the public and the critics for its length, for its bawdiness and for the character of Sir Lucius O'Trigger being a meanly written role played very badly. The actor, Lee, after being hit with an apple during the performance, stopped and addressed the audience, asking "By the pow'rs, is it personal? — is it me, or the matter?" Apparently, it was both. Sheridan immediately withdrew the play and in the next 11 days, rewrote the original (the Larpent manuscript) extensively, including a new preface in which he allowed:</p>


<p>For my own part, I see no reason why the author of a play should not regard a first night's audience as a candid and judicious friend attending, in behalf of the public, at his last rehearsal. If he can dispense with flattery, he is sure at least of sincerity, and even though the annotation be rude, he may rely upon the justness of the comment.</p>


<p>Sheridan also apologised for any impression that O'Trigger was intended as an insult to Ireland. Rewritten and with a new actor, Clinch, in the role of O'Trigger, the play reopened on 28 January to significant acclaim. Indeed, it became a favourite of the royal family, receiving five command performances in ten years, and also in the Colonies (it was <ref target="/wiki/George_Washington" title="George Washington">George Washington</ref>'s favourite play). It became a standard show in the repertoires of 19th-century companies in England and the US.</p>
<p>The play is now considered to be one of Sheridan's masterpieces, and the term <ref class="extiw" href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/malapropism" title="wikt:malapropism">malapropism</ref> was coined in reference to one of the characters in the play. She was first played by <ref target="/wiki/Jane_Green_(actress)" title="Jane Green (actress)">Jane Green</ref>.</p>

<h2>Characters[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: Characters">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Edwin_Austin_Abbey_-_Bob_Acres_and_His_Servant.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:Edwin_Austin_Abbey_-_Bob_Acres_and_His_Servant.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref>Bob Acres and His Servant, illustration by <ref target="/wiki/Edwin_Austin_Abbey" title="Edwin Austin Abbey">Edwin Austin Abbey</ref>, c. 1895
<p>Sir Anthony Absolute, a wealthy <ref target="/wiki/Baronet" title="Baronet">baronet</ref></p>
<p>Captain Jack Absolute, his son, disguised as Ensign Beverley</p>
<p>Faulkland, friend of Jack Absolute</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Bob_Acres" title="Bob Acres">Bob Acres</ref>, friend of Jack Absolute
<p>Sir Lucius O'Trigger, an Irish baronet</p>
<p>Fag, Captain Absolute's servant</p>
<p>David, Bob Acres' servant</p>
<p>Thomas, Sir Anthony's servant</p>
<p>Lydia Languish, a wealthy teenaged heiress, in love with "Ensign Beverley"</p>
<ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Mrs._Malaprop" title="Mrs. Malaprop">Mrs. Malaprop</ref>, Lydia's middle-aged guardian
<p>Julia Melville, a young relation of the Absolutes, in love with Faulkland</p>
<p>Lucy, Lydia's conniving maid</p>
<h2>Plot[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: Plot">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>The play is set in 18th-century <ref target="/wiki/Bath,_Somerset" title="Bath, Somerset">Bath</ref>, a town that was legendary for <ref target="/wiki/Conspicuous_consumption" title="Conspicuous consumption">conspicuous consumption</ref> and fashion at the time. Wealthy, fashionable people went there to "<ref target="/wiki/Spa#Bathing_in_the_18th_century" title="Spa">take the waters</ref>", which were believed to have healing properties. Bath society was much less exclusive than London, and hence it provides an ideal setting for the characters.</p>
<p>The plot centres on the two young lovers, Lydia and Jack. Lydia, who reads a lot of popular novels of the time, wants a purely romantic love affair. To court her, Jack pretends to be "Ensign Beverley", a poor army officer. Lydia is enthralled with the idea of eloping with a poor soldier in spite of the objections of her guardian, Mrs. Malaprop, a moralistic widow. Mrs. Malaprop is the chief comic figure of the play, thanks to her continual misuse of words that sound like the words she intends to use, but mean something completely different (the term <ref class="extiw" href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/malapropism" title="wikt:malapropism">malapropism</ref> was coined in reference to the character).</p>

<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Elsie_Leslie_(1899)_by_Zaida_Ben-Yusuf.jpg"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:Elsie_Leslie_(1899)_by_Zaida_Ben-Yusuf.jpg" title="Enlarge"></ref><ref target="/wiki/Elsie_Leslie" title="Elsie Leslie">Elsie Leslie</ref> as Lydia Languish in The Rivals, 1899. Photograph by <ref target="/wiki/Zaida_Ben-Yusuf" title="Zaida Ben-Yusuf">Zaida Ben-Yusuf</ref>.
<p>Lydia has two other suitors: Bob Acres (a somewhat buffoonish country gentleman), and Sir Lucius O'Trigger, an impoverished and combative Irish gentleman. Sir Lucius pays Lucy to carry love notes between him and Lydia (who uses the name "Delia"), but Lucy is swindling him: "Delia" is actually Mrs. Malaprop.</p>
<p>As the play opens, Sir Anthony arrives suddenly in Bath. He has arranged a marriage for Jack, but Jack demurs, saying he is in love already. They quarrel violently. But Jack soon learns through the gossip of Lucy and Fag that the marriage arranged by Sir Anthony is, in fact, with Lydia. He makes a great show of submission to his father, and is presented to Lydia with Mrs. Malaprop's blessing. Jack confides to Lydia that he is only posing as Sir Anthony's son. She annoys Mrs. Malaprop by loudly professing her eternal devotion to "Beverley" while rejecting "Jack Absolute".</p>
<p>Jack's friend Faulkland is in love with Julia, but he suffers from jealous suspicion. He is constantly fretting himself about her fidelity. Faulkland and Julia quarrel foolishly, making elaborate and high-flown speeches about true love that satirise the romantic dramas of the period.</p>
<p>Bob Acres tells Sir Lucius that another man ("Beverley") is courting the lady of Acres' choice (Lydia, though Sir Lucius does not know this). Sir Lucius immediately declares that Acres must challenge "Beverley" to a duel and kill him. Acres goes along, and writes out a challenge note – despite his own rather more pacifist feelings, and the profound misgivings of his servant David. Sir Lucius leaves, Jack arrives, and Acres tells him of his intent. Jack agrees to deliver the note to "Beverley", but declines to be Acres' second.</p>
<p>Mrs. Malaprop again presents Jack to Lydia, but this time with Sir Anthony present, exposing Jack's pose as "Beverley". Lydia is enraged by the puncturing of her romantic dreams, and spurns Jack contemptuously.</p>
<p>Sir Lucius has also learned of the proposed marriage of Jack and Lydia, and determines to challenge Jack. He meets Jack, who, smarting from Lydia's rejection, agrees to fight him without even knowing the reason. They will meet at the same time as Acres is scheduled to fight "Beverley".</p>
<p>At the duelling ground, Acres is very reluctant to fight, but Sir Lucius will have no shirking. Jack and Faulkland arrive. Acres learns that "Beverley" is actually his friend Jack, and begs off from their duel. However, Jack is quite willing to fight Sir Lucius, and they cross swords.</p>
<p>David informs Mrs. Malaprop, Lydia, Julia, and Sir Anthony of the duel, and they all rush off to stop it. Sir Lucius explains the cause of his challenge, but Lydia denies any connection to him, and admits her love for Jack. Mrs. Malaprop announces that she is Delia, but Sir Lucius recoils in horror, realising that he has been hoaxed. Sir Anthony consoles Mrs. Malaprop, Julia is reconciled to Faulkland, and Acres invites everyone to a party.</p>

<h2>Adaptations[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: Adaptations">edit</ref>]</h2>
<h3>Musical (1935)[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: Musical (1935)">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>A successful musical production of The Rivals with songs by <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Herbert_Hughes_(musicologist)" title="Herbert Hughes (musicologist)">Herbert Hughes</ref> and lyrics by <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/John_Robert_Monsell" title="John Robert Monsell">John Robert Monsell</ref> was staged by <ref target="/wiki/Vladimir_Rosing" title="Vladimir Rosing">Vladimir Rosing</ref> at London's Novelty Theatre in September 1935. The Novelty Theatre had a few other names but was demolished in 1941 as Kingsway Theatre. <ref target="/wiki/Mary_of_Teck" title="Mary of Teck">Queen Mary</ref> attended one of the performances.<ref target="#cite_note-4">[4]</ref></p>

<h3>"Maverick" adaptation (1958)[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=8" title='Edit section: "Maverick" adaptation (1958)'>edit</ref>]</h3>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:James_Garner_Bret_Maverick.JPG"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:James_Garner_Bret_Maverick.JPG" title="Enlarge"></ref><ref target="/wiki/James_Garner" title="James Garner">James Garner</ref> as Maverick
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Roger_Moore_Beau_Maverick_1960.JPG"></ref> <ref class="internal" href="/wiki/File:Roger_Moore_Beau_Maverick_1960.JPG" title="Enlarge"></ref><ref target="/wiki/Roger_Moore" title="Roger Moore">Roger Moore</ref> in Maverick
<p>The play was rewritten as a <ref target="/wiki/List_of_Maverick_episodes" title="List of Maverick episodes">1958 episode</ref> of the television series <ref target="/wiki/Maverick_(TV_series)" title="Maverick (TV series)">Maverick</ref>, starring <ref target="/wiki/James_Garner" title="James Garner">James Garner</ref> and <ref target="/wiki/Roger_Moore" title="Roger Moore">Roger Moore</ref>, and was the only episode of the series in which Garner and Moore appeared together (Moore did not play "<ref target="/wiki/Maverick_(TV_series)#Roger_Moore_as_Beau_Maverick" title="Maverick (TV series)">Beau Maverick</ref>," <ref target="/wiki/Maverick_(TV_series)#James_Garner_as_Bret_Maverick" title="Maverick (TV series)">Bret Maverick</ref>'s cousin, until after Garner had left the series). <ref target="/wiki/Pat_Crowley" title="Pat Crowley">Patricia "Pat" Crowley</ref> portrays the <ref target="/wiki/Leading_lady" title="Leading lady">leading lady</ref>. The episode was called "The Rivals" and the original playwright was given due credit.</p>

<h3>Television productions[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=9" title="Edit section: Television productions">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The play was <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/The_Rivals_(1961_play)" title="The Rivals (1961 play)">adapted for Australian television in 1961</ref>.</p>
<p>The <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/British_Broadcasting_Corporation" title="British Broadcasting Corporation">BBC</ref> produced a version which was broadcast in 1970 as part of their <ref target="/wiki/Play_of_the_Month" title="Play of the Month">Play of the Month</ref> series, starring <ref target="/wiki/Jeremy_Brett" title="Jeremy Brett">Jeremy Brett</ref> as Captain Jack Absolute.</p>

<h3>Jack Absolute Novels (2003–2006)[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=10" title="Edit section: Jack Absolute Novels (2003–2006)">edit</ref>]</h3>
<p>The leading character of the play was taken to be the identity of the hero of a series of historic fictional adventure books by actor/novelist <ref target="/wiki/Chris_Humphreys" title="Chris Humphreys">Chris Humphreys</ref>. They take place in Cornwall, London, Quebec, the American colonies during both the Seven Years' War and the American Revolution, and Portugal.</p>

<h2>Biographical sources[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=11" title="Edit section: Biographical sources">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>Richard Brinsley Sheridan, The Rivals (New Mermaids 1979, Elizabeth Duthie, Ed.).</p>
<p>Linda Kelly, Richard Brinsley Sheridan, A Life (<ref target="/wiki/Sinclair-Stevenson" title="Sinclair-Stevenson">Sinclair-Stevenson</ref> 1997).</p>
<p>Brooke Allen, <ref class="external text" href="http://www.newcriterion.com/archive/17/dec98/brooke.htm" rel="nofollow">The Scholar of Scandal</ref>, a review of Fintan O’Toole, The Traitor's Kiss: The Life of Richard Brinsley Sheridan, 1751–1816 (Farrar, Straus & Giroux 1998), at New Criterion.</p>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.theatrehistory.com/irish/sheridan001.html" rel="nofollow">Richard Brinsley Sheridan</ref> (1751–1816) at Theatre History.
<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=12" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>


<ref target="#cite_ref-1">^</ref> Dramatis Personæ

<ref target="#cite_ref-2">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="https://archive.org/details/dramaticworkswit01sheruoft" rel="nofollow">The Dramatic Works of Richard Brinsley Sheridan</ref> at the Internet Archive. Oxford University Press 1930. Introduction by Joseph Knight p10. Retrieved 28 June 2013.

<ref target="#cite_ref-Oxford_DNB_3-0">^</ref> <ref class="external text" href="http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/10.1093/ref:odnb/9780198614128.001.0001/odnb-9780198614128-e-39764#" rel="nofollow">Oxford Dictionary of National Biography: Bulkley née Wilford; other married name Barresford, Mary, by John Levitt</ref>

<ref target="#cite_ref-4">^</ref> Rosing, Ruth Glean. Val Rosing: Musical Genius. pg. 123, Manhattan: Sunflower University Press (1993).


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit&section=13" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>



<p>Wikimedia Commons has media related to <ref class="extiw" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:The_Rivals" title="commons:Category:The Rivals">The Rivals</ref>.</p>

<ref class="external text" href="http://www.gutenberg.org/etext/24761" rel="nofollow">Full text of The Rivals</ref> at <ref target="/wiki/Project_Gutenberg" title="Project Gutenberg">Project Gutenberg</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.ibdb.com/broadway-show/7543" rel="nofollow">The Rivals</ref> at the <ref target="/wiki/Internet_Broadway_Database" title="Internet Broadway Database">Internet Broadway Database</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JjPuQ5crX68" rel="nofollow">The Rivals</ref> on <ref target="/wiki/YouTube" title="YouTube">YouTube</ref>
 <ref class="external text" href="https://librivox.org/search?title=The+Rivals&author=SHERIDAN&reader=&keywords=&genre_id=0&status=all&project_type=either&recorded_language=&sort_order=catalog_date&search_page=1&search_form=advanced" rel="nofollow">The Rivals</ref> public domain audiobook at <ref target="/wiki/LibriVox" title="LibriVox">LibriVox</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Template:Richard_Brinsley_Sheridan" title="Template:Richard Brinsley Sheridan">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:Richard_Brinsley_Sheridan" title="Template talk:Richard Brinsley Sheridan">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:Richard_Brinsley_Sheridan&action=edit">e</ref>Plays by <ref target="/wiki/Richard_Brinsley_Sheridan" title="Richard Brinsley Sheridan">Richard Brinsley Sheridan</ref>
<ref class="mw-selflink selflink">The Rivals</ref> (1775)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Duenna" title="The Duenna">The Duenna</ref> (1775)
<ref target="/wiki/A_Trip_to_Scarborough" title="A Trip to Scarborough">A Trip to Scarborough</ref> (1777)
<ref target="/wiki/The_School_for_Scandal" title="The School for Scandal">The School for Scandal</ref> (1777)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Camp_(play)" title="The Camp (play)">The Camp</ref> (1778)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Critic_(play)" title="The Critic (play)">The Critic</ref> (1779)
<ref target="/wiki/The_Glorious_First_of_June_(play)" title="The Glorious First of June (play)">The Glorious First of June</ref> (1794)





<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&oldid=912007683">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&oldid=912007683</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_by_Richard_Brinsley_Sheridan" title="Category:Plays by Richard Brinsley Sheridan">Plays by Richard Brinsley Sheridan</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:1775_plays" title="Category:1775 plays">1775 plays</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Plays_set_in_the_18th_century" title="Category:Plays set in the 18th century">Plays set in the 18th century</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:EngvarB_from_September_2013" title="Category:EngvarB from September 2013">EngvarB from September 2013</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Use_dmy_dates_from_September_2013" title="Category:Use dmy dates from September 2013">Use dmy dates from September 2013</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_needing_additional_references_from_July_2007" title="Category:Articles needing additional references from July 2007">Articles needing additional references from July 2007</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:All_articles_needing_additional_references" title="Category:All articles needing additional references">All articles needing additional references</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Commons_category_link_is_on_Wikidata" title="Category:Commons category link is on Wikidata">Commons category link is on Wikidata</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_with_LibriVox_links" title="Category:Articles with LibriVox links">Articles with LibriVox links</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=The+Rivals" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=The+Rivals" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/The_Rivals" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:The_Rivals" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/The_Rivals">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/The_Rivals" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/The_Rivals" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&oldid=912007683" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7760957" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=The_Rivals&id=912007683" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>In other projects</h3></p>


<ref target="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:The_Rivals" hreflang="en">Wikimedia Commons</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=The+Rivals">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=The+Rivals&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://bg.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D0%A1%D1%8A%D0%BF%D0%B5%D1%80%D0%BD%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B8" hreflang="bg" lang="bg" title="Съперници – Bulgarian">Български</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Rivaux_(Sheridan)" hreflang="fr" lang="fr" title="Les Rivaux (Sheridan) – French">Français</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q7760957#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 22 August 2019, at 16:48 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=The_Rivals&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.236","walltime":"0.367","ppvisitednodes":{"value":855,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":20879,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":948,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":13,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":3,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":0,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":1658,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":1,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 313.732 1 -total"," 25.34% 79.504 1 Template:Refimprove"," 23.28% 73.050 1 Template:Ambox"," 16.92% 53.087 1 Template:Commons_category"," 14.25% 44.701 1 Template:Infobox_play"," 12.28% 38.514 1 Template:Infobox"," 11.36% 35.639 1 Template:EngvarB"," 11.28% 35.384 1 Template:Find_sources_mainspace"," 7.10% 22.262 1 Template:Ibdb_show"," 5.74% 18.013 2 Template:DMCA"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.087","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":3141577,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1273","timestamp":"20190925031220","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"The Rivals","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/The_Rivals","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7760957","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q7760957","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2004-06-21T16:22:30Z","dateModified":"2019-08-22T16:48:41Z","headline":"play by Richard Brinsley Sheridan"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":88,"wgHostname":"mw1275"});});</p>


