



<p>Whoopi - Wikipedia</p>
<p>document.documentElement.className="client-js";RLCONF={"wgCanonicalNamespace":"","wgCanonicalSpecialPageName":!1,"wgNamespaceNumber":0,"wgPageName":"Whoopi","wgTitle":"Whoopi","wgCurRevisionId":916272605,"wgRevisionId":916272605,"wgArticleId":322141,"wgIsArticle":!0,"wgIsRedirect":!1,"wgAction":"view","wgUserName":null,"wgUserGroups":["*"],"wgCategories":["Articles lacking sources from June 2018","All articles lacking sources","Episode list using the default LineColor","All stub articles","2000s American sitcoms","2003 American television series debuts","2004 American television series endings","English-language television programs","NBC network shows","Television series by Carsey-Werner Productions","Television shows set in New York City","United States comedy television series stubs"],"wgBreakFrames":!1,"wgPageContentLanguage":"en","wgPageContentModel":"wikitext","wgSeparatorTransformTable":["",""],"wgDigitTransformTable":["",""],"wgDefaultDateFormat":"dmy","wgMonthNames":</p>
<p>["","January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"wgMonthNamesShort":["","Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"wgRelevantPageName":"Whoopi","wgRelevantArticleId":322141,"wgRequestId":"XZYdVgpAAEEAABZP4qgAAABE","wgCSPNonce":!1,"wgIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRelevantPageIsProbablyEditable":!0,"wgRestrictionEdit":[],"wgRestrictionMove":[],"wgMediaViewerOnClick":!0,"wgMediaViewerEnabledByDefault":!0,"wgPopupsReferencePreviews":!1,"wgPopupsConflictsWithNavPopupGadget":!1,"wgVisualEditor":{"pageLanguageCode":"en","pageLanguageDir":"ltr","pageVariantFallbacks":"en"},"wgMFDisplayWikibaseDescriptions":{"search":!0,"nearby":!0,"watchlist":!0,"tagline":!1},"wgWMESchemaEditAttemptStepOversample":!1,"wgPoweredByHHVM":!1,"wgULSCurrentAutonym":"English","wgNoticeProject":"wikipedia","wgWikibaseItemId":"Q478953","wgCentralAuthMobileDomain":!1,</p>
<p>"wgEditSubmitButtonLabelPublish":!0};RLSTATE={"ext.globalCssJs.user.styles":"ready","site.styles":"ready","noscript":"ready","user.styles":"ready","ext.globalCssJs.user":"ready","user":"ready","user.options":"ready","user.tokens":"loading","mediawiki.legacy.shared":"ready","mediawiki.legacy.commonPrint":"ready","mediawiki.toc.styles":"ready","wikibase.client.init":"ready","ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.noscript":"ready","ext.uls.interlanguage":"ready","ext.wikimediaBadges":"ready","ext.3d.styles":"ready","mediawiki.skinning.interface":"ready","skins.vector.styles":"ready"};RLPAGEMODULES=["site","mediawiki.page.startup","mediawiki.page.ready","mediawiki.toc","mediawiki.searchSuggest","ext.gadget.teahouse","ext.gadget.ReferenceTooltips","ext.gadget.watchlist-notice","ext.gadget.DRN-wizard","ext.gadget.charinsert","ext.gadget.refToolbar","ext.gadget.extra-toolbar-buttons","ext.gadget.switcher","ext.centralauth.centralautologin","mmv.head","mmv.bootstrap.autostart","ext.popups",</p>
<p>"ext.visualEditor.desktopArticleTarget.init","ext.visualEditor.targetLoader","ext.eventLogging","ext.wikimediaEvents","ext.navigationTiming","ext.uls.compactlinks","ext.uls.interface","ext.cx.eventlogging.campaigns","ext.quicksurveys.init","ext.centralNotice.geoIP","ext.centralNotice.startUp","skins.vector.js"];</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.loader.implement("user.tokens@tffin",function($,jQuery,require,module){/*@nomin*/mw.user.tokens.set({"editToken":"+\\","patrolToken":"+\\","watchToken":"+\\","csrfToken":"+\\"});</p>
<p>});});</p>

























<ref id="top"></ref>



<p>Whoopi</h1></p>

<p>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</p>


<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#mw-head">Jump to navigation</ref>
<ref class="mw-jump-link" href="#p-search">Jump to search</ref>
<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:Question_book-new.svg"></ref>This article does not <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Citing_sources" title="Wikipedia:Citing sources">cite</ref> any <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Verifiability" title="Wikipedia:Verifiability">sources</ref>. Please help <ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit">improve this article</ref> by <ref target="/wiki/Help:Introduction_to_referencing_with_Wiki_Markup/1" title="Help:Introduction to referencing with Wiki Markup/1">adding citations to reliable sources</ref>. Unsourced material may be challenged and <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Verifiability#Burden_of_evidence" title="Wikipedia:Verifiability">removed</ref>. (June 2018) (<ref target="/wiki/Help:Maintenance_template_removal" title="Help:Maintenance template removal">Learn how and when to remove this template message</ref>)
<p>WhoopiGenreSitcomCreated byBonnie TurnerTerry TurnerStarring<ref target="/wiki/Whoopi_Goldberg" title="Whoopi Goldberg">Whoopi Goldberg</ref>Wren T. Brown<ref target="/wiki/Omid_Djalili" title="Omid Djalili">Omid Djalili</ref>Elizabeth RegenGordana RashovichOpening theme"Whoopi" by Whoopi GoldbergComposer(s)Ahrin MishanCountry of originUnited StatesOriginal language(s)EnglishNo. of seasons1No. of episodes22ProductionExecutive producer(s)<ref target="/wiki/Whoopi_Goldberg" title="Whoopi Goldberg">Whoopi Goldberg</ref><ref target="/wiki/Marcy_Carsey" title="Marcy Carsey">Marcy Carsey</ref><ref target="/wiki/Tom_Werner" title="Tom Werner">Tom Werner</ref><ref target="/wiki/Caryn_Mandabach" title="Caryn Mandabach">Caryn Mandabach</ref>Camera setup<ref target="/wiki/Multiple-camera_setup" title="Multiple-camera setup">Multi-camera</ref>Running time30 minutesProduction company(s)<ref target="/wiki/Whoopi_Goldberg" title="Whoopi Goldberg">One Ho Productions</ref><ref target="/wiki/Universal_Television" title="Universal Television">NBC Studios</ref><ref target="/wiki/The_Carsey-Werner_Company" title="The Carsey-Werner Company">Carsey-Werner-Mandabach</ref>ReleaseOriginal network<ref target="/wiki/NBC" title="NBC">NBC</ref>Picture format<ref target="/wiki/1080i" title="1080i">1080i</ref> (<ref target="/wiki/High-definition_television" title="High-definition television">HDTV</ref>)Original releaseSeptember 9, 2003 (2003-09-09) –April 20, 2004 (2004-04-20)</p>
<p>Whoopi is an American <ref target="/wiki/Sitcom" title="Sitcom">sitcom</ref> starring <ref target="/wiki/Whoopi_Goldberg" title="Whoopi Goldberg">Whoopi Goldberg</ref> that premiered on September 9, 2003, on <ref target="/wiki/NBC" title="NBC">NBC</ref>. The show aired for one season and ended on April 20, 2004. The series revolved around the events and people at her hotel, the Lamont Hotel, in <ref target="/wiki/New_York_City" title="New York City">New York City</ref>.</p>

<head>Contents</head>

<ref target="#Premise">1 Premise</ref>
<ref target="#Cast">2 Cast</ref>

<ref target="#Main">2.1 Main</ref>
<ref target="#Notable_guest_stars">2.2 Notable guest stars</ref>


<ref target="#Episodes">3 Episodes</ref>
<ref target="#References">4 References</ref>
<ref target="#External_links">5 External links</ref>


<h2>Premise[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit&section=1" title="Edit section: Premise">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref target="/wiki/Whoopi_Goldberg" title="Whoopi Goldberg">Whoopi Goldberg</ref> starred in this comedy as <ref target="/wiki/One-hit_wonder" title="One-hit wonder">one-hit wonder</ref> Mavis Rae, a cigarette-smoking, alcohol-drinking, menopausal and especially opinionated hotelier. The former one-hit wonder runs her own small hotel in <ref target="/wiki/New_York_City" title="New York City">New York City</ref> - and does it any way she wants. Goldberg also served as an executive producer on the series.
<p>In 1986 Mavis had one huge, spectacular hit song, the two-time <ref target="/wiki/Grammy_Award" title="Grammy Award">Grammy Award</ref>-winning "Don't Hide Love". Quickly realizing that her initial success was a fluke, she parlayed her finances from that hit into purchasing the Lamont Hotel in <ref target="/wiki/Manhattan" title="Manhattan">Manhattan</ref>. Mavis operates the hotel on her charm and wit while assisted by Nasim (<ref target="/wiki/Omid_Djalili" title="Omid Djalili">Omid Djalili</ref>), who is a native of <ref target="/wiki/Iran" title="Iran">Iran</ref>. Also in the regular cast were Mavis's brother Courtney (Wren T. Brown), a conservative <ref target="/wiki/Republican_Party_(United_States)" title="Republican Party (United States)">Republican</ref>, and his girlfriend Rita (Elizabeth Regen), who spoke <ref target="/wiki/African-American_Vernacular_English" title="African-American Vernacular English">jive</ref> and was portrayed with an exaggerated urban black stereotype despite the fact that she was white. Rita and Mavis frequently clashed over the course of the series, leading to many of the conflicts that drove the plot of each episode.</p>

<h2>Cast[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit&section=2" title="Edit section: Cast">edit</ref>]</h2>
<h3>Main[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit&section=3" title="Edit section: Main">edit</ref>]</h3>
<ref target="/wiki/Whoopi_Goldberg" title="Whoopi Goldberg">Whoopi Goldberg</ref> – Mavis Rae
<ref target="/wiki/Omid_Djalili" title="Omid Djalili">Omid Djalili</ref> – Nasim
<p>Elizabeth Regen – Rita Nash</p>
<p>Gordana Rashovich - Jadwiga</p>
<h3>Notable guest stars[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit&section=4" title="Edit section: Notable guest stars">edit</ref>]</h3>
<ref target="/wiki/Sheryl_Lee_Ralph" title="Sheryl Lee Ralph">Sheryl Lee Ralph</ref> as Mavis' former band mate, Florence Lamarck (episode: "She Ain't Heavy, She's My Partner")
<ref target="/wiki/Diahann_Carroll" title="Diahann Carroll">Diahann Carroll</ref> as Mavis' mother, Viveca Rae (episode: "Mother's Little Helper")
<ref target="/wiki/Rue_McClanahan" title="Rue McClanahan">Rue McClanahan</ref> as a hotel guest using marijuana with a group of "ill" seniors (episode: "American Woman")
<ref target="/wiki/Eli_Wallach" title="Eli Wallach">Eli Wallach</ref> as a medical marijuana using senior and husband of Rue McClanahan's character. Wallach had previously worked with Goldberg in 1996's <ref target="/wiki/The_Associate_(1996_film)" title="The Associate (1996 film)">The Associate</ref>. (episode: "American Woman")
<ref target="/wiki/Patrick_Swayze" title="Patrick Swayze">Patrick Swayze</ref> as Mavis' former choreographer, Tony (episode: "The Last Dance")
<ref target="/wiki/Celeste_Holm" title="Celeste Holm">Celeste Holm</ref> as an elderly tenant of Mavis', Diana (episode: "The Squatter")
<ref target="/wiki/Krysten_Ritter" title="Krysten Ritter">Krysten Ritter</ref> as Diana's granddaughter, Brynn (episode: "The Squatter")
<ref target="/wiki/Scott_Stevens" title="Scott Stevens">Scott Stevens</ref> as himself (episode: "Smoke Gets in Your Eyes")
<ref target="/wiki/Darius_Kasparaitis" title="Darius Kasparaitis">Darius Kasparaitis</ref> as himself (episode: "Smoke Gets in Your Eyes")
<ref target="/wiki/Anson_Carter" title="Anson Carter">Anson Carter</ref> as himself (episode: "Smoke Gets in Your Eyes")
<ref target="/wiki/Scott_Gomez" title="Scott Gomez">Scott Gomez</ref> as himself (episode: "Smoke Gets in Your Eyes")
<ref target="/wiki/Jay_Pandolfo" title="Jay Pandolfo">Jay Pandolfo</ref> as himself (episode: "Smoke Gets in Your Eyes")
<h2>Episodes[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit&section=5" title="Edit section: Episodes">edit</ref>]</h2>
<p>No.TitleDirected byWritten byOriginal air date1"Pilot"<ref target="/wiki/Terry_Hughes_(director)" title="Terry Hughes (director)">Terry Hughes</ref><ref target="/wiki/Bonnie_and_Terry_Turner" title="Bonnie and Terry Turner">Bonnie Turner and Terry Turner</ref>September 9, 2003 (2003-09-09)</p>
<p>Mavis Rae makes room for her brother Courtney after his recent employer, Enron, suffers a small financial setback. However, her new hotel guest is in love and Mavis soon has the pleasure of meeting Rita, Courtney's white girlfriend who talks and dresses like a "sister" -- and is just too much fun for her to ignore. Meanwhile, the hotel's need for a fulltime concierge prompts Mavis to promote her reliable handyman Nasim giving him a shot at this new position.</p>
<p>2"Don't Hide Your Bag"Terry HughesMike Chessler & Chris AlberghiniSeptember 16, 2003 (2003-09-16)</p>
<p>When the nation's security threat level is elevated to an orange alert, Nasim's paranoia over an abandoned designer briefcase in the hotel lobby and fear of getting SARS from a group of Toronto tourists, carries over to Mavis, who calls the police bomb squad to blow up the attache. But when Mavis discovers that Courtney is missing his expensive new briefcase -- which was a gift from girlfriend, Rita, she scrambles to find an inexpensive knockoff.</p>
<p>3"Once Bitten"Terry HughesJerry CollinsSeptember 23, 2003 (2003-09-23)</p>
<p>Mavis has trouble getting seen at the emergency room after getting bitten by Rita's pet ferret.</p>
<p>4"Shout TV"Terry HughesMike LarsenSeptember 30, 2003 (2003-09-30)</p>
<p>Frustrated after receiving a ticket for smoking in her hotel, Mavis feels responsible when poor Nasim is also cited for spitting in public after she stuffs a hot pepper in his mouth -- but when she urges him to contest the penalty in court, the naive handyman quits, fearing deportation back to Iran. Meanwhile, Mavis' unemployed brother Courtney loses cash in an ATM and then loses his cool when he is put on phone hold for hours which only makes Rita pout.</p>
<p>5"Smoke Gets in Your Eyes"Terry HughesTBAOctober 7, 2003 (2003-10-07)</p>
<p>While at a <ref target="/wiki/New_Jersey_Devils" title="New Jersey Devils">Devils</ref>-<ref target="/wiki/New_York_Rangers" title="New York Rangers">Rangers</ref> game, Mavis meets a blind man.</p>
<p>6"The Vast Right Wing Conspiracy"Terry Hughes<ref target="/wiki/Larry_Wilmore" title="Larry Wilmore">Larry Wilmore</ref>October 14, 2003 (2003-10-14)</p>
<p>After a chance encounter with President Bush when his motorcade stops at the Lamont Hotel, Mavis cannot mouth off to the Commander in Chief after he recognizes her and pays homage to her singing talents -- but she clashes with Republican Courtney when Bush graciously invites her for a face-to-face meeting. Later, while out of place at a GOP function, a sassy Mavis drinks, smokes and speaks her mind -- and soon gets up-close-and-personal with the Secret Service.</p>
<p>7"She Ain't Heavy, She's My Partner"Terry HughesDavid RegalOctober 21, 2003 (2003-10-21)</p>
<p>When one of Mavis' former singing trio dies, she recoils at the sight of Florence, the other remaining member of "The Ebony Blackbirds" who arrives for the funeral looking sleek,stylish -- and scheming -- all of which re-ignites outspoken Mavis' jealousy and disgust. Meanwhile, girlfriend Rita is off-the-hook crazy when she learns that her shy Courtney was seduced by Florence years ago -- a scenario that inspires Nasim.</p>
<p>8"Rita Plays Poker"TBATBAOctober 28, 2003 (2003-10-28)</p>
<p>When hip-hop Rita joins Mavis' rowdy all-girl smoker-poker night, she shows a new side of herself that offends conservative Courtney -- but the hip girlfriend won't hop to his orders to abandon the game and walks out on him, leaving the lawyer crestfallen on the eve of a big job interview. In order to reinvigorate her zombie-like brother before the interview, Mavis recruits Nasim in a desperate bid to reconcile the mismatched lovebrids.</p>
<p>9"Sticky Fingers"Terry HughesMike Chessler & Chris AlberghiniNovember 11, 2003 (2003-11-11)</p>
<p>After unwittingly ruining Nasim's favorite shirt, a slightly guilty Mavis takes the handyman shopping for a replacement only to find herself in department store jail after mistakenly taken a belt without paying. Once word of her detention and alleged theft hits the media, Mavis' popularity skyrockets forcing her to fields interview requests from a bevy of reporters including VH1 -- who wants to use the incident to tailor a special "Behind the Music" on her illustrious career.</p>
<p>10"Mother's Little Helper"Terry HughesLaurie ParresNovember 18, 2003 (2003-11-18)</p>
<p>Mavis is stricken with dread when her domineering, obnoxious mother arrives with her dad from North Carolina, but her mom's surprising polite and charming demeanor is due to her new prescription medication -- and things change for the worse when her pills are accidentally tossed.</p>
<p>11"The Fat and the Frivolous"TBADavid WyattDecember 9, 2003 (2003-12-09)</p>
<p>Mavis is dragged into court when a corpulent man sues her after he checks into her hotel and crashes through the room's bed -- and an intimidated Courtney must represent her against a slick, high-price lawyer who always out-wits his opponent. Aware that the plaintiff makes a living off false lawsuits, Courtney stages a mock trial to prepare his loud-mothed sister for the real thing but muzzling Mavis might prove impossible.</p>
<p>12"American Woman"TBATBAJanuary 6, 2004 (2004-01-06)</p>
<p>Mavis deals with guests smoking weed in her hotel while Nasim studies for his Citizenship Exam and gets some help from Mavis.</p>
<p>13"Airplane"TBATBAJanuary 13, 2004 (2004-01-13)</p>
<p>Fear of flying besets Mavis, who's forced to confront her phobia because her poker friends and her are taking a trip to Bermuda. When Rita finds out Mavis is afraid of flying, she sends Mavis to a flight-simulator school.</p>
<p>14"Is Rita Pregnant?"Terry HughesTerry TurnerFebruary 3, 2004 (2004-02-03)</p>
<p>After Rita starts to think she's pregnant, Courtney gets a job so he can buy a ring and propose to Rita. But when she says no because it is not a true loving proposal, they start to rethink their relationship. All of this news shocks Mavis. Elsewhere, Nasim and Jadwiga try to win Connecticut's Powerball Jackpot.</p>
<p>15"The Last Dance"TBATBAFebruary 24, 2004 (2004-02-24)</p>
<p>Mavis' former choreographer from her days as a one-hit singing wonder drops by her hotel and inspires her to resume their good times-loving relationship. However, her old friend has newfound religious convictions that Mavis intends to undermine.</p>
<p>16"No Sex in the City"TBATBAMarch 2, 2004 (2004-03-02)</p>
<p>Mavis dons a blonde wig and presides over her female posse during a wild bachelorette party at a trendy night club as they celebrate Soo Lin's wedding and meet a wide variety of exotic patrons -- and as the bar bill adds up, the bride-to-be starts to have second thoughts. In another corner, designated driver Nasim is mistaken as Mavis' macho male escort and soon entertains offers of similar employment.</p>
<p>17"What Child Is This?"TBATBAMarch 16, 2004 (2004-03-16)</p>
<p>A bratty boy pesters Mavis, who's further piqued by the lad's pesky dad, a GOP functionary who offers Courtney a job with President Bush's reelection campaign.</p>
<p>18"Don't Hide Love"TBATBAMarch 23, 2004 (2004-03-23)</p>
<p>Mavis agrees to host her gay cousin's wedding at the hotel, particularly after finding out that her one hit, Don't Hide Love, has become a gay anthem in the years since she recorded it. Complications arise when Mavis's right-wing brother Courtney plans to host a meeting of the Republican Inclusion Coalition at the hotel on the same weekend.</p>
<p>19"The Squatter"TBATBAMarch 30, 2004 (2004-03-30)</p>
<p>Mavis causes havoc throughout the hotel.</p>
<p>20"Identity Crisis"TBATBAApril 6, 2004 (2004-04-06)</p>
<p>After becoming a victim of identity theft, Mavis starts to secretly suspect Rita, who has a secret of her own about a poker game she has set up to help Mavis make some fast cash.</p>
<p>21"Strange Bedfellows"TBATBAApril 13, 2004 (2004-04-13)</p>
<p>A dating service lures Nasim, whose matchup bears a startling similarity to his tormenting nemesis: the smart-alecky Jadwiga. Also, Rita's insouciance bewitches a GOP functionary, who has ulterior motives in hiring her.</p>
<p>22"Sins of the Sister"TBATBAApril 20, 2004 (2004-04-20)</p>
<p>Dirty politics entangle Mavis with an old crony, an assemblyman who's smearing an opponent, Courtney, who hasn't a clue about how to retaliate. Mavis, however, does know how to play hardball.</p>
<h2>References[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit&section=6" title="Edit section: References">edit</ref>]</h2>


<h2>External links[<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit&section=7" title="Edit section: External links">edit</ref>]</h2>
<ref class="external text" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20030821013106/http://www.nbc.com/Whoopi/" rel="nofollow">Official NBC site for Whoopi</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.carseywerner.com/shows_about.php?showid=11" rel="nofollow">Carsey-Werner - Whoopi</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0364902/" rel="nofollow">Whoopi</ref> on <ref target="/wiki/IMDb" title="IMDb">IMDb</ref>
<ref class="external text" href="http://www.tv.com/shows/whoopi/" rel="nofollow">Whoopi</ref> at <ref target="/wiki/TV.com" title="TV.com">TV.com</ref>


<ref class="image" href="/wiki/File:USA_flag_on_television.svg"></ref>This article relating to a <ref target="/wiki/Comedy" title="Comedy">comedy</ref> <ref class="mw-redirect" href="/wiki/Television_series" title="Television series">television series</ref> in the United States is a <ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Stub" title="Wikipedia:Stub">stub</ref>. You can help Wikipedia by <ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit">expanding it</ref>.<ref target="/wiki/Template:US-comedy-tv-prog-stub" title="Template:US-comedy-tv-prog-stub">v</ref><ref target="/wiki/Template_talk:US-comedy-tv-prog-stub" title="Template talk:US-comedy-tv-prog-stub">t</ref><ref class="external text" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:US-comedy-tv-prog-stub&action=edit">e</ref>




<p>Retrieved from "<ref dir="ltr" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&oldid=916272605">https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&oldid=916272605</ref>"</p>
<ref target="/wiki/Help:Category" title="Help:Category">Categories</ref>: <ref target="/wiki/Category:2000s_American_sitcoms" title="Category:2000s American sitcoms">2000s American sitcoms</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:2003_American_television_series_debuts" title="Category:2003 American television series debuts">2003 American television series debuts</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:2004_American_television_series_endings" title="Category:2004 American television series endings">2004 American television series endings</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:English-language_television_programs" title="Category:English-language television programs">English-language television programs</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:NBC_network_shows" title="Category:NBC network shows">NBC network shows</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Television_series_by_Carsey-Werner_Productions" title="Category:Television series by Carsey-Werner Productions">Television series by Carsey-Werner Productions</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Television_shows_set_in_New_York_City" title="Category:Television shows set in New York City">Television shows set in New York City</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:United_States_comedy_television_series_stubs" title="Category:United States comedy television series stubs">United States comedy television series stubs</ref>Hidden categories: <ref target="/wiki/Category:Articles_lacking_sources_from_June_2018" title="Category:Articles lacking sources from June 2018">Articles lacking sources from June 2018</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:All_articles_lacking_sources" title="Category:All articles lacking sources">All articles lacking sources</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:Episode_list_using_the_default_LineColor" title="Category:Episode list using the default LineColor">Episode list using the default LineColor</ref><ref target="/wiki/Category:All_stub_articles" title="Category:All stub articles">All stub articles</ref>







<head>Navigation menu</head>


<p>Personal tools</h3></p>

<p>Not logged in<ref accesskey="n" href="/wiki/Special:MyTalk" title="Discussion about edits from this IP address [n]">Talk</ref><ref accesskey="y" href="/wiki/Special:MyContributions" title="A list of edits made from this IP address [y]">Contributions</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CreateAccount&returnto=Whoopi" title="You are encouraged to create an account and log in; however, it is not mandatory">Create account</ref><ref accesskey="o" href="/w/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=Whoopi" title="You're encouraged to log in; however, it's not mandatory. [o]">Log in</ref> </p>



<p>Namespaces</h3></p>

<ref accesskey="c" href="/wiki/Whoopi" title="View the content page [c]">Article</ref><ref accesskey="t" href="/wiki/Talk:Whoopi" rel="discussion" title="Discussion about the content page [t]">Talk</ref> 




<p>Variants</p>
</h3>






<p>Views</h3></p>

<ref target="/wiki/Whoopi">Read</ref><ref accesskey="e" href="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=edit" title="Edit this page [e]">Edit</ref><ref accesskey="h" href="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=history" title="Past revisions of this page [h]">View history</ref> 



<p>More</h3></p>




<h3>
<p>Search</p>
</h3>


 





<ref class="mw-wiki-logo" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page"></ref>

<p>Navigation</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="z" href="/wiki/Main_Page" title="Visit the main page [z]">Main page</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Contents" title="Guides to browsing Wikipedia">Contents</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Featured_content" title="Featured content – the best of Wikipedia">Featured content</ref><ref target="/wiki/Portal:Current_events" title="Find background information on current events">Current events</ref><ref accesskey="x" href="/wiki/Special:Random" title="Load a random article [x]">Random article</ref><ref target="https://donate.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FundraiserRedirector?utm_source=donate&utm_medium=sidebar&utm_campaign=C13_en.wikipedia.org&uselang=en" title="Support us">Donate to Wikipedia</ref><ref target="//shop.wikimedia.org" title="Visit the Wikipedia store">Wikipedia store</ref> 



<p>Interaction</h3></p>


<ref target="/wiki/Help:Contents" title="Guidance on how to use and edit Wikipedia">Help</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Find out about Wikipedia">About Wikipedia</ref><ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:Community_portal" title="About the project, what you can do, where to find things">Community portal</ref><ref accesskey="r" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChanges" title="A list of recent changes in the wiki [r]">Recent changes</ref><ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us" title="How to contact Wikipedia">Contact page</ref> 



<p>Tools</h3></p>


<ref accesskey="j" href="/wiki/Special:WhatLinksHere/Whoopi" title="List of all English Wikipedia pages containing links to this page [j]">What links here</ref><ref accesskey="k" href="/wiki/Special:RecentChangesLinked/Whoopi" rel="nofollow" title="Recent changes in pages linked from this page [k]">Related changes</ref><ref accesskey="u" href="/wiki/Wikipedia:File_Upload_Wizard" title="Upload files [u]">Upload file</ref><ref accesskey="q" href="/wiki/Special:SpecialPages" title="A list of all special pages [q]">Special pages</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&oldid=916272605" title="Permanent link to this revision of the page">Permanent link</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&action=info" title="More information about this page">Page information</ref><ref accesskey="g" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q478953" title="Link to connected data repository item [g]">Wikidata item</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:CiteThisPage&page=Whoopi&id=916272605" title="Information on how to cite this page">Cite this page</ref> 



<p>Print/export</h3></p>


<ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:Book&bookcmd=book_creator&referer=Whoopi">Create a book</ref><ref target="/w/index.php?title=Special:ElectronPdf&page=Whoopi&action=show-download-screen">Download as PDF</ref><ref accesskey="p" href="/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&printable=yes" title="Printable version of this page [p]">Printable version</ref> 



<p>Languages</h3></p>


<ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whoopi" hreflang="de" lang="de" title="Whoopi – German">Deutsch</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whoopi" hreflang="fr" lang="fr" title="Whoopi – French">Français</ref><ref class="interlanguage-link-target" href="https://it.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whoopi" hreflang="it" lang="it" title="Whoopi – Italian">Italiano</ref> 
<ref class="wbc-editpage" href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:EntityPage/Q478953#sitelinks-wikipedia" title="Edit interlanguage links">Edit links</ref> 





 This page was last edited on 18 September 2019, at 01:11 (UTC).
<p>Text is available under the <ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Text_of_Creative_Commons_Attribution-ShareAlike_3.0_Unported_License" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License</ref><ref target="//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" rel="license" style="display:none;"></ref>;</p>
<p>additional terms may apply. By using this site, you agree to the <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Terms_of_Use">Terms of Use</ref> and <ref target="//foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</ref>. Wikipedia® is a registered trademark of the <ref target="//www.wikimediafoundation.org/">Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.</ref>, a non-profit organization.</p>


<ref class="extiw" href="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy" title="wmf:Privacy policy">Privacy policy</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:About" title="Wikipedia:About">About Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="/wiki/Wikipedia:General_disclaimer" title="Wikipedia:General disclaimer">Disclaimers</ref>
<ref target="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Contact_us">Contact Wikipedia</ref>
<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/How_to_contribute">Developers</ref>
<ref target="https://foundation.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cookie_statement">Cookie statement</ref>
<ref class="noprint stopMobileRedirectToggle" href="//en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Whoopi&mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile">Mobile view</ref>



<ref target="https://wikimediafoundation.org/"></ref> 

<ref target="https://www.mediawiki.org/"></ref> 



<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgPageParseReport":{"limitreport":{"cputime":"0.472","walltime":"0.627","ppvisitednodes":{"value":4161,"limit":1000000},"ppgeneratednodes":{"value":0,"limit":1500000},"postexpandincludesize":{"value":112046,"limit":2097152},"templateargumentsize":{"value":2451,"limit":2097152},"expansiondepth":{"value":20,"limit":40},"expensivefunctioncount":{"value":1,"limit":500},"unstrip-depth":{"value":0,"limit":20},"unstrip-size":{"value":12,"limit":5000000},"entityaccesscount":{"value":1,"limit":400},"timingprofile":["100.00% 554.606 1 -total"," 48.80% 270.646 1 Template:Episode_table"," 45.64% 253.148 22 Template:Episode_list"," 21.68% 120.261 1 Template:Infobox_television"," 18.40% 102.028 1 Template:Infobox"," 12.87% 71.381 1 Template:Unreferenced"," 7.57% 41.983 1 Template:Ambox"," 7.52% 41.712 1 Template:Tv.com_show"," 6.99% 38.783 23 Template:Start_date"," 6.34% 35.172 1 Template:WikidataCheck"]},"scribunto":{"limitreport-timeusage":{"value":"0.260","limit":"10.000"},"limitreport-memusage":{"value":11517483,"limit":52428800}},"cachereport":{"origin":"mw1295","timestamp":"20191003120350","ttl":2592000,"transientcontent":false}}});});</p>
<p>{"@context":"https:\/\/schema.org","@type":"Article","name":"Whoopi","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Whoopi","sameAs":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q478953","mainEntity":"http:\/\/www.wikidata.org\/entity\/Q478953","author":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Contributors to Wikimedia projects"},"publisher":{"@type":"Organization","name":"Wikimedia Foundation, Inc.","logo":{"@type":"ImageObject","url":"https:\/\/www.wikimedia.org\/static\/images\/wmf-hor-googpub.png"}},"datePublished":"2003-09-19T20:32:05Z","dateModified":"2019-09-18T01:11:17Z","headline":"2003 - '04 American sitcom starring Whoopi Goldberg"}</p>
<p>(RLQ=window.RLQ||[]).push(function(){mw.config.set({"wgBackendResponseTime":99,"wgHostname":"mw1270"});});</p>


